[Music]
Hey, hey, hey.
Heat. Heat. N.
[Music]
Wow.
Good evening, good day everybody and
welcome to episode 300 of the Ask a
Widget Show. It's great to have you all
with me on this live stream this fine
evening here. So before we begin let us
see who all is there on the live stream.
I can see many people I can see Kalborgi
Aush Singh Purva Anu Anupama Anime
knowledge nuk abhishek shukla swami jane
from jaipur nakul verma amit patil
ipk_1s animals for laugh from mumbai
animeish suraj s mystic skanishes
koshikatistic
rdra gulba shivasai aadin
uh knowledge Nukar, Swami, Jane, Shas D
from Pune, Geopolitical Dubai from
Indor, Diya Channel, PSJ,
Abhishek from Kpur, Avin, Mirangabonia
from Assam,
uh, Fields Strong Man, Chaitanya Manuja,
Tanmay Desh, Pande, Vinay, Meet Mistri,
uh, General Subutai, yes, Amisha Mishra,
Nir, Kash Bali, Bak
Bali today
Kushal Chi
Mangabonia Kanish Manish Sha Mi Manisha
Kardo thank you Damru
Nikil Medi Vinay
Dak Dave Joi Bori Gautam K RBG Pranay
Patel Anirud Parakala Priyanka Jalia
Nirkash Bali Vinay Field Strong Man once
again uh Ashwani Karthik Rishi Rahul Dun
anonymous scientist Dak Hunter Kenway
Su Yudha
um who else do we have Suraj S
Kel Kennel is here mystery is from
Australia from stria good to see you sir
amay birulkar Anand Divor Singh Chetan
Aradhya
Radhya Das
okay injured soccer player is here from
Richmond Hill, Ontario in Canada.
Deepanita Mang Mandal Goss.
Uh who else? Who else? Okay, so we've
got lots of people and uh yeah, so first
of all, thank you everybody. The we are
here. This is the 300th episode. I
remember I had done the first episode in
early June 2021 and I had no idea
whatsoever that I would end up doing 300
of these episodes. It is all thanks to
you only. You are the the people who
drive the episodes. So without you this
doesn't happen. It's your questions I
take. I don't invent the questions
myself. And uh so thank you so much for
for your viewership. Thank you so much
for sticking with me all these years.
Some of you are newer. Some of you have
been around for the for the longest time
from the very beginning. So thank you
everybody to to thank you very much to
all of you. I am really very grateful. I
don't take this for granted at all. It
is a privilege to have so much
viewership from all of you. So once
again thank you very much. Um okay let's
take questions. Uh this is going to be
an extended episode. Let's take it as
long as we can. Obviously, I once did an
8 hour episode not a very long time ago.
I'm not sure I'll do it for 8 hours
today, but let's see how long it goes.
Yeah. Um, and why is something happening
on YouTube listen? I have no idea.
YouTube decides what it does. Let it do
what it does. It's not in my hands. So,
I don't I don't worry about it. That's
it. Let YouTube do its thing. All right.
Okay. Uh, let's take some questions.
What questions do we have? We'll take as
many and I'll take questions about
everything today. Uh no restrictions on
the topics whether it's geopolitics,
history, science, something else you
want to talk about. I'll take all the
questions.
Okay. 6P70 Delta says the justification
for having bases in Japan given by some
US people is protection of Japan from
China. Looking at history, it feels like
nonsense. What's my opinion? The
justification of having American bases
in Japan so that is that so that is so
that they can occupy Japan and hold this
very important geostrategic location.
It's nothing to do with the protection
of Japan.
When you have captured a territory, you
obviously want to protect it from your
enemies. So yeah, it's not because they
are doing this out of the the the
goodness of their hearts for the safety
and security of the Japanese people in
the in the nation. It's because they
have captured Japan and they don't want
to give it up. Right? And uh from look
if you let's take a look at the map and
understand why Japan is so important
strategically. Look at the location. Uh
where's the map? Here is the map. Let's
take a look at this. So we go to Japan
and you will see that the Japanese
territory it kind of prevents Russia
from uh sending its uh sending its
warships out in the into the Pacific
Ocean. So if if the if the Russians want
see for example the Russians have um a
naval fleet that is stationed around the
Vladivosto area over here and if they
want to send out let's say nuclear
submarines or warships out into the
Pacific they have to pass through
various choke points that you can
monitor if you are in occupation of
Japanese territory which is why it makes
a lot of sense for America to occupy
Japan and of course they can keep an eye
on Russia.
as well as China over here and possibly
target both of the nations from there
which is why Japan is a very very
important uh asset to have in your kitty
bag. So that's why the Americans have
hundreds well more than 130 military
bases in Japan. It's not for Japan's
protection. It's for power projection.
Prattana says there is something called
IVC infinity not see the similarity with
son shields. It also appears in Andhra
Pradesh later with exact same design.
The Indis Valley culture first of all
this is a misnomer. Let's understand
that it's not Indis Valley culture or
Indis Valley civilization. It's Indian
culture and civilization.
Now this infinity not it's it looks like
the infinity symbol right? Let's so
let's go and take a look at that. Let's
Google that. Okay. Uh I V C infinity not
did I get that right the spelling all
right endless not etc eight auspicious
symbols let's take a look at the Google
thing
um indis valley let's see indust
valley
infinity kn so this is the kind of uh
symbol it is and you will see it in
other parts of India also it's not just
like and and and in other time periods
in Indian history. So over here as you
can see on the right you have the script
with the same infinity symbol. Um so you
find it in various parts of India. Uh do
we find it here? Yeah something similar
to that
uh and so on.
Harapan symbol etc. It appears unchanged
in Gujarat in the 9th century CE. Okay.
This is an inscription from Gujarat. All
right. Uh and you find something similar
on Sonali shields. So it is something my
point is very very simple very it's a
point I've made so many times. Um
we've had cultural continuity going back
10,000 years. Right? The culture hasn't
changed. The culture that was practiced
during the Indust Valley times or
Sarasati Hindu times. It's the culture
we still practice in different forms
today. So, no surprises here, right? No
surprises.
Okay. What next is the question? 6P70
Delta says, "Being a viewer since
lockdown." Okay, that's that's been
Yeah, that that period of time. Pleased
to get a perspective to get to know a
perspective different from dominant
leftists. One
um sad to see the growth of your channel
seeing starting to resemble the Soviet
economy during Brev era. Well, look,
it's not in our hands. It's not in my
hands how the growth of the channel
goes. If the reach is restricted,
there's nothing I can do about it. It is
what it is. Let it be.
So, first of all, thank you very much
for having been a viewer since lockdown.
And uh we continue, right? We continue.
Karthik Arisha says, "Does Israel have
its own deep state have a deep state in
it in in its own country?" I don't know.
Maybe it does, maybe it doesn't. We
don't know. I don't have any u knowledge
of what's going on deep inside Israel.
Maybe it does, maybe some countries do
have that, maybe some countries don't.
So, can't say. Uh field strongman says,
"Hypothetically, I work at parliament.
Allegedly, my in instincts align with
external forces."
Okay. But ideally, no amount of dollars
should make me agree with racist posts
with against own people. Uh I would say
that I would agree with you that you may
work at hypothetically at parliament
your instincts may allegedly align with
external forces. Okay. But uh if you
work for parliament and you have taken
an oath of allegiance to India and so on
then and if you are Indian if you have
any selfrespect whoever you are whoever
you may be uh no amount of dollars
greenbacks should make you
you know agree with racist post against
your people. So yeah, I would completely
agree with this entirely utterly
hypothetical situation. Yes, completely
agree.
Um, Dignor Singh says, "What would
happen if Sam Manako had actually taken
over the country of India like Indira
Gandhi feared? Did she fear that Sam
Manuk would take over India?
Um, I am not aware of that fear of hers
if she if it existed. But let's say that
Sam Manuk actually took over the
country. What would have happened? Well,
the standards of the country would have
risen tremendously
assuming that he had the full support of
the military in his takeover of India
and then the military gets to call the
shots. So if that sort of thing happens
what could have happened what would have
happened is the Indian see first of all
we don't understand the strength of the
Indian military manpower uh perspective
what currently what is the the manpower
strength of the Indian military it's
it's a million something right maybe 2
million maybe in the past we've had a
military let's say even if you had 5
million personnel in the military and
they're all aligned with uh the person
who takes over the country in a coup
okay uh Can 5 million people control the
entire country? I suppose it's possible.
I mean, the British control the whole
country with 20,000 people. Yeah. You
know, so if they get it right, then
maybe they could control the country and
uh take the country forward in a
direction that was that would have been
different from what was happening. So if
Sam Mano had actually taken over India,
right, successfully,
then I suppose India would have turned
out to be very different. Let's say it
happened in 19 in the 1970s. That's
about 50 years ago. It would have given
India 50 years of a far better direction
in which than in in which India did did
go. So yeah, India could have possibly
been like like we all claim vishwa guru
superpower today possibly. Who knows?
Yeah.
MojiPo African says sudden drop in your
viewership and theories.
It is what it is. Yep. I don't care
what's not in my control. I don't worry
about at all. I I I enjoy doing what I'm
doing. I enjoy the viewership I have. I
enjoy connecting with you all. You
YouTube, whatever it wants to do, it can
keep doing. I have no issue with that.
It's their platform. It's it's their
choice. Let them do what they want. I'm
good to go. I have no issues.
Okay. Ankit Duta says, "As a founder, I
need DSA to build." What is DSA? First
of all, what is DSA? DSA to build tech
tech products. What makes an app
scalable and fast? Are rust C++ needed
or is JS enough? What's important? Where
to focus? It all depends on what you're
doing. What technology stack you use?
Depends on what you're trying to
achieve, right? What makes an app
scalable and fast? The back end has to
be super powerful. I mean, super super
aligned with whatever you're doing,
right? Of course you the back end means
your data uh that has to be on on on
point. Uh first of all let me see what
is DSA. Let's let's Google DSA. What is
DSA?
DSA can refer data structures and
algorithms.
Of course you need data structures and
How will you build tech products without
that?
Yeah. Uh yeah. So you need to have the
best possible algorithms.
Do you need data structures and
algorithms? If you are building a tech
product,
uh I think the backend company will take
care of all of that to give you blazing
fast uh access to the back end. I
suppose you will need data structures
and algorithms only if you are if you
are building a backend company or
something. Uh so what makes an app
scalable and fast? The the tech stack
matters.
um the the the the company that you hire
whose services you hire for the back end
and all that that matters. Rust, C++,
JS, it entirely depends on what you're
trying to achieve, sir. Entirely depends
on what you're trying to achieve.
Um yeah, so that's what I can say sir.
Dimnur Singh says, "How accurate is the
news that CIA agents planned to kill
Modi?" That's been all over the news,
right? Uh that Mr. Modi had gone for the
uh Shangai Cooperation Summit
organization SEO uh summit in China and
it is being said that there was a coup.
There was there was a a plot to
allegedly assassinate Mr. Modi. It's
been all over news. Twitter is full of
these theories. How accurate is this
news? and and apparently some some
individual was found uh not alive in in
Dhaka who has some background with you
know the US Marine Corps or something
like that. Uh is there a connection
between what have between what happened
in Dhaka and what was going on in China?
I don't know. So I see look I am sitting
here like all of you all. Okay. I don't
have any access to any any privileged
information any confidential or
classified information. I can't say and
neither do the people who are making
these speculations,
the people who are putting out these
pieces of analysis, speculation,
whatever you want to call it, do they
have access to any information that we
don't have access to? Are they part of
the raw or whatever it is? I don't know.
So, in the absence of any any,
you know, anything that corroborates
these claims, I would say it's pure
speculation. I I don't know if it's
accurate or not. Yeah.
Prardana says, "Future strategy for the
channel." We keep going. We keep going.
I I keep going essentially. Uh I enjoy
doing the Ask a Budget show. Um
I I've been doing this study with me
thing for a for quite a while which is
getting you know uh so that I will
complete 50 episodes and I'm done with
that also. Can't do that forever. and uh
let us see what else I can do with the
channel. Maybe I can do just see
essentially I can do whatever I want
with the channel. Uh it's not like it's
going to grow beyond beyond a million
anytime soon. So I can play around with
the channel. I don't know. I I I may do
something different. I may perhaps uh
start some kind of
We'll see. But what one thing I can
assure you is that the Ask show goes on.
That goes on. I have no intention of
ever stopping it. Yeah. So yeah.
Uh Basar Kayatwal says, "Seven months of
the year I'm in Moscow, rest of the time
in Bhat. You JD, Major Goravari and
others are always playing in my house."
My mom says as it feels like you are
part of our family already. Thank you so
much. I really appreciate it. Uh please
give my regards to your mom. Thank you
so much sir. Thank you so much. I really
appreciate that very much so. Animeish
says, "Happy 300th. Thank you very much.
Being a member since the 37th." Well,
thank you. Thank you. It's been a long
time. Am eternally indeed for the
transformation you have brought in me
and many many others. That's that's all
I try to that's all I seek to do. I seek
to share whatever I understand of the
world with you all in a way that you
want. That's why I have you ask the
questions and I answer the questions.
So, uh yeah, we keep going, right? and
and there's no greater privilege than
doing what I'm doing. So So yeah, thank
you.
Busai says, "First of all,
congratulations on for completing 300
episodes. Thank you very much, sir. Why
is Russian literature so d dark and
pessimistic as if the world will end
tomorrow?" Yeah, that's that's that's
a fact, isn't it? I mean, if you study
Russian literature, it's dark.
It's because Russian life, Russian
history has been dark. If you look at
Russian history, uh if you look at where
Russia is, first of all, I mean, take a
look at the map. There's a reason why I
open the map all the time. There's a
reason for it. If you look at the map,
it explains why things are the way that
they are. If you look at Russia, it's
all up there in the northern latitudes,
right?
uh very harsh climate, very cold,
lakes freeze over, rivers freeze over uh
even in summer it it it's colder than
what you would want it to be, especially
if you from from a place like India. So
first of all, the climate, the terrain,
all of that is pretty harsh, pretty
unforgiving. It's very hard to survive
over there, right?
That's one thing you don't understand.
And secondly, their history has been
full of all these tra tragedies, wars. I
mean, look at the history of the second
world war. How many Russians died like
27 million Russia lost so many people?
And then you have uh the before that you
had the Bolshevik revolution. Then you
had the the rule of Stalin, then you had
the rule of the you know the communist
party of the USSR.
It's it's it's it's a nation that's h
and before the communists take over you
have the the Romanov family that is that
is assassinated you know executed by the
communists before that you have the eras
of the sars you had uh Peter the great
yeah sure but also Ivan the terrible
Katherine the great uh very tough rulers
they've had and overall their history
has been has been full of tragedies and
it's it's just been that way so no
wonder that you know Russian literature
is dark and it's not entirely
pessimistic but it's pretty dark. I mean
if you read for example war and peace by
Toltoy it's got all these dark things
but it's not entirely pessimistic. Yeah
but the literature of the nation
reflects what the nation has gone
through. So no surprise there.
Ritik P says our country has produced
mediocre leaders
but the one thing that surprises me is
that is how they've managed to keep
India a sovereign nation at least
militarily. See uh yeah
yeah yeah we are against all odds still
sovereign.
We have produced very mediocre leaders
because the system is designed to
produce mediocrity. The system is
designed to to promote mediocrity and on
the on the other hand it's it's it's
designed to seek out and destroy talent
which is why all talented people leave
the country right uh yeah but we are
still still sovereign and if things if
the gods keep smiling on us then maybe
in the future we'll we'll produce better
leaders right right now we have a good
leader no question about that uh Mr.
Modi the way I see it some of you may
disagree that's fine but the way I see
it uh he is the best prime minister
we've had despite all my personal
frustrations also about various things
but still overall if you look at it he's
the we are lucky that we have someone
like him and hopefully in the future we
have leaders who are even better so
let's see
Dnur Singh says some people blame MI6
for killing the CIA guy in Dhaka well I
have no idea honestly I have no idea
some guy dies in Dhaka and um allegedly
he's taken away he's uh without any any
autopsy or whatever and that's the end
of it as far as far as we know MI6 is
the British intelligence agency CIA is
the well the Americans and then you have
various other intelligence agencies so I
have no idea look it's all speculation I
have no way of corroborating uh whether
it's correct or or whether you know
telling you assertaining whether it's
false. I have absolutely no idea. It's
all speculation at at this time and the
people who are speculating I don't think
they have any access to any any
confidential information. So on what
basis are they speculating? I have no
idea but maybe there may be some some
potentially possibly some grain of truth
behind it but I can't say.
Tarun says was Iran a major source for
foreign migration to India as 90% of
Mughal cortisans after Hayun's return
were Persians and they all settled here.
Does it explain why many modernday
Shia Muslims are of Iranian descent?
Was Iran a major source of foreign
migration? It's a tiny source of foreign
migration. How many mogul courters did
you have in India? 100, 200, 5,000,
20,000,
whatever the number you can come up
with. Let's say 90% of that is is is
Iranians. So if you had the incredibly
fantastic number of 20,000 Mughal
courters and 90% of that is Iranians,
that's that's 18,000.
out of a population of what 330 million
Indians undivided India that's that's
insignificant
completely insignificant you see if you
put it in the in the in the proper
perspective you will see that 18,000
people which obviously was not the case
you did not have 18,000 Iranians who
came and were part of the Mughal court
um but you but see back in the day
you do not have any visas you do have
passports. You could just, you know,
travel to countries and as long as you
were there on legitimate business or
whatever your purpose was, it was seen
as legitimate, you were allowed to come.
There was no visa applications in blah
blah. So, so India and Persia were
anyway neighboring civilizations and
Persians used to come to India. Indians
used to go to Persia. Uh,
yeah. So, that's how it was. Um, many
modern day Shia Muslims are of Iranian
descent. Well, I was not aware of that.
I don't know about the history of Shia
Muslims in India. Uh, it's not something
I've studied. Um, what I know is that
lot of
see some of them are of Yemeni descent
if I'm not mistaken.
Some people especially the the Shia
Muslims who are of Gujarati origin the
the Bodhi people many of them seem to
have some kind of connection with with
uh with Yemen once again I am not very
clear about their history either so I
can't say but yeah when it comes to
India Iranian India we are neighboring
regions so no no surprise if there is
significant Iranian you know presence in
India first of all the genetics of the
two peoples they aren't that different
Right.
Okay. 6P70 Delta says, "Us US YouTubers,
okay, American YouTubers make videos
weekly about UA, Ukraine, hammering
Russia and wiping out the so-called
orcs, but also run fundraiser campaigns
for Ukraine, mainly Azov V Battalion.
If Ukraine is really willing, why
winning, why are they asking for
donations?"
you know, this propaganda has been going
on since uh early 2022. The special
military operation, like Donald Trump
says, it was it's not a war. It's a
special military operation. He also
agrees with me now, Trump. So, the
special military operation, SMO, started
in February. It it began on the 22nd of
February, 2022. And ever since this
started there is there has been you know
this campaign of misinformation in the
western media claiming that Ukraine is
winning. At some point in time they were
saying that Putin is dying. He's got
cancer. He's got three months to live.
Some point in time they were saying that
Bakmut is you know Ukraine is winning
Bakmut. And when Russia takes over
Bakmut they said that why is Russia
taking has taken over Bakmut? This this
completely insignificant city. So if it
was so insignificant why were you
talking about it for 6 months? and so
on, you know. So, they have been
claiming that Russia is losing and
Ukraine is winning since 2022.
It's been over 3 years
and yeah, like you say, if Ukraine is
winning, why are they really asking for
donations? And now Trump himself is
saying that Ukraine will be wiped out if
they don't agree with to Russia's deed.
And we know that Russia is way too
powerful and over the past 3 years,
their military-industrial complex has
really taken off. Their economy is doing
well despite all the sanctions.
You know, Russia is not going anywhere
and people like Zalinsky have have been
responsible for destroying their country
because Russia's reasons for going to
war are legitimate reasons. I mean,
imagine
China or Russia funding Mexico and doing
a regime change there. Will the US allow
that to happen? They won't, right?
Similarly, Russia also can't allow
things certain things to happen in
Ukraine and that's why they had to go to
war. They did their best to prevent a
war, but eventually they had to. Right.
Fast snail. That's quite a name.
That's quite a name. Fast snail. Is US
aggression in Latin America due to
Chinese influence?
Uh no. See the US the you know some of
some people may say that what I am
saying is outdated obsolete because this
is the 19th century century matter. The
Monroe doctrine. What was the Monro
doctrine? The Mandro doctrine was this
US policy that no external power will be
allowed to influence any part of the
Americas. The US has to be the
predominant power in the Americas
whether it is North America or South
America. England isn't allowed to
interfere. Spain is no longer allowed to
inter interfere even though they created
these colonies right by taking over
native land.
uh once the Monro doctrine came into
force the US was very clear only the US
has the right to complete hedgemony in
the Americas. Now if you look at uh and
and most Latin American nations today
they they bow down to American wishes
they never do a thing that displeases
the US uh you know in in any major way.
But Venezuela and Cuba are two
exceptions. So Cuba is not in Latin
America, it's in the Caribbean region.
And the Cubans have steadfastly been
super independent and uh yeah the you
could say anti- US. The Americans say
they are anti- US. And secondly,
Venezuela. Venezuela has uh refused to
well cave into the US. They they are
socialists and so on. So uh that's why
the US is aggressive towards Venezuela
and anybody else who deser who who who
dares to challenge the US in any way.
It's not because of Chinese influence.
Obviously the Chinese have some role to
play in this a little bit which is um
something that's happened only in the
last 1015 years maybe the last 15 20
years maximum that the Chinese have had
a presence in Latin America for
extracting resources out of nations like
Brazil etc. But this uh US aggression
like you say US hedgemony it it dates
back well to the 19th century. So it's
nothing to do with China overall.
Tanmai says your views on attempt to
attack Modi at the SEO summit. There is
no evidence that this happened. There's
all kinds of rumors and speculation
going on in in social media but I don't
know if this is true. Right. I
personally have seen no evidence and I
am not in connect contact with any
government agencies or whatever who will
allow me to see evidence. So I have no
idea. I it's it's possible that this
could be just pure speculation and
rumors and it's also possible that may
there may be some truth to it. So I
can't say my views is that my what are
my views? I have no idea what's
happening. That's my views. I don't
know. Could be possible, could be true,
could maybe not. Uh DN Singh says so
apparently Columbus was a Jew secretly.
I have no idea about this sir. I have no
idea.
Um so Dn Singh says apparently Columbus
was a Jew secretly found the USA in 1492
when Jews were expelled from Spain.
Coincidence.
Yes. The reconista
happened. It it it culminated in the
expulsion of the Jews from from Spain in
1492.
And that's when Columbus discovers the
Americas, not the USA. He never set foot
in what is now called the USA. Uh he
never even saw with his own eyes what is
now called the USA. But he set foot in
the Caribbean region and eventually
during this third voyage in uh he was
able to see South America as well. The
first European to do that, Venezuela if
I'm not mistaken.
So
um
and he was of Italian origin of course
and he was financed by the by the king
and queen of Spain.
So if the Spaniards had done a reconista
and u expelled all the Muslims and the
Jews from their country, then why would
they fund a person who was secretly
Jewish to go and search for India?
Unless they did not know that he was
Jewish. Was Columbus Jewish? Let's let's
do a quick fact fact check. Uh let's
see. Was Columbus Jewish? Let's see. Was
Christopher
Columbus
Jewish? Was he?
Recent genetic research suggests that
Christopher Columbus may have been a
Spanish Sephardic Jew, challenging the
traditional view that he was Italian.
This theory proposes that he was from
the Iberian Peninsula, possibly
Valencia, and and concealed his Jewish
identity due to religious persecution at
the time. The evidence supporting this
is not universally accepted and some
scholars point to the lack of conclusive
proof. Genetic evidence. A recent study
analyzing DNA from Columbus's remains
found the genetic markers are compatible
with the Spanish Jewish origin.
The research suggests that he may have
been from a family of silk weavers in
Valencia, an area with a large Jewish
community. Many Jews and Muslims were
forced to convert VA. Yeah. Okay. Yeah.
The theory suggests that Columbus may
have been one of these new Christians
who secretly practiced their Jewish
faith.
The traditional view holds that Columbus
was in Okay, fine.
Okay. So, there's no evidence. Uh,
genetics,
it cannot tell you what a person
actually practiced, what religion a
person practiced. Yeah, possibly there
is some connection with Sephardic Jews.
That's what this says. I haven't first
of all seen the actual research. Is
there a research paper behind this? We
are doing a live stream so I will not go
and do all that right now. But
interesting interesting maybe I will
look into this in the future. Yeah.
Busker says I sent several super chats
yesterday. Possible to review them.
Um this is a different live stream. It
won't be possible to review yesterday's
super chats in this live stream. Uh and
yesterday was not a super chat live
stream. You should not have done that
sir. Yesterday I took questions from the
comments.
So yeah, I'm I'm very sorry that you
sent super chats and I could not see
those. Won't be possible to review those
today. Very sorry. I apologize. Yeah, I
apologize.
Hershel Shing Singla says, "What will
India do after sanctions to Russian oil
companies? What's your take? What what
should we do and what do you think the
government will do?"
Well, what should we do? What will the
government do? I don't think the Indian
government wants to be in a
confrontation with the US.
Um, so maybe we will reduce our intake
of Russian oil. Yeah, it's it's a
possibility. I would not want that to
happen, but if it affects us
uh in a negative way, then it is not a
good idea. And I'm sure the Russians
will understand.
Um so I would not want that to happen.
What should we do?
We should do whatever is best for us in
the long term. You know long-term uh
always always prioritize the long term
over the short term. A long term we
understand that our relationship with
Russia is good. It's been good long-term
in the past also and it should remain
good long term in the future also.
temporarily maybe we possibly may reduce
our consumption of Russian oil but it's
a temporary thing perhaps and uh
what do I think the government will do
the government I think they are
prioritizing the trade deal with the US
right now and a trade deal may not
happen unless we agree to certain terms
from the US so maybe temporarily
or maybe long-term we may cut down on
Russian oil it looks like it may happen
right now which is not something that
pleases me but it may happen.
Yeah. Because it should not the sanction
we should not be in a position next that
we ourselves are sanctioned. Right.
We've had American sanctions in the
past. Uh when did that happen? It
happened in uh 1998 after our nuclear
tests and we don't want to be in that
situation again. So maybe we will you
know
uh maybe we will make that sort of a
choice for now.
BJ Sai says during the Vic period Lord
Indra was the god that was most prayed
to then why did we stop praying today no
one stopping you from from praying to
Lord Indra things change things change
the Vic period was not first of all we
don't understand the how how how
long how ancient our history is our
history is so ancient that there was a
river that we used to pray to that no
longer exists Our history spans
geological time time periods.
Time spans, right? Thousands of years.
Our history goes back about 10,000
years, maybe most likely even longer
than that. So if your history is so old,
massive, massive changes will happen in
your history.
One of the reasons the Saraswati dried
out is because there was a shortfall of
rain,
right?
And who was the god responsible for
rain? It was Indra. So Indra did not
Indra stopped blessing us. So maybe
that's why we stopped praying to Indra.
I don't know. It's a possibility. U
there could be multiple reasons. Maybe
the emergence of new gods or new aspects
of divinity.
We still worship Saraswati as the
goddess of of of uh knowledge and
wisdom. We no longer worship Dors Pitru,
the oldest of the gods, right? The
skyfather. We know people don't even
remember Dioshitra today. People still
do remember Indra, but in a different
way from what Indra used to be, the
great warrior god. So
primarily it's because our history is so
ancient. 10,000 years is not day before
yesterday, right? 10,000 years a lot of
changes happen in 10,000 years. We no
longer refer to Lord Shiva as Rudra in
the Rigida. All you see all you will see
is rdraha
that's not
that isra
but whatever right so there's been so
much change in India that's how it goes
says big fan thank you sir thank you
very much I have heard the rumor that
the voke movement originated in the US
it was originated and orchestrated by
the French intelligence as a means to
degrade the US from within is it true
thanks
Well, uh, what you could what you could
call the the origins of the Voke
movement comes out of, uh, movements
such as, uh, what was it called?
Jacqu Deida and, uh, Jean Paul Sak.
I forget what it was called, but yeah,
some of it does originate from from
France.
Um,
some of it also originated in Germany by
the way. Yeah.
So, is it possible that the French
intelligence was involved in this? It it
the possibility does exist. I'll tell
you what about France. France is the one
European nation that is not entirely
subjugated and controlled by the US.
France has a quasi independent foreign
policy to some extent. And I can also
assure you that the French intelligence
does not regard the US as a friendly
nation. That I can assure you of.
Okay. So it is certainly possible that
there could have been something like
this because see you've got to play the
long-term game. You have to think in
terms of decades and centuries. You have
to think in terms of time periods in
which you may no longer be in existence
anymore, but you've got to account for
that. So, it's possible the French
intelligence may have planted the seeds
of what is now vocism in the United
States back in the 1950s and60s. It's
possible. Yeah,
it is certainly possible. Um, I still
don't I'm trying to remember what was
this movement called. Let's let's Google
it. Uh,
Jacqu Dida.
Uh, what was it called? Deconstruction
etc.
phenomenology, deconstruction,
um, hospitality, margins of philosophy,
fukult,
derida and fukult and fu.
Oh, come on.
Fukulta debate. Postmodernism. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. Okay. Postmodernism.
So, this entire voke nonsense comes out
of postmodernism.
And I have tried to understand what
postmodernalism is. I've even tried to
read some of the literature. I um
apologize but I is I am not sufficiently
intelligent to understand what it's all
about. I have never been able to wrap my
my head around it. It sounds like
nonsense. It sounds like there is
nothing to it. Just word salads. Yeah.
Hersh Rati says, "Please check Kan Jats
Reik
phrase Ajay Jarto Hunan." I have no idea
what you're saying, sir. Kanj
Vicki phrase a jar hunan.
Um, okay sir. Thank you. I I'm not sure
what you're saying. Aronomous scientist
says, "Will we ever be able to unify all
four fundamental forces like the theory
of everything by Stephven Hawking? What
would such a theory explain about the
universe? I don't know what it would
explain. Will we be able to unify all
four fundamental forces? Okay, first of
all, what are the four fundamental
forces? We have the strong nuclear
force. We have the the weak nuclear
force. We have the electromagnetic force
and then we have the force of gravity.
But if you look at gravity from the
perspective of general relativity of
geometronamics,
then gravity is not a force.
Gravity is not a force. It's the
curvature of spaceime that accounts for
what we what appears to be to us this
force that is gravity. But it's not a
force. It's the consequence of the
warping or curvature of spacetime.
So if you want to unify the four
fundamental forces, you have to do that
in curved spaceime. Right? Now what
happens when you try to do quantum
mechanics in curved space time? It's not
compatible.
Yeah. First of all, time itself doesn't
seem to it seems to be an external
parameter in quantum physics, in quantum
mechanics and quantum field theory. So,
uh yeah, I'm sure in the future we may
be able to unify, you know, have a
single equation that accounts for
everything. But, uh how would we do it?
I'm not sure you know and one of the
major questions is about time. Time I
mean yeah sure we have four even if we
consider G gravity to be a force. Okay,
let's say you want to unify the four
forces. But where does time figure in
all of this? Time is even an even bigger
mystery than all of these things.
The big question is what is time? What
is time? Yeah, it's something you see on
the on the on the watch. You look at
your phone and you see what time it is.
Wonderful. Brilliant. What is time?
Where does it emerge from? Where does it
come from? Is it intrinsic to the
structure of spaceime? It doesn't seem
to be. Does it emerge from somewhere? Is
it an emerging phenomenon?
Do you have quanta of time? Do you have
atoms and molecules of time? What where
does it come from? We only vaguely
perceive it. So, how do you fit time
into all of this? You can't fit time
into quantum mechanics as as an an
integral outcome of quantum mechanics.
Time is an external parameter. So, um
big big questions and we don't have the
answers right now. And what if we are
able to unify everything into a single
theory, a grand unified theory, what
would such a theory explain about the
universe? I think it may raise more
questions than answers.
Yeah. I mean it what will it tell us? It
will tell us how all the four forces are
related to each other and it may explain
to us the nature of reality better. It
may even explain what time is. But then
the bigger question will arise
why why this equation? Why not a
different equation? Yeah.
And another question is will it be able
to explain the constants
the constants of physics?
The constants of physics physics seems
to be seem to be hardcoded into reality.
Who did the hard coding?
Who did the hard coding? Who programmed
that? Who's the programmer?
So I think even if you have a grand
unified theory, it may still just tell
you that what the program is, what the
software is. It won't tell you who wrote
the software. Right? These are these are
questions that are bigger than the
universe itself.
Right? Okay. Divor Singh says if
Churchill actually drank liters of
alcohol and a few cigars every day, how
did he even lead? I don't think
Churchill drank liters of alcohol every
day. And okay yeah so he was fond of
cigars right we know that he used to
smoke a cigar every evening or something
smoking a cigar takes about an hour
depending on the size
so if you want to spend an hour not
doing any work then you sit down in a
cigar lounge and have a cigar and when
it comes to alcohol I I am told if I
recall correctly I'm not told I read
that he used to drink brandy he used to
drink a quart a quarter of brandy not
not litters. So every day in the evening
he had this this time that he he would
have for himself in which he would have
a quarter of brandy
and a cigar. So maybe this whole
ritual would take about an hour, hour
and a half and uh so that's how it was
for him. So clearly if you drink liters
of alcohol every day you want you won't
function let alone lead. But if you
drink a quarter of of
brandy or whiskey or whatever, I suppose
you can still be a functioning
alcoholic. Yeah. So I suppose that's
that's what he was. He was not the
healthiest person. He did not have the
healthiest lifestyle. And uh yeah, he
and and the thing about cigars is that
you don't you don't inhale the smoke.
People who smoke cigarettes, they inhale
the smoke. That goes into their lungs
and it messes them up very badly
obviously depending on how many they
smoke. But cigars are not supposed to be
inhaled. So it doesn't really affect
your your health badly. Unless you're
inhaling that otherwise if you do that I
suppose you will meet your maker very
soon. So I think that's that was a deal
with Churchill.
Um Zeir right Zafir Zafir says we
Chinese think fascism is coming back and
we hosted a grand parade
September 3rd. Is anti-fascism a thing
in India? Indians don't even know what
fascism is. Indian don't Indians don't
care what fascism is. Fascism is a thing
that was a thing in Italy, wasn't it? Um
during the first half roughly first half
of the 20th century and uh
and Mussolini El Dulce right Benito
Mussolini was the fascist dictator of
Italy and he was an ally of Adolf
Hitler. So fascism is a thing that's u
that's western in nature. Uh there is no
equivalent of that movement or that
ideology in India.
U so if it could be coming back it could
be coming back in the west. Yeah I'm
sure there is there is there are some
people who are sympathetic to that
ideology in the west as are some people
as you have well have some people who
are sympathetic to every ideology you
can imagine. But it's not a thing in
India. So anti-fascism is not a thing in
India. Most of 99% of Indians won't even
know what fascism is and they won't care
about it.
Vishal Nas says good evening. Good
evening sir. Why is the Schinger
equation considered to be the core of
quantum mechanics? Good question. Why is
the Schoinger equation considered to be
the core of quantum mechanics? What does
the Scholinger equation do? It describes
well there are two forms of the
Scholinger equation. One is a time
dependent one, one is a time independent
one. And uh it essentially tells you see
in the shing see the shinger equation is
a differential equation a partial
differential equation and the argument
in this it's it's s which is uh the wave
function what is the wave function it's
not a physical thing but the wave
function if you you know it's complex
conjugate it it describes the
probability
of finding a particle in a certain
location in in space not in spaceime but
in space. Uh so the Schroinger equation
if you solve it it will tell you
essentially where you can find the
particle where the likelihood of finding
the particle is higher where it's lower
and so on. Um and because of that it is
the core of quantum mechanics. It's
quantum mechanics is all about all about
subatomic particles and the equation
that describes the behavior of subatomic
subatomic particles is the sodinger
equation. Uh and uh yeah so so that's
about it. That's that's what I can
explain in brief.
Literally officer K says how are some
cookie infiltrators calling themselves
Jewish? the flag of their proposed
cookie land as the star of David on it.
I have no idea. They claim apparently
some of their religious practices are
similar to Jewish
uh religious practices. So they have
started calling themselves one of the
lost tribes of Israel. They the you know
the if you look at Jewish history there
are some lost tribes apparently. I
haven't really studied that in in
detail. Uh but the cookies claim that
they are one of the lost tribes of
Israel. And I I'm sure that genetic
tests were done on the on on these
people who call themselves cookies. And
I and am certain that there was not even
a drop of Jewish blood that was found in
these people. But many of them have
moved to Israel and they have been
baptized or whatever the procedure is
for Jewish people and they are now
Israeli citizens some of them. Right.
um others other cookies are Christian.
So I don't know what the logic the
rationale is but apparently some
religious practices of theirs are
similar to Jewish things and that's why
they have been allowed to become Jewish.
So those of them who want to go to
Israel they claim that they are Jewish
and they go and move there and that's
about it. And uh there are various
versions of their flag of this
artificial fictitious nation called
Cookie Land and some of these versions
have the star of David on it. Yeah.
Shashad Jenna says big fan. Thank you
very much. Thank you sir. Uh you have
always said that the humanities of IITs
are west colonized. Is the medic medical
education of India west colonized also
or is it good? I don't know. I have no
exposure to the medical education system
of India.
Um so I I can't really say the IIT
why do they even need humanities
departments?
These are the Indian institutes of
technology. Please teach technology.
If someone wants to get exposure to the
humanities, they can do it in their own
godamn free time. The internet will give
you all the information that you need
that you seek.
The IITs have no business setting up
sociology departments and humanities
departments. This is a waste of taxpayer
money. And the humanities departments in
the IIAS if you see the kind of research
output that's coming out of that out of
those it's it's garbage. It's totally
anti-India which obviously is pro- west.
Right? So that's why I say that. Now the
medical education system of India I have
no idea. I have never looked into it so
I can't really say. Sorry.
Wun says Google says China invented
gunpow
shows ara shastra mentions the same and
predates China. Same bias with molecule.
Why?
If you so I won't be able to do do this
right now, but there is there are
multiple levels and layers of evidence
that demonstrate that explosive chemical
powders were known in India long before
this supposed date when China invented
gunpowder. Now what is an explosive
chemical powder? It obviously is
gunpowder. You can't you don't need
necessarily need to have just one
chemical composition or one chemical
formula of gunpowder. You can have
different ways of producing explosive
chemical powders. Right?
So the truth is that India is the
civilization that invented gunpowder
long before China. But if you ask
Google, if I can if I do it right now,
it'll tell you that it's China. Why is
it biased? Because this is called
algorithmic bias. AI will have biases.
Whatever information you feed AI while
training AI, while training it, it will
be biased in that manner. So whatever
information it has absorbed, it's going
to tell you that it's not AI's fault.
It's the fault of the people who trained
the AI, right? And it's the west that
did that. And obviously the west is
biased. There is a strong anti-india
bias in the west. So no surprises there.
All right. Anonymous scientist says five
four more most interesting
archaeological mysteries according to
me.
Okay. Interesting archaeological
mysteries. Well, one is Duara.
Yeah.
Darka and the overall
broader issue of the Gulf of Kat
archaeological complex.
You have apparently these ancient cities
that are on the ocean ocean floor that
are laid out in the same grid structure
that you find in cities of the Saraswati
Hindu region the so-called Harapan
cities Mahjadaro Harapa Rakari etc. The
same grid structure that you find in
civilized countries today in advanced
countries today we are of course a
civilized country but we are not
advanced we are a third world country.
So the same grid structure you have
right and and these cities are sitting
on the bottom of the ocean floor in the
Gulf of Kad and the last time you that
that part of the ocean floor was above
sea level was about 10,000 or so years
ago. So how did our ancestors build
these cities 10,000 years ago that are
laid out in a modern grid structure big
archaeological mystery? Same to same
about Darkara. Duara is also in the same
overall region slightly for the west.
Uh and it's a mystery why the government
of India won't fund any excavations or
or any archaeological investigations of
these structures. That's one. Uh what
else? What else? Uh Egyptian pyramids,
Egyptian history overall. I mean, who
built the pyramids? Obviously, the
Egyptians would have built them, not
UFOs, not aliens, but how did they do
it, right? Uh, and what lies bene
beneath the pyramids. So, if you when I
was a kid, you know, there used to be
these movies about Egypt in which we are
told that the the the pyramids are these
places where the pharaohs, the Egyptian
kings were buried. But the fact is that
not a single Egyptian mummy has been
found in a single pyramid. The question
is then what was the purpose of building
the pyramids? If these are not tombs for
emperors,
what was the real purpose? We don't
know. A big mystery. Um then you have,
you know,
South America, the Inca Empire. U you
have these stones, you know, walls
for let's let's Google that. If you go
to a place like Cusco, for example,
Yeah.
CO
walls, stones,
okay, wall, stone, whatever you want to
say. Look at this.
I mean, how on earth were these stones
fixed in this manner,
right? Incredible. Gigantic stones,
massive stones that are almost
impossible to lift without, you know,
cranes.
and and uh mechanized equipment,
enormous stones, and they all fit so
incredibly precisely.
How did How was this done? Look at the
fit. Look at Look at how incredibly
precisely the stones fit. There's no
gaps. You can't even put a knife through
the in the gaps. How was this done? Who
How did the the people who made this do
it?
It's it's it's a huge mystery. So, I
suppose that's three mysteries, right?
That's Cusco,
Peru, present day Peru. Peru. Yeah,
probably Peru. Uh, what else? What other
mysteries can I think of
archaeologically?
I'm sure there's plenty.
Okay, let me think of one more
archaeological mystery.
Yeah, I can't think right now.
Yeah, I I I'll I'll I'll keep it at
three, but yeah, three that I can think
of. Very interesting. If something comes
to my mind, I'll I'll let you know.
Okay. Fast snail. Lovely name. I love
it. Uh Colombia. Is it Colombia or is it
Colombia? Colombia. Oenor. Colombia.
Colombia. Muls ending US military
presence possible. Um
let us see. Let's Google this. Colombia
US military. Colombia
US military bases. Let's see. Is there
any news regard regarding this? Ole
Maida U air base. Okay. Colombian
airfield. Seven new US bases. Do we have
any news?
What's at stake? Trump pro feud strains
the US Colombia alliance. Petro Muls
ending US in military and CIA presence
in Colombia. Will this happen? It won't
happen.
It won't happen. Yeah. Is it possible?
Well, possible. Anything is possible.
But will it happen? I think it's very
unlikely
that they will be able to ask the, you
know, make the Americans
vacate the country. I think it's Yeah,
it's it's it's a it's not going to
happen.
WMA Nadim Pali says, "Why do a lot of
historians claim that there are no
chhatrias in South India despite the
existence of pandas, cha cha, chas?
I have no idea. There's an agenda,
right? There's an agenda to separate
South India and North India.
I don't say South India. I say Southern
India and Northern India, right?
Southern and Northern because words
matter. They want South India and North
India separate. And they want to claim
that South Indian culture has nothing to
do with northern Indian culture and
Hinduism and and everything else is a is
a is a northern imposition. It's an
Arian imposition on southern India. And
southern India is the original India,
the true indigenous India and northern
Indians, people from northern India are
are imposters, invaders, descendants of
barbarians and so on.
But if you have the same societal
structures in northern and southern
India, then you can't make the claim.
That's why you have to deny these
things. So you have to deny that you
know there are no kri in south India
which is a lie. Obviously a lie. So it's
an agenda. It's an agenda-driven thing.
The agenda is to fragment India. The
agenda is to create more divisions among
our people. That's the agenda. That's
why all these claims are made and we
have to ridicule these claims because
they are ridiculous and they are
outright lies.
What says magnetic field requires moving
charges to exist. Then how come spinning
neutron stars have massive magnetic
fields if the net charge of neutrons is
zero?
Um magnetic fields require massive
moving charges to exist then how come
spinning neutron charge stars have
massive magnetic fields. If the net
charge of neutrons is zero see neutron
stars don't only have neutrons they also
have other charged particles. They are
mostly made of neutrons but they also
have an atmosphere which is iron plasma.
They also have charges on their surfaces
and that's why they have massive
magnetic fields. It's not like they're
completely electrically neutral. They
have charges. Without charges, you're
right. You won't have magnetic fields.
So, neutron charges, neutron stars have
charges. They they may mostly be
electrically neutral. If you look at a
macros spokic
perspective, but if you look if you do a
cross-section, you will find different
uh you know, you have nuclear pasta
inside and stuff. So there's going to be
charged regions in neutron stars and
neutron stars spin so incredibly fast
which also creates so even if you have
small charges but they're spinning so
incredibly fast the magnetic fields that
result as a that are produced as a
result are going to be very powerful so
that's the deal
fimate says is it safe to assume that
post 1947 Indian government neg
neglected the far east of India and
that's why we see so much racism against
northeast people.
See after 1947
the far east of India was given utterly
stepmotherly treatment by the government
of India completely neglected. You are
right absolutely neglected. There was no
development done there.
um you know and and the whole region was
essentially cut off from the rest of
India. Uh most Indians did not even know
what existed in the far east of India,
what the people there looked like.
And because of this stepmotherly
treatment, you had the
the emergence of all these insurgency
movements and separatist movements all
across the far east of India. Every
state had multiple ins insurgencies,
right?
which was just just mismanagement.
Terrible, terrible. Uh so that's the
reason why you had so many insurgencies
that cropped up and still you know you
still are dealing with the consequences
of that today in the Far East. Uh when
it comes to racism against northeast
people
uh it's because most Indians were not
aware of what northeast Indians looked
like because there was no national
integration. There were only slogans of
national integration. we have to be
nationalally integrated blah blah blah
slogans but no actual work done to
actually integrate Indians from various
parts of of the country
and Indians
knew what Chinese people look like right
now see if you are Indian and you have
never been abroad to you a person from
Sweden from Denmark from France from
Italy from Norway from Germany from
England they look the same they look the
same right
no question about it they will all look
the same just they're just white people
for you
similarly if you have never been outside
of India never been exposed to this then
people from Japan Korea China Mongolia
etc they will also look the same to you
even though they they are different
so India fought a war with China 1962 we
lost right because of our government's
terrible handling of the matter so we
already had this this deep angst anguish
in our in our hearts that we lost
territory to the Chinese. The Chinese
are evil and then we know what the
Chinese look like. You know the
stereotype of what Chinese look like and
that is kind of similar in some ways if
you are not well informed to what people
from various parts of northeast India
look like. Now even among the
northeastern you know of the far eastern
people of India different different
states they look different but you have
to be aware of that. So because Indians
had no exposure you know India from the
so-called main Indians from the
so-called mainland of India had no
exposure to people from the far east of
India that's why when you would see
somebody like that you would assume that
they're Chinese or maybe Nepalese and
that sort of thing but mainly Chinese
and that's why you would have you know
mistreatment or whatever or what you
call racism today it has reduced
drastically because now Indians because
of social media and because India is so
much more mobile today Indians most
Indians from various parts of the
country know what the people of the far
east look like today so today it's it's
not the case it's it's much
significantly lesser than than in the
past but yeah historically this is the
reason why you had all these issues in
India the government was a massive
failure massive failure kesh kakoshik
says congratulations on 300 sir thank
you very much been watching since 2021
that's essentially the beginning thank
you very much thank you very much sir
thank Thank you so much for raising your
standards. You're very welcome. Sad to
see the US limiting your reach. I don't
care. It's fine. Please add more
regional languages in post stream VODs
for more audience. I will consider that.
Sure. Um
um more regional languages. How to do
that? I'll have to look into that. I'm
sure it'll involve more work. But let's
see if it's possible. I will be happy to
do that. So Kesh Kaj, thank you so much.
Kanesh Koshik G, thank you very much. I
really really appreciate your having
been here since 2021 and many more years
to go. Thank you very much sir. Thank
you. Anumita Roy. Thank you very much. I
think ma'am. Thank you very much. Thank
you. Rahul Lak Manan says, "When can we
see updates to geostrategy.ac?"
Yep, it'll happen eventually when I get
a little more time on my hands. I'm more
into writing these days and in case you
are aware, I'm writing. I'm writing a
lot. So that will also happen.
Ankit GI says Cambodia's prime minister
nominates Trump for Nobel Peace Prize
after a peace deal with Thailand. What
is the truth of this deal? Why doesn't
he try to strike a peace deal between
Afghanistan and Pakistan? Thailand,
Cambodia, it's easy to do that, right?
These two nations aren't that powerful.
They don't have nuclear weapons. They
don't have any any massive armed forces.
And the dispute is about a Hindu temple
and and multiple Hindu temples mainly
the the Priya Vihar temple and the US
can easily end you know bring about a
ceasefire without actually resolving any
issue right Trump is all about
ceasefires he doesn't resolve any actual
matter he resolves nothing the issue
still stands
the the po the point of contention
between Thailand and Cambodia
is the Priya Vihar temple which is a
1,000 plus year old temple. Both nations
claim it. Both nations want it. They
both crave it. Has Trump been able to
resolve the problem, the core issue at
the heart of the matter? No. It's a
ceasefire which means that we will fight
maybe some other day.
So that's what Trump does. He wants to
add all of this to his resume and he he
craves the Nobel Peace Prize. So if you
want to please Trump, you have to
nominate him for a Nobel Peace Prize and
he'll be like nice to you, nice towards
you, towards your country. So Cambodia's
prime minister is the son of Mr. Hunen.
Mr. Hunen is the long-term military
strongman, military dictator of of
Cambodia. Now he has uh stepped into a
more advisory kind of role where he
where he still holds all the power and
his son is now the prime minister. Mr.
Hunen's son, I forget his name.
Um yeah, so Mr. Hunen's son is a smart
man. You know, nominate Mr. Trump for
the Peace Prize.
The truth of the deal is that it doesn't
resolve the problem. There's no real
deal. It's just a ceasefire. That's it.
Uh why doesn't he try to strike a peace
deal between Afghanistan and Pakistan?
Because you can't
because you can't strike a peace deal
between Afghanistan and Pakistan without
resolving the issue which is causing the
fighting. What is the core issue? It's a
territorial dispute. It is far bigger
than the issue with Kashmir. Afghanistan
claims massive Pakistani occupied
territory. Kaibar Pakuna which
historically should be Afghan territory
because it is a pashon dominated
dominated region where pashons haven't
come in yesterday or day before
yesterday. They they've been living
there for centuries. So that territory
actually belongs with Afghanistan and it
is currently occupied by Pakistan and
the Taliban are pashon nationalist. They
want their ancestral territory back
which is why you have a massive problem
between Pakistan and Afghanistan which
is made worse by the fact that Pakistan
is a terrorist nation right and also
made worse by the fact that Pakistan
treats the pashon people very badly.
Trump can't resolve this matter. He can
all he can do is order a ceasefire or or
urge both sides to do a ceasefire but
that is only postponing the issue for
tomorrow or day after tomorrow right so
Trump is not really making any peace
anywhere he's just
create you know urging ceasefires
everywhere I did this I did that come on
man if you are really a peacemaker you
have to resolve the problems what's the
resolution to the Afghanistan Pakistan
problem there's only one resolution
karaku A needs to go back to
Afghanistan. That is the only just
resolution of the issue. Which means we
have to redraw the map of this temporary
artificial nation which will happen
sooner or later.
Shishir Upadia says Upadia.
Okay. Shishir says why did Germany
become the most immigrated country in
the EU? You see, Germany,
Germany is a fantastic nation which is
under foreign occupation since 1945.
Uh
you could argue that it's a it's an
artificial nation because there was no
Dutch chalanda before 1871.
You never had a unified Germany ever
before 1871.
uh even during the the the Roman times
when you had Armenius who fought the the
the Roman legions in the year 10 AD you
do not have a unified Germany. You had
various Germanic tribes who spoke
similar languages and who came together
to fight the Roman uh occupiers.
Um now after 1871 Germany became an
industrial powerhouse and the nation
with the highest standards in Europe the
best education system in Europe. Germans
discovered quantum mechanics. Germans
discovered relativity. Germans, it was
mainly Germans who did this work. Of
course, you had the French and uh people
from Denmark and so on, but mainly
Germans. Um and after 1945, after the
end of the Second World War, Germany
rebuilt itself and it became the
industrial and economic powerhouse of
Europe. the engine that drove the
European economy, which is why migrating
to Germany was very um was very
attractive if you were a person who came
from, you know, a third world country or
a or that sort of thing. Of course, you
had to learn the German language. Well,
you learn any foreign language, same
thing whether you learn English or
German. So, uh that's why Germany became
a country that was very attractive for
immigration. Now, after 1945, the
Germany had to be rebuilt. So a lot of
Turkish workers were brought into
Germany to rebuild the country and they
never left. So so Turks became part of
Germany's uh society. About 10% of of
Germany's population is of Turkish
origin. Some Kuresh people also Turks
Kurds never friends by the way. Okay.
And after Germany became part of the EU,
the EU has pushed in
immigrants into Germany. immigrants of
certain kinds from certain nations,
usually nations that are war torn
nations, Middle Eastern nations,
typically military age men with very few
women or children. So that's a policy
that the EU, the European Union has
imposed upon Germany
and that's how Germany has become the
nation with the largest amount of
immigration in the European Union. Yeah.
They want to essentially end Germany and
create a new kind of Germany.
6P70 Delta says, "Did you watch Mir Shar
and Tucker's podcast?" I haven't seen
it. I think he's spot on on China. I
think the government of India should
hire him to get educated about the PRC
instead of wasting energy on slogans
like Vishwaguru, Atman,
Super.
So, I haven't seen this podcast. I don't
watch podcast anymore. I don't have the
time to watch any podcasts.
Um I I know people who tell me that if
you want to be a podcaster, you have to
watch podcasts. I understand that if you
want to be a writer, you to read also.
You read read a lot. And I do read, but
I don't have the time to watch podcast.
So I haven't seen this one. Um so I
don't know what Mir Shmer has said about
China. Should the government of India
hire him to get educated about the
People's Republic of China? I don't
think it's a bad idea. uh you can you
know hire consultants hire people who
who have expertise in various various
domains no there's no harm in doing that
uh all these slogans like vishwaguru
atmana superpower etc I think they are
for public consumption
and the public you know it it it gets
induced when this you know by the
slogans vishwa guru
um which are actually pointless slogans
right now so I agree about that
superpower what What are you talking
about? Superpower Vishwaguru we are not
even Vishwa student properly right now
atma that is a very important slogan and
I hope we become more Atman as we go on
but yeah overall I agree.
Carla Dika Carla Daika says I hope I got
your name pronunciation right. Um the
racist stuff appearing on my ex Insta
algorithm is laughable since I know my
Indian relatives are not like that. Why
are no are we in the states being
manipulated? See what's happening on on
social media. Uh I see X every day. So I
I tweet very little these days because I
don't want to be a spreader of
negativity and there's very little
positive to tweet about these days
unfortunately. So anyway coming to your
question, if you are on X, I'm not on
Facebook. I'm not on Insta that much. I
have an Insta account but I don't use it
that frequently. So if you see X there's
this tremendous outpouring of racism
against Indians. No question about it.
Is this organic? I don't think so at
all. I don't think so. Uh it's it's
I mean I have seen these videos of these
server farms and uh uh these things. You
see you see this is book rack behind me.
you know, books. Uh, I've seen these
videos with racks similar to these, but
you have mobile phones on those racks,
like thousands and thousands of mobile
phones, each of which is connected to
the internet. Each of which is a bot,
has a bot account, which pretends to be
a real account on X. It's powered by AI.
And you can use this bot farms to to
create narratives and amplify narratives
about whatever. So it's possible that
Chinese and Pakistanis have been doing
this you know spreading hatred about
India towards Indians and amplifying
this hatred and eventually it's become
mainstream. So now we don't need these
bot farms to do it. It's become
mainstream. Indians are like punching
bags in in the US. Um they don't fight
back.
um
they they're not like for example the
Arabs the Muslims who are going to fight
fight back and and come and harm you if
you do something about them or if you
say something about their religion right
Indians are are absolutely dosile uh
they don't hit back so they're the best
in you know ideal punching bags and and
obviously Indians
if you look at the various demographics
in the US Indians earn the most so there
is going to be a tremendous amount of
jealousy that's directed towards Indians
So my point is that I I don't see this
as an organic
issue. I don't see this as an organic
phenomenon. This has been
this has been artificially
created and amplified and now it's taken
a life of its own. So now people the
ordinary western person people the
ordinary white person let's say in the
US they they have a negative outlook
towards towards Indians
um yeah so so in case you have Indian
relatives you will know how Indians are
and whatever is being said about Indians
that's not quite accurate not all of it
is accurate uh some some things that
that they say about India some of it is
accurate obviously India is a third
world country even today India still has
a lot of issues, infrastructure and and
corruption and whatnot allegedly poverty
also but we have made huge strides
in the right direction but some of the
issues still persist. Anyhow my point is
that all of this is a manufactured
narrative that has now taken a life of
its own and uh most frustrated people
need someone to punch at and that's why
Indians are the perfect punching bags if
you're American.
Divor Singh says, "Funny how YouTube
would not let me ask about Israel."
Okay, I suppose there are certain
keywords that if you use those and then
your comments or whatever get flagged
and it depends, yeah, on the moderators
and what they have said as the keywords,
right?
Anonymous scientist says, I I think Modi
G postponing a meet with loudmouth Trump
is a good move. What what's my view? I
think it's a very good move. I agree
with you. See, the Americans just now
have imposed sanctions on various
Russian companies that are going to
affect India, right? Uh our purchases of
of Russian oil. So, it's it's a hit on
India
and right after they do this to us, if
we go and meet Trump and also after all
the fake all the all the lies has been
telling about Mr. Modi having spoken to
him and assured him about not buying in
Russian oil anymore then it's like we
are condoning his behavior and we are
going we are you know caving into him
and and bending our knee to him. If Mr.
Modi goes and meets meets with with Mr.
Trump after all this behavior and if Mr.
Modi does go and meet Mr. Trump even if
you ignore all that behavior then Mr.
Trump can make more claims after the
meeting than Mr. Mr. Modi has promised
me XYZ has promised me the moon has
promised me the stars and then again the
onus comes on Mr. Modi or on the Indian
Ministry of External Affairs to either
deny these false claims or just keep
quiet silent stay silent and swallow
this. It makes no sense for Mr. Modi to
meet a guy who behaves in this manner.
So uh I
think it's a good idea. What Mr. Modi
has done is the right thing. There is no
point meeting with Mr. Trump right now
at least until this trade deal if it
ever gets done is done. Once the trade
deal is done, see what Mr. Trump would
like is that the trade deal the major
negotiation happens between him and Mr.
Modi. And it should not be a
negotiation. It should be it should just
be demands. I'm going to demand this
this and Mr. Modi has to say yes. In a
trade deal, it's not the principles who
should negotiate.
It is the officials and bureaucrats who
are supposed to negotiate. Go down,
drill deep down into issues and
negotiate each of these issues
one by one. That's how it is done. But
Mr. Trump wants to ram it through from
the very top. And that's why he wants to
meet with Mr. Modi and get his immediate
sign off on whatever deal he seeks.
Okay, just sign this document. That sort
of thing. So I think it's a very good
thing that Mr. Modi has not gone for the
ASEAN summit where so that he doesn't
have to meet Mr. Trump. I think it's a
good thing
says sir apples
what are your thoughts on this and
congrats on 300 thank you very much sir
um I don't know I can't say there are
all these different timelines all of
these any of those could be right and
I'm not sure what the details of his
timelines are because there are now so
many people who have made so many
different claims on what is the date of
the Ramayan and what is the date of the
Mahabharat? Some are very near to where
we are maybe 1500 BC around that time.
Some are 3,000 something BC. Some are
like 30,000 BC. Uh so many different
claims. Uh so right now I'm not not
looking into all of this and there's too
much toxicity and too much fighting
among each other. See various you know
first of all we to understand it takes a
lot of personal time. there's you need
to invest a lot of your personal time in
doing this research.
So all of these people have done
tremendous service to India by by
investing their personal time which is
money into doing all this research and
they have all come up with all these
different dates. So first of all I
commend all of them and I thank them all
for their efforts but the dates don't
match like five people will have five
different dates and then they become
emotional and they fight each other on
on social media and that's a very
unfortunate
situation we have that all these people
who are actually like scholars are
fighting each other taunting each other
on social media calling each other names
some are being egoistic some are being
toxic so I have been seeing this for
several years and I've just, you know,
tuned out of it. So, I don't know which
is correct, which is not. Um, and I'll
just, you know, I'm staying out of it
right now. That's all. So, I don't know
what to say about his dates. Maybe they
are right, maybe they're not. I can't
say because I personally haven't looked
into the into the calculations.
Mr. Senna says, "Minimum wage is a norm
in the US and the EU. How does its
absence contribute to wealth inequality
in India and hinder our path to
prosperity?
Do we have minimum wages in India? I
suppose we should have at least
something on paper. I'm not sure. Does
India have minimum wages? Let's let's
Google that. Uh does India have minimum
wage law? Do we have this? Yes, India
does have a minimum wage law which was
established in 1948. Wonderful. However,
there is no single national minimum
wage. Instead, the rate varies by state
and the states decide all of these
things. It's determined by various
factors. Okay. And both the central and
state governments have the authority to
fix and revise these rates which apply
to workers in scheduled environments.
Blah blah blah. That's the need in
India. Everything is hazy and whatever.
So it looks like we have
a minimum wage law and each state can
decide what its minimum wage uh norms
are right. So there is so you don't have
an ab ab ab ab ab ab ab ab ab ab ab ab
ab ab ab ab ab ab ab ab ab ab ab ab ab
ab ab absence of this minimum wage law
we have it we have it wealth inequality
of in India India is one of the least
inequal nations when it comes to wealth
I think it's the fourth least unequal
inequal unequal nation the nation with
the fourth least inequality in wages
right um and look you cannot have
complete equality of wages is otherwise
you are in communism right so um so I
don't see this this to be an issue I
don't even think it's desirable to have
more equality among people you need to
have some inequality and it's it's just
natural for there to be some inequality
in wages in everything have you ever
seen two people who are exactly equal
no even among twins you will have
differences it's just natural for there
to be differences So yeah, so I don't
see this as a as an as a big issue.
Swapna says, "What were Norway's
motivations for mediating in the Sri
Lanka civil war?"
The Sri Lanka civil war.
The Sri Lanka civil war was the LTT
versus the government of Sri Lanka,
wasn't it? And uh the LT was a pioneer
of various kinds of innovations like the
suicide bomber, suicide west, sin
capsules and whatnot. all kinds of
horrific things.
Um, and the the LTT so the one
misconception people have about the LTTE
is that it was a Hindu organization,
liberation tigers of Tamil Elum. The
fact is that the Prabhakaran family were
all converted Christians and that's why
they were very aminable to to
being uh you know persuaded by the west
to do various things. Uh so Norway is
Norway was a proxy. Norway was you could
say a middleman.
See various European nations, they play
the role of proxies of the US.
That's what it was. It had no
motivations of its own. Um beyond
serving larger master.
Divor Singh says Jews bought Tik Tok
literally. What now? Well, Tik Tok
continues the way it is or maybe some
changes happen.
Uh what now?
So now it's no longer under the under
the control of China. It now the the
talk that's available in the west
becomes a separate entity and now
whoever has bought it gets to control it
and decide how the algorithm works and
what not. So that is the deal. Now have
Jews bought Tik Tok? I think you
mentioned this earlier also. Who has
bought Tik Tok? Let's take a look at
this. who has acquired
acquired tick tock
enterprise tech giant Oracle Silver Lake
and the Abu Dhabi based MGX investment
fund will be the main investors in the
in Tik Tok's US business controlling a
roughly 45% stake in the equity while
bite dance investors and new holders
will own 35%.
Um, okay. Oracle Silver Lake, but I hear
that Jews have have bought Tik Tok, so
maybe there is something to it. I
haven't looked into it in detail, sir.
Okay. Anonymous scientist says, "How was
your Diwali crackers?" I personally did
not burst crackers, but everyone around
me did that. So, it was great. Diwali is
always great.
Friend of Sharma, thank you very much,
sir. Thank you very much. Amisha says,
"How did humans mostly become
right-handed?" I don't remember right
now. I hear that polar bears are mostly
left-handed. I don't remember what the
reason is right now. I'll have to look
into it. Let's let's quickly
Google Google it. If Google has an
answer, um why
did humans become predominantly
predominantly
right-handed? Mostly right-handed. What
is the reason? Left hemisphere of the
brain which controls something or the
other. Language fine motor skills
connected left hemisphere dominance for
tool use and later you language.
Okay. Something to do with the
hemispheres of the brain. The left
hemisphere is the more mathematical
hemisphere controls the right and the
bodies are crossconnected and so on.
That sort of thing. So I I'll have to
look into this. I don't remember
exactly. Maybe I would have known the
answer in the past when I was a much
younger.
Looks like it has something to do with
brain hemispheres.
Divor Singh says, "Explain the Balur
declaration."
PS Rothchild.
The Balfur declaration was what was it?
It was the support for a Jewish nation.
Lord Balur was the was a prominent
politician
I think it's 1917 is it and he was a
prominent politician of some kind in
Britain
and they needed Jewish support for
something and that's why they they
expressed support for the creation of a
Jewish nation somewhere I I suppose
various parts of the world were were
considered for creating a Jewish nation.
Madagascar was considered once but
eventually uh Israel was created in the
ancient holy land, the ancient ancestral
land of the Jewish people. Uh Rose
Shield, I'm not sure what the connection
is. I'm sure there must be some
connection. Don't know for sure. So
yeah, that's that's what I can tell you
off the top of my head about the Balfur
declaration. Yeah.
Ammon
um Anand Ray Fimate says, "How did
bullets pass through propellers of
planes?"
Yeah. So um
so during the first and second world
wars, mostly during the Second World
War, you had uh fighter planes which
were propeller-driven fighter planes.
You did not have the jet engine until
late in the Second World War. And it was
the Germans who developed the first uh
jet engines. So you had fighter planes
with propellers like the Spitfire for
example. And these fighter planes also
had cannons, guns and bullets would be
fired from these
from these cannons. And in front of the
cannon you would have the propeller
that's propelling the plane. So you
would have to fire the bullets through
the place where you had you would have
the propeller doing its thing.
So how did bullets pass through
propellers? So they did not pass through
the propellers. I suppose the the
bullets were timed in such a such a
manner that they coincided with the time
where the propeller was not present
exactly in the path of the bullet. The
propeller would have a certain
period, right? Period of rotation. So
let's say it rotates,
let's say a thousand times a minute. No,
that's too less. maybe uh 10 times a
second for example.
So and and let's say the bullet the the
cannon's rate of fire is also 10 times
per second. I'm just giving a
hypothetical example. So you can time it
in such a manner that when you press the
the the button the big red button for
the cannon it'll fire in such a way that
it doesn't ever hit the propeller
blades. So yeah I suppose that's how it
was done.
Pratt Dhana says this Diwali felt
special. Did you feel the same? I really
enjoyed this year Diwali. Uh did it feel
special compared to other Diwali? I'm
not sure about that but it was it was
great and this time there was no ban on
crackers that I know of which which is
also a good thing. So people really
enjoyed bursting crackers. Yeah, I I
hope everyone enjoyed this.
Uh DNU Singh says US news ranked Israel
higher than China in military strength
recently. India is not in the top 10.
Okay, anybody can come up with rankings.
Um,
if you are a media outlet, you can
create your own rankings of whatever you
want to create. So, military strength,
naval strength, air force strength.
Recently somewhere I hear I hear that
the Indian Air Force is ranked the
second or third most powerful air force
or second most powerful air force in the
world which makes no sense whatsoever.
But there was this human cry about that
in the Indian social media
>> or Indian Twitter or whatever. So you
know what are my views on this? I don't
care. Anybody can create rankings.
And uh Israel higher than China in
military strength. Well, that is a
little laughable. Of course, that's a
little laughable. Uh even if you look at
um nuclear
capabilities,
Israel would have what 70 80 100 nuclear
weapons, maybe 200 nuclear weapons, but
China would have at least 600 and
overall China's economy and military
capabilities far surpass that of
Israel's. So that obviously makes no
sense whatsoever. Shas Jenna Jenna says,
"What is the history of Kolinga? It's
underestimated.
The history of Kolinga will take hours.
It will take like multiple semesters
of of a university course to teach. The
history of Kolinga. How can I explain
the history of Kolinga here? Kolinga is
history goes back as as as far back as
Indian history. And Kolinga was the part
of India that was instrumental in
connecting us with Sarabumi with the far
east with with Southeast Asia right it
is merchants from Kolinga who first
ventured out and crossed the sea of
Kolinga or the Bay of Bengal how it's
called today and uh by by ship about
3,000 years ago at least and they
started trading with Southeast Asia
which is how You had the creation the
emergence of various Indianized
Hinduized kingdoms and empires in
Southeast Asia all thanks to the great
merchants of Kolinga. So the history of
Kolinga is is spectacular fantastic but
you can't explain it in 2 minutes here.
Divor Singh says all American presidents
descend from one man some English
kind named John except Van Buran. Let's
see. Do all American presidents descend
from one man? Do all American presidents
presidents descend?
Descendants of King John really? Who's
John?
No. All US presidents are not not all
are descendants of King John of England.
Who was King John of England?
Who is King John of England?
Okay, it's not explaining that.
Let's see. King John of England. Who was
that first of all?
King John. Okay. Are you talking about
uh Edward Long Shanks? No, that that was
Edward. Okay.
King of England from 1199 to his death
in 1216. He lost the duty of Normandy in
most of his etc. So a lot of these guys
are descendants of King John. Okay. Many
presidents share a common ancestry.
Barack Obama and Martin Vanburn have
non-English ancestry that is not
descended from him. Most are related to
King John. Very interesting. So is Trump
is Trump related? Is Trump
is Trump
a descendant of King John? Is he? Let's
see. Yes, he is. Fascinating. likely
through his Scottishborn mother's
lineage. Very interesting. This is quite
a rabbit hole that you have
pointed out to us. Very interesting.
Very interesting. What's the
significance of this? I'm not really
sure. I'll have to look into it.
Um Dur Singh, let us not discuss this.
All right, sir. Thank you, sir. Deadshot
Diri says, "Why are we more inclined
towards being followers?
For example, we tend to go out of our
way to follow the internet trends. One
dude says, "Thanks for your attention to
this matter." And tons of others follow.
Yes, everyone follows trends, don't
they? Why are we more inclined towards
being followers?
Because it's hard to lead. It's hard to
lead. You need a tremendous amount of
originality in you first of all to lead.
See, most people don't even know who
they are. Do you really know who you
are? Can you spend 10 days alone without
talking to anybody else? That's the only
real way to find out who you who you
really are. What are your own real
thoughts?
Most people you will find have thoughts
that are the carbon copies of something
they've heard here or there. None of
their thoughts are original. None of
their beliefs are original. their
beliefs also they have acquired from
here or there. Oh, I like this person.
This person is very popular. Let me find
out what they think about this issue or
that issue and then I'll make it my
belief.
Right?
Because thinking is hard work.
Thinking is painful. It hurts to use the
brain. Right? Most people have no
original thought.
Most most people have no original
beliefs. they have no original ideas
and it's not their fault because the
education system etc does that to you.
Um so it it so if you have the situation
most people will therefore
want to just follow.
So leadership is very uncommon and most
people don't even know what leadership
is. Leadership actually is service of
all these people who have no thoughts of
their own. Uh so it is it is human
nature that we tend to most of us tend
to want to follow. Most of us have no
original thoughts of our own. Most of us
find thinking to be very difficult.
Right? Most of us want to be like
everyone else. We want to fit in. We
want to be comfortable.
We look around okay if I think this way
will everyone approve? Will my peers
approve? If I do something that is
different from what they think, will
that hurt me? Will they no longer be my
friends? Do I have the courage to stand
out and be different? Most people don't
have this. That that's why everyone
wants to be followers. Most most people,
very few people want to be leaders and
most people when they want to lead, they
want to actually manipulate. They don't
want to serve. So that's human nature.
You see human nature.
Rahul G says as of late October 25 sir
creek activity among India and Pakistan
I have no idea no idea whatsoever I am
not keeping track of that if something
happens we'll see lanya says if you want
to guess based on your knowledge and
instincts
by what year will we see the planet free
from the Anglo-Saxon le world order
Garajia
if I want to guess based on my knowledge
and instinct
By what year will we be free of
the world order that is currently in
existence which is led by the
Anglo-Saxons?
When will that happen?
That's a good question. When do I think
that will happen? I don't see that
happening anytime in the near future.
Unfortunately,
if the See, I'll tell you what the what
my thinking process is.
Um there's only one nation that has
currently the capability to to make life
interplanetary.
If they are able to send
missions
and colonists
to the moon and Mars, then they are here
for another couple of hundred years at
least in the in the pole position, in
the leadership position.
Um, so I don't know or maybe something
changes very rapidly. It is very hard
for me to look into the future and say
what could happen
based on my instincts.
I don't know
50 years. I'm being a little hopeful
here.
Yeah, I'm I'm just making a wild guess.
Maybe 50 years. Maybe it won't be that
long. Maybe some some things will
change. Maybe 30 years. Okay, let's see.
I don't know. Fast snail says, "What's
the secret? What is secret information
declassification? What are criteria for
that?"
Secret information is declassified when
it is no longer dangerous.
Why is information classified? Why is it
kept secret? Because it is dangerous to
those who are in power.
Okay? If that knowledge becomes
widespread, if it becomes common
knowledge, then it will be dangerous to
the people who are in power or it will
be dangerous to your country.
So information is kept secret only if it
is if it compromises you, if it
compromises the country or it
compromises those who are in power. When
it no longer has that power of of
compromising you or the country, then it
is then it can can be made secret.
So one example is the Nakaji thing.
Naki Subashand most likely did not die
in the so-called plane crash of which
there is no actual record in Taiwan.
Most likely he was alive until 1985. But
why is the government unwilling to
accept this? Why is it unwilling to
declassify the documents that they would
have?
Because it is these documents are still
dangerous. They can still cause trouble
too perhaps. I mean nobody in power will
will will
be singed by this right but maybe the
country
will face some problems because the west
will attack the country for glorifying a
person who they will claim was a
supporter of Hitler or something like
that. So you know that's the deal. So
secret info is declassified when it is
no longer dangerous or it can no longer
compromise the people who are in power
or or the country.
6 P70 Delta says about around 15,000
Ukrainian civilians
are dead peanuts compared to Afghanistan
and Iraq. But the US is a democracy
valuing human life in evil Russia having
complete disregard for human life.
That's how it goes. People all people
aren't equal. You see,
all people aren't equal.
That's how it goes. People with certain
skin colors are more equal.
That that's the hypocrisy of of of the
West and and overall of all human
beings. You pref you tend to prefer
people who are more like you. You will
always prioritize your people, your
country people and so on. So
yeah, you see what happened in Iraq
when the Americans liberated Iraq? How
many Iraqis died? Civilians, more than a
million. Those you don't talk about.
Entire cities were flattened. You don't
talk about that, right? Because you are
bringing in democracy. So that that's
how it goes. That is the way of the
world. Divor Singh says, "Are Chinese
the best businessmen?" That's what
American businessmen say. In the 1970s
and 80s, American businessmen used to
say that there is no better businessmen
than the Japanese.
The Japanese are the toughest
negotiators. They do business in such a
hardcore way that we Americans can't
deal with them. That's what they used to
say in the 1970s and ' 80s. Then the
Americans dealt with Japan. Now, China
is up here and right now because of the
leverage that China has that other
countries don't have, right? That's why
China is right now in vogue and the
Chinese are the best businessmen.
So my point is why do we have to base
our understanding on who the best
businessmen are based on what one nation
says?
You don't necessarily have to do that.
Of course, the US is the most
consequential nation in the world right
now. It's the nation that matters the
most. It's the nation which historically
the past century or so has had the
highest standards. So, it kind of makes
sense to to listen to what they have to
say. And if they regard the Chinese to
currently be their,
you know, the toughest peer competitors
they have, then maybe the Chinese are
the best right now. So as a nation the
Chinese the Chinese nation is the
biggest competitor to the US right now
and maybe their business people are the
best in the world right now.
Anonymous scientist says why are our
countrymen insecure, naive and
emotional? The moment your view differs
from theirs they start fighting.
It's the fault of the education system.
It doesn't teach you how to think
rationally.
critical thinking.
You know, you you're not taught any of
these things that it's okay to have
different opinions. It's okay to have
different viewpoints. Try and understand
the other person's viewpoint. Maybe you
will learn something from them. Maybe
they will learn something from you. You
don't have to react to everything
emotionally. Be analytical.
Try and understand what that viewpoint
means.
But none of this is taught to us in
school. in college, in university,
right? So that's why Indians are
insecure, naive, emotional and so on.
And that's why unless we reform the
education system, this country is going
to go nowhere.
Dr. Rita Brata Debat says, "Although the
truth will never be out, but the CIA,
but doesn't the CIA seem dumb enough to
try assassination of Mr. Modi knowing
his successor will be more hardliner.
There is no guarantee of anything.
First of all, there is no evidence there
was an assassination attempt of Mr. Modi
or a ploy to to assassinate him. That's
all speculation on social media without
I have not seen any evidence that could
actually uh point in that direction. But
let's say hypothetically assuming that
maybe hypothetically this there could be
some truth to it. Okay?
And hypothetically there was this ploy.
So when you want to do so, let's say you
want to assassinate a world leader.
You don't make a plan to assassinate
somebody unless you have a succession
plan that you think will succeed.
And there is no guarantee
that if if something
happens to so and so person somewhere in
the world
that a more hardline successor will come
up.
No guarantee.
So maybe they have some kind of plan you
know action plan contingency plan
whatever you want to call it. So yeah
this is all speculation.
Okay. Aradush Darwilli.
Aradush Dwari is a Georgian name. Okay.
Would you eat raw food and turn
liquidarian for life? Why? I would not.
Why would I do it? Why? Why raw food? I
would never eat raw meat. That would be
madness.
Uh raw vegetables and fruits. Of course,
I I'm happy to eat that. turn
liquidarian for life.
No. Why would I? Is there any benefit of
doing that? No. Team talks Dharma says,
"Congratulations. Thank you very much.
Why doesn't the US do military parades
like Russia, China, and India? Is there
some link from the past? I have no idea.
Why do they not do parades?"
Um, well, they do parades, right? Don't
they? Trump recently had a military
parade.
Donald Trump recently had some kind of
military parade which did not really go
out very well which kind of indicates
that the US doesn't really do parades.
So why don't they do military parades? I
suppose if you are the most powerful
nation in the world and if you are a
nation that's accustomed to hiding
its in instruments of power then it
makes sense not to do parades. Yeah. Let
the wars do the talking for you. No need
to display what you have. just deploy it
in warfare and win.
6P70 Delta says YouTube may decide to
delete the Nuring's account. You never
know what YouTube will decide.
Vishnu says if Turks are of Central
Asian origin why did so why did many
western Gturks tatars have a 100%
European ancestry which is ancient even
before migrating to Anatolian lands and
settling there
see migrations aren't like straight
arrows human migration is like a back
and forth process okay Um
if you look at
the
tarim basin mummies which uh are found
in present day singinjang you know
currently occupied by China uh you will
find that those people who lived about
what 3,000 4,000 years ago they look
like present day western European people
many of them have blonde hair or red
hair light colored skin probably had
light light colored eyes but if you see
their language in their religion it was
Indian so that's very weird isn't it so
various kinds of genetics have spread
across Eurasia over thousands of years
uh the Turks
the Turks they originate in the region
that is present day Mongolia
they their ancestors were called the
Shau
or the Hunu the Huns
uh and they spread spread across Eurasia
as as nomadic conquerors and their
descendants some of them eventually came
to be known as the Turks. Now these
folks they migrated all across Eurasia
and they would have picked up all kinds
of genetics along the way. So if you
look at the Tatar people like you're
mentioning some of them have very slanty
eyes some of them look
like Europeans. Uh one example is Marat
Safhin and Dinara Safhino the the the
the siblings who are grand slam
champions. Marat Safin Dinara Safhina
these two are siblings.
If you see here they these two are
brother and sister. Now as you grow
older you will see more cha. So do they
look do they look European or Central
Asian? I think they look kind of mixed,
don't they?
But if you see Maratafin when he was
young, he looked less Central Asian and
more European.
Uh, Grand Slam, US Open.
Let's see which Okay, which one did he
win?
Um,
Grand Slam
here. Does he look he has blonde or or
light colored hair
uh and that sort of thing? He looks more
European here. So the point is that you
know all these people if you are if you
are a nomadic
if you are a nomadic people you're going
to pick up all kinds of ancestry all
kinds of genetics during over the course
of centuries and that's how it goes. All
right. Okay. Uh DN Singh says what is
cherankov? Cheranken of radiation.
Cherank of radiation.
Okay. So that comes when you break the
speed of light in a certain medium.
Yeah. The speed of light.
So let's say we know what the speed of
light in a vacuum is. It's roughly
300,000 km/s.
300,000 m/ second. kilometers
uh kilometers/s 300,000 kilometers/s no
m kilometers per second okay
so that is the speed of light in vacuum
one second let me just remember whether
is speed of light
speed of light meters/s 300,000 m/s we
don't talk about kilometers we talk
about meters okay so we know what the
speed of light is in vacuum
But the speed of light
in let's say glass will be different.
The speed of light will not be the same
in glass as it is in vacuum. The speed
of light will not be the same in water
as it is in vacuum. And it's possible
for the speed of light to
break that limit in a certain medium.
And that is what gives rise to this this
radiation which is called cherank of
radiation which is this this bright
flash that you suddenly see blue flash
typically. So you can see uh if you want
to see what it looks like.
Okayov
radiation. And if you look at the
images,
this is what it looks like and that's
how it originates.
Okay. Deadshot Diri says Sal. Okay. Sal,
are we still sovereign because we
because
and haven't sold out because the
insanely corrupt politicians already
have infinite money to be farmed in
land.
Look, uh there are different ways of
looking at sovereignty.
And you can complicate it as much as as
you want or simplify it as much as you
want. The way I look at sovereignty is
from different three four different
perspectives. One is territorial
sovereignty. Second is economic
sovereignty.
Um
so economic sovereignty is do you
control your own money? Do you control
your own currency? So India does control
its own currency doesn't it? Right? We
have the Indian rupee that we entirely
control. When it comes to territorial
territorial sovereignty, we control our
borders. We have full control over our
borders. So we have that as well. When
it comes to uh legislative sovereignty,
we make our own laws. So we are
sovereign there as well. When it comes
to uh
policies, so we we we decide what
policies will be implemented in our
nation and nobody else does. So if you
look at all these different
perspectives, we are still a sovereign
nation for sure. Um yeah, sure you can
have issues and we do have allegedly
issues such as corruption that are a big
problem in India and that need to be
resolved and corruption can have the
effect of various
people potentially becoming assets of
foreign countries in your nation, right?
Uh so that is there. So it does
compromise the nation but it doesn't
encroach on our sovereignty entirely. So
every nation has these issues. Even the
US will have some people
who will secretly be working for some
other country. But that doesn't prevent
the US from continuing to be a sovereign
nation. Right? So these are issues that
compromise national security and
national interests to a certain extent.
Uh but until and unless it becomes a
widespread epidemic scale problem,
you're still sovereign.
Busker Kywal says, "Dear sir, the
questions weren't sent to yesterday's
live stream.
I sent 8 to 10 questions to this
particular 300th episode, but
yesterday." Well, if the questions have
been sent, then I should be able to see
them.
And uh right now I can see 149
um
super chat questions and I'm going
through these one by one. So and I
started with the first one. So let me
see the first one is not yours. So maybe
if you send those yesterday maybe they
disappear. I have no idea. See if that's
happened I apologize but that's
something that YouTube controls. I don't
control it and I am simply taking every
single super chat question I am seeing.
So
yeah, in case your your questions aren't
there, I apologize. But it's it's not in
my hands, then maybe in the future,
maybe you should do it when it's live,
right? So if I see it, I see your
questions. I'll take them for sure. But
I don't think I'm seeing any questions
from yesterday.
All right, sir. Shia says, why destroy
EU and Japan introducing Muslim human
crisis by the US? Listen uh I will talk
about immigrants. I will not talk about
religion. All right?
I I don't talk about religion. I don't
talk about that specific religion. First
of all, if you are talking about
bringing in bringing in illegal
immigrants of various kinds into Europe
or Japan, why do that?
See, if you consider a nation to be a
dangerous nation, for example, Germany,
if you consider that Germany is a
potentially dangerous nation, they were
able to produce something like the
third. They were able to produce Nazi
Germany. And if we are not careful,
maybe in the future something like that
will happen again. Then you go to the
root cause of Nazi Germany. Their belief
that the German people are the master
race. the master race, a superior kind
of human being.
That's what caused Germany to become the
third Reich, Nazi Germany. So, how can
you prevent this from happening? By
changing the race, by bringing in
outsiders into your country and having
them interbreed with your people so that
you no longer have that master race.
Maybe that's one reason. I'm just
speculating here. I don't have any real
answers because I don't know what's
going on in the minds of the people who
are planning and and and executing this
but maybe that is one of the causes why
one of the reasons why they want to do
that and similarly in Japan maybe
something similar I I'm just guessing I
don't know but possibly yeah that sort
of argument does make sense logically
perhaps yeah Rajat Rasogi says Indian
diplomats say that in in that India will
be a 30 trillion economy in next 30
years what do I
Where will where will be the US in the
next 30 years? What will happen to
China? You ask me to make predictions
about the future you can't uh Indian
diplomats say all kinds of things. TK
good wonderful. What will most likely
happen?
What will where will India's economy be
by 2050?
Look right now it's a $4 something
trillion economy in 2025.
Um in 2014 we were half of that. So in
10 years we've doubled roughly. Okay. Uh
what was India's econ? How large
large
was the Indian
Indian economy
in 2015?
USD trillions
how many 2.1 trillion right and today we
are what 4.3 4.4 4 trillion. So India's
economy has doubled in 10 years. Right
now it is 4.5 let's say. So in another
10 years by 2035 let's assume it
doubles. So it's 9 trillion. Then
another 10 years will it double? Let's
say it doubles hypothetically. Okay we
are doing the exponential thing. So by
2045 we are 18 trillion. So it is
possible that by 2050 we could be a 20
trillion economy.
But a lot can happen. We could become a
$50 trillion economy or we may still
remain a $10 trillion economy depending
on so many different factors. Maybe the
leadership is a very important factor.
Right now we have something someone like
Mr. Modi that we are very fortunate to
have.
What if something somebody else comes to
comes to power in 2029 or before that
and maybe then we make a complete U-turn
U-turn and our economy slows down.
That's also possible, right? Depending
on how you people vote.
Uh so I am confident I am I am hopeful I
would say that we will be at least a 20
trillion economy by 2050.
Where will the US be? It will most
likely still be the most powerful nation
in the world. What will happen to China?
China will still be the second largest
economy if not the largest economy by
the time if things go
on track, stay on track the way they are
right now. But you never know what the
future will bring. You know, you never
know. Divor Singh says Raan had the
knowledge of the of four Vedas. If Riga
is just 1500 BC, Raan Ramayan happened
just 3,000 years ago. Does not make
sense. No, it doesn't make sense. It
doesn't make sense.
So, look, these timelines don't make any
sense. They have been force fitted into
euroentric notions of how the world is
supposed to be.
uh when Maxim Miller made this this
claim that the Arian invasion the
so-called Arian invasion happened around
1500 BC he was trying to force fit
everything into this biblical uh
timeline of the universe's age according
to Christianity according to the Bible
or whatever their their texts are the
world was was created about 4,000 years
ago by God in in a period of 7 days 4,04
years ago or something like that.
So, and that's why people like Newton
used to be astonished when Egyptians
seemingly claimed that they their
civilization was like 5,000 years old
and they would the Europeans would say,
"How can it be?" Because God made the
the world 4,000 years ago. So, how can
you even claim that your civilization is
5,000 years old? So all of these dates
that we that are currently mainstream
are because of the force fitting that
was done by people like Max Müller to
force everything within the the biblical
time frames. So this this dating of the
rigid of 1500 BC or whatever it makes
absolutely no sense. The rigida was most
likely written closer to 6,000 BC than
to 1500 BC based on what we know about
the Saraspati and when the river was
last in its prime. So the Raman clearly
happened significantly before uh 1500
BC. That's for sure.
Hersa says I was reading an article that
shows that 60% of women leave their man
if they are incapable of providing
capital. So what is this unconditional
love crap views?
Well, okay. I'm not sure where this
article came from and how they decided
that 60% of women will leave their man
if they can't provide uh capital.
But from a biological evolutionary
perspective, it kind of makes sense,
right? It kind of makes sense that a man
has to be strong and and and capable of
providing for a woman. and uh her
offspring and his own offspring. So from
an evolutionary perspective, it kind of
makes sense.
But from a civilizational perspective,
maybe not not so much so, right? You're
supposed to be unconditionally
loving each other or or something. So
you know what I I would have to see the
article and what was their research
methodology, you know, and so on and
maybe it doesn't make sense. I don't
know. Divor Singh says, "What was the
Iran Contra affair?" It was this um Iran
Contra affair. This is from the Reagan
era, isn't it? Somewhere around that
time.
And there was this guy called Oliver
North who testified with his hand out
like this. Oliver North. Let's let's
Google this. You're bringing back
memories from the time when I was a
little kid. Oliver
North,
American political commentator. What was
he kn What's he known for? What is
Oliver North known for?
Come on, Google. Do your thing. Test. He
testified or something. Iran contra
affair. Iran contra affair. Yes, he
maintained a public blah blah blah. Arms
for host. All that stuff. Yeah, that's
fine. But he testified. Let's see.
Testifying.
There he is. Yep. There he is.
Yeah. So it was some some kind of
corruption scandal of or something.
Um
the see in 1979 you had the uh Islamic
revolution in Iran and the the
government of Muhammad Raza Pakabi who
used to be who who was a US asset. it
was overthrown and the regime of the
Ayatollah took over which still
continues in in Iran.
And when this happened, the Iranians
they uh stormed the US embassy and they
took uh a bunch of diplomats hostage and
that hostage crisis went on for like 2
three years
and around this time you had some kind
of bribery scandal or something. I don't
remember the details of the Iran contra
affair. If you want we can look it up.
But it was something from that time.
Iran Contra affair
affair. What was this thing? Yeah. Arms
trafficking to Iran between 81 and 86.
And what was the objective? What was
what was?
Yeah. Secret sales of weapons to Iran,
exchange of rel. Yeah, that sort of
thing. Yeah. So I kind of was was in the
right ballpark.
um you know some kind of deal with Iran
some kind of u sale of weapons or
whatever in exchange for releasing the
hostages. Yeah.
Pratt says is in the US Republican
politicians got a backlash for Diwali
wishes. Have they opened a can of worms?
Maga Magore is size Magore is size gone
full as of mode. YouTube won't let me
super chat. Okay. Um in the US
Republican politicians some of them got
a backlash from their own constituency
from their own voters for wishing for
for Diwali wishes. Have they opened a
can of worms?
See um in the US
the conservative people consider the
nation to be a Christian nation
and it is kind of a Christian nation
isn't it? Uh
the US was founded in what 1776 by
Christians.
Um and yeah overall it's been a
Christian nation and when you
wish people
for a polytheistic
religious major holiday it will
definitely offend the Christians the
Christian conservatives and so yeah the
politicians who have done that will most
likely have got a significant backlash
from their own voters.
It is what it is that's how it goes.
Have they opened a can of worms? No,
it's not a can of worms.
Um, yeah, it's not surprising at all.
And see, the thing is that if you are
Indian in a western nation, uh, you
despite the fact that the law gives you
equal rights and so on, if you are a
citizen of the nation, you are kind of
still going to be kind of a secondass
citizen implicitly.
Yeah. Unless you are a white Christian,
you're going to be a second class
citizen. I mean the Latinos know that,
the natives know that and Indians are
also discovering that now. It is what it
is. An says to fulfill its full
potential, Bat needs a robust governance
system, government system, governance
system. For a robust system, we need
excellent education system, which in
turn requires a robust system. Are we
trapped in a catch22?
So what needs to happen first is the
question.
For a better system, do we first need to
create a better better education system?
No.
The question really is what comes first?
A better education system or a better
system of governance?
I would say a better system of
governance comes first. Otherwise, the
education system will never be reformed
because in the current system, this is
the best form of education that we can
have.
uh the politicians who who have come to
power in the current system, the current
flawed system, they would not want to
change the education system because that
will then inform
the citizens of how how bad the the
current governance system is. So it it
doesn't make sense for them to reform
the education system. So what first
needs to happen is that the the
governance system itself needs to
change. Then other things will change.
See that's the thing
Dur Singh says if we cannot go further
from the north pole is it same with time
and the big bang there was no time
before the big bang as far as we know
time is a big mystery it's an
interesting question you're asking here
time is a big mystery we don't know
where it comes from we don't know
whether time is an emergent phenomenon
that emerges out of spaceime or emerges
thought of something that is part of the
universe or time is maybe even external
to the to the universe itself. We have
no idea.
So you are right. We can't go further
north of the north pole. No question
about that.
Time and the big bang. Did time begin
with the big bang?
What has caused time? Is time a
consequence of quantum entanglement and
decoherence?
And all of that obviously comes with the
beginning of the universe which is the
big bang. So I would say it is likely
but I'm not sure about this. No one is
sure about this that time began with the
big bang with the expansion of spacetime
itself at the very beginning
because we think of you know uh Steve
Weinberg has a book called the first 3
seconds. It's about the first 3 seconds
after the big bang assuming that time
begins with the big bang once again. So
most probably
there was no time before the big bang
and time began with the big bang itself.
But who knows? Maybe time is external to
the universe itself. We don't know. We
don't know for sure.
Uh net net stat says why are elites
building bunkers all of a sudden? I
don't know sir. Are elites building
bunkers? What what does elite mean? Do
you mean the billionaires in the US?
Because I don't know if any elite in
India is building bunkers. Maybe you're
talking about the US.
So, does Elon Musk have a bunker? Does
Bill Gates have a bunker? Does uh
I don't know. I don't know.
An says, "In my opinion, in 200 years,
the British were able to colonize BAT
much more thoroughly than the Turks
could in 800 years." I agree with you,
sir. I agree. What do you credit their
success to? The Turks tried to destroy
our culture and civilization through
violent means through the sword.
The British did that with bureaucracy.
They passed laws.
They changed the education system. First
of all, they abolished the indigenous
education system that gave India so much
everything we had. They abolished that
and then they created they imposed their
own colonial education system that was
designed to to churn out clerks and
peons and they made it such that unless
you have a degree through the colonial
education system you can't get a job
and they made English the language
through which you can get jobs
because of that Indians had to become
anglicized
And if you become anglicized and if you
go through the education system, you
will start worshiping the British.
So that is what they did. They did more
through the power of the pen than the
Turks could achieve through the power of
the sword. Right? Very very intelligent,
very smart, very insidious.
That is why even though the British are
gone, their system still continues and
we are getting more and more colonized
today. Right? That's the deal.
Gallour says what is time? Does it make
sense before knowing what is plank time?
Uh the plank time is the shortest uh
unit of time. See there are there's
something called the plank units.
Plank units are made up of the
fundamental constants of the universe
such as G, H, C. G, H, and C. H is the
plank constant. G is Newton's constant
of gravitation. C is the speed of light.
And using these and they all have
different units. And using these
fundamental constants, you can create
you can construct
uh fundamental units of of u length,
breadth, mass, temperature, etc. you. So
you have the plank mass,
you got the plank length, you got plank
time
which are all constructed out of these
fundamental constants. So plank time is
is a unit of time. It is a very very
very brief unit of time. It's about 10
to - 44 or 45 seconds. Okay, I let let's
let's verify whether what I just said
was is correct or not. uh plank time if
I recall correctly if you calculate
properly it's about 10 it's of the order
of - 10 10 - 44 or - 45 seconds so let's
see plank time
10 - 44 seconds right it's of the order
of 10 - 44 seconds it's the smallest
unit of time that can be measured well
you can't really measure it
hypothetically theoretically be measured
you can't actually measure something of
you know that brief
Okay. Uh, nationalist says top 10
biggest historical lies fed to Indians.
I'll tell you the top one. Nonviolence.
Nonviolence is the best thing. Right?
Nonviolence will turn you into losers.
Nonviolence
is a lie. It's a myth.
Don't ask yourself what what would
Gandhi do? Ask yourself what would Kali
do? Why do all our gods hold a weapon?
If nonviolence is the biggest biggest
best thing in the world, then why do all
our gods hold weapons? Maybe because
Hinduism is evil, right? Again, there we
go. So, these are some of the biggest
lies, historical lies. Yeah, nonviolence
works. Nonviolence doesn't work.
Nonviolence turns you into slaves. Okay.
Bjusai says, "The more I read about
World War II, the more I realize that
Italy was more actually more of a burden
on Germany." What do you think? Italy
was a junior partner to to Germany.
Germany was the major power in Europe
and Japan was the major power in in the
east.
Italy was a junior partner to Germany,
but it was ideologically aligned with
Germany Germany, which is why the two
nations were on the same side. Right?
The axis
Uh so I agree with you. Um Italy was a
junior partner and maybe you could say a
burden to some extent on Germany.
Rajat Chhattajji says why does dipole
from cosmic microwave background match
with earth's equinox in ecliptic
when there is no connection between
these?
I'm
what
dipole from cosmic microwave background.
The cosmic microwave background
radiation is photons. Photons
it is the leftover light.
The after go afterlow of the big bang.
It's photons.
There's no dipole there.
Right?
So I'm not sure what you have read, but
you need to first have clarity about
what you have read or heard. The cosmic
microwave background radiation is just
photon. It's just light. But it's it's
extremely cold light. Extremely low
energy,
right? Um it's about what 2.4 2.5 Kelvin
the temperature.
What is 0 Kelvin? It is absolute zero.
CNBR is about 2.5 or something Kelvin
and that's it. There's no dipole in
there. So yeah.
Uh Dnor Singh says why is Scotland and
Ireland the home to whiskey?
Well, Scotland is home to Scotch
whiskey.
Uh Ireland has its own whiskies. The
Americans have their own whiskies,
right? I mean what is Jack Daniels? It's
it's Tennessee mash sour mash whiskey.
So even the US has has its own whiskies.
What do what else do they have? Whatever
else they have rye whiskey and whatnot.
Um
Irish whiskey. What are famous Irish
whiskies? I'm not really sure. I know
about scotch whiskies. You know various
i scotch and peted scotches and whatever
else.
Um, and what are whiskies made from?
Hops, right? Hops. At least in Scotland,
they're made from hops. Ireland, I'm not
sure what they're made of. And um,
in the US, what does what are what is
Jack Daniels made from? Let let's let's
I Let's see. Uh, what is Jack Daniels
made from?
Oh, it's made from corn, rye, and Okay.
Molted barley.
Okay. What is scotch whiskey made from?
Oops. What is that? Ma made from
scotch.
Scotch whiskey made from. It's made from
water, cereals, and yeast. Molted
barley.
So what is made from hop? Hops.
What is what alcohol?
Alcohol
is made from hops. Is it beer?
It's made from Okay, it's beer. Okay.
So, yeah. I don't know what rabbit hole
I'm going into, but okay. So, I think I
suppose every nation has its own brand,
its own, you know, favorite kind of
alcohol. And u yeah, Scot Scotland is
Scotch whiskey, Ireland has it own
whiskey, and the US has its own
whiskies, I suppose. Okay. 6P70 Delta
says, "Does power come from violence
rather than money? As a person with a
truck full of Kalashnikovs would be more
powerful than with one with a truck full
of money?" Well, you have hit the nail
on the head, sir.
Power comes from the capacity
to unleash violence if required. You are
absolutely right. A truck full of
cash is It doesn't give you the kind of
power that you get from a truck full of
Kalashnikovs. Right? Imagine you have a
100 guys each of whom carries a suitcase
full of dollars
and then you have 100 guys each of whom
carries a Kalashnikov and sufficient
ammunition to do a lot of damage. What
makes you more powerful? It's the guys
with the Kalashnikovs, right?
So power comes from the capability to
unleash violence on demand. That is the
truth about power. It's like what
Maadong said, political power flows out
of the barrel of a gun, right?
So yeah, violence is the key or the
possibility the potential to do
violence. Anonymous scientist says is it
possible to test multiverse theory and
professor Alan Gut's bubble universe
theory maybe some observation through
James Web it it is not possible to test
any multiverse theory ever through any
observation because to test the
multiverse theory you have to prove that
there are more universes than the one we
live in which means that you need to
have find data
you need to collect data from beyond our
universe which is impossible
right so it's not possible to test the
multiverse theory bubble universe I'm
not sure about that but no matter how
how far you crank crank up the James web
telescope how do you find any evidence
of universes beyond our own we don't
even know what lies beyond the
observable universe that bubble that we
live in
because there is a certain horizon
horizon the observable horizon of the
universe which is about what which has a
radius of of about 45 to 47 uh billion
light years we can't see beyond that so
the universe will live in itself we can
only see a small part of it so how are
we going to see something that's beyond
our universe it's it's impossible so
yeah you can't test it unfortunately you
can't
um swastik mahesh says how much is
India's power projection capabilities.
So how do you define power projection?
Power projection means the ability to
project power far beyond your territory
or beyond the territories you control.
Right?
Um
so in the case of the US, power
projection is done
through the various military bases the
US has
in territories that are not it its own.
For example, the US has more than 130
military bases on Japanese territory
which is not US territory. So that's how
it's able to project power in that
region. It has a military base in Diego
Garcia south of the Maldives. That's how
it's able to project power in the Indian
Ocean region and so on. So that's how
the US does it. Does India have any such
power projection capabilities? Any extr
territorial military bases? Maybe a few.
So our power projection capabilities
aren't great.
Um
another way of projecting projecting
power is through missiles.
So what are the longest range missiles
we have? The publicly available
information is that the AGNI 5 has a
range of about 8,000 kilometers
roughly. So that's how far our power
projection goes more or less. But
obviously the the
actual range may be different which is a
different story.
Uh, Gallivor says, "Burvestnik,
Burvestnik missile." Burstnik missile.
Does this change the game once and for
all more than Chinese FOBs deployment?
Buritnik missile. Is it that
nuclearpowered missile that you're
talking about? Let's let's Google it.
Buritz Buritnik.
Yeah, there you have it.
Buritnik missile. It's a nuclearpowered
cruise missile. Oh, really? They test it
today.
That's fantastic. That's interesting.
Okay. They tested this today. This
missile was first announced, I think, in
2019 or 18.
So, what's the deal with this missile?
We I think we know what cruise missiles
are. I I think you all must be knowing
what a cruise missile is. A cruise
missile is a missile that kind of flies
like an aircraft.
Okay. It's not a ballistic missile that
has a parabolic trajectory that exits
the atmosphere and then re-enters and
then impacts. A cruise missile flies
like an aircraft. It's got wings. It
flies at aircraft speeds or maybe
higher, maybe lower, whatever. And uh so
it plays a totally different role
and it these missiles typically have
engines that are similar to aircraft
engines or maybe sometimes different. So
this missile that we're talking about
the Buretsnik Burve Wnik missile
it has nuclear propulsion.
What does that mean? It's not a nuclear
tipped missile necessarily.
It may not necessarily have a nuclear
warhead. It may have a conventional
warhead but its propulsion system is
nuclear in origin. Typically, you would
have something like a nuclear ramjet,
nuclearpowered ramjet. So, it'll have a
nuclear power plant in it, which
produces heat that powers a ramjet or
possibly even a scramjet. So, let's
Google this.
Okay. Burvetsnik, what is the propulsion
like? Bitnik
missile
propulsion.
Is it a nuclear ramjet? What is it?
Uh, nuclear armed cruise missile blah
blah blah. Propulsion. Propulsion.
Propulsion. What is it? Design
speculation. We don't know. Of course,
we don't know.
Okay, let me just search for ramjet.
Ramjet.
It could possibly have a ramjet. Yeah,
but it's so classified that we don't
really know what the deal is. And it's
definitely not not a Basad Ramjet. So
yeah, it definitely is a gamecher
because see what's the deal with this
missile?
If it has nuclear powered propulsion, it
means it doesn't need to be refilled
with kerosene or whatever um fuel
chemical fuel is used in standard uh
propulsion.
Which means that this this cruise
missile can fly for months
on and on and on. And then one day
without warning it can go and hit the
target. That's a gamecher. Nobody else
has this capability. Yeah, totally game
changer.
Shashank Kukhat says Peshwa Bajiro
remained undefeated throughout his life.
Shattered the Mughals and transformed
the Marata kingdom into an empire. Can
he be considered India's greatest
military general ever? One of India's
greatest military generals. I would not
say that he would be the greatest ever
military general. one of the absolute
legends. Okay, no question about that.
Uh but we have other legends.
Uh we have for example Samudra Gupta
whose entire life, Emperor Samudra Gupta
whose entire life was an extended
military campaign and he never lost
and he conquered more. We also have
Kaneshka who defeated everybody who
conquered an empire that boggles your
mind from the Caspian Sea to the Aral
Sea including the whole of present day
Shinj Jang which is part of China. He
defeated
everybody who came his way. So we've had
many legends, many legends. Uh so we
have to put things in the right
perspective. All right, friends.
James says, "James princip is the man
who deciphered your brahmiscript, found
your history. We civilized you, taught
you your own language, of course. Yet
you still hate us superior British."
Yeah.
James Princip. James Princip, right?
He's the guy who deciphered the
brahiscript, is he? So suppose uh found
your history right? See see what
happened is this.
This is what happened.
India was the uh nation that
invented education. India wasn't the
nation. India was the civilization
that invented education. We invented the
concept of the school, the college, the
university, especially the university.
We had the oldest libraries. We invented
the concept of the library before
anybody else. Um so we had our own
records of our own history.
And then what happened is that we were
invaded and occupied by the Turks. And
what the Turks did was they destroyed
all our universities and burned all our
libraries. So we lost all the written
records of our history and whatever was
left we we had to pass it on orally.
Then the British arrived in India later
on right and uh once they took over
India they they said that you you guys
have your these fake histories these
legends everything is done orally
everything is passed on orally so we
will teach you what your history is and
then they proceeded to write our history
for us and teach us what their version
of our history and that's something that
is still being taught to us to our to
our children to children in schools
colleges universities is today. So, um I
don't know much about this gentleman,
James. James James Princip, but but
okay, let's quickly look at him. James
Princip,
who's this guy? Princip RN
P. He was an English scholar, etc., etc.
Karashi, Brahis. Okay, so I'm sure he
was interested in these matters, right?
and he would have deciphered the brahmy
and the koshi script. So, so good for
him, good good for us, good for all of
us. Um, so yeah, some of this was done
by the British. But the British also did
other stuff which was very nasty, wasn't
it? Like genociding 200 million plus
Indians, right?
Uh, construct not constructing,
engineering
hundreds of artificial famines and so
much more. So you see just because a
couple of things happened because of
because somebody was curious about
Indian industry doesn't mean that you
civilized us and taught our own language
and so on and so on. But you know what
James
I appreciate you James. I appreciate you
from for bringing these things up. Thank
you sir. Thank you. Dnour Singh says so
I told this white guy that Jesus looked
more like me than him and I believe I I
became the villain in the people around
somehow. You see, everyone wants to see
God in their own form. If you go to
Southeast Asia, they have statues of
Gotham Buddha there.
Those look Southeast Asian. You go to
China, they have statues of the Buddha
in China. And whether the Buddha looks
Chinese,
right? Um,
so that that's how it's going to be. uh
you will find
paintings of Lord Shiva and and and
goddess Parvati in central Asia and
there they will have slanted eyes.
So that's how it goes. You see so today
Christianity is the the the primary
religion of the white people and because
of that they would want Jesus to look
like them. So I believe that Jesus was
the the standard depiction of Jesus as
this as this person with a beard and and
uh long blond hair. I believe it was
modeled on one of the Borgas of the
Bourja family right
Chisar Borg was it was it
what did he look like? Chazar Borgia. So
this is what the guy looked like.
Chazaria
and uh and I suppose that family
commissioned some artist to depict Jesus
in the like likeness of Chisar Borgia
and that's how that image has been
passed on and today most Europeans
believe that Mr. Jesus was this white
man with
Italian-looking face and and long blonde
hair.
And if you dispute that, then you're
going to become the villain. Of course.
Yes. Abishek Shivas says, "What went
wrong in the 1857 war? Who was Taty
Tope?" I don't I remember when I was a
little kid, we were taught about
Tattope. Some reference to to a freedom
fighter called Tate Top. I don't know
about his life history, so I won't be
able to answer that. What went wrong in
1857? We weren't united
and some of us fought for the
occupiers. That's what went wrong. You
see, so the lesson, the moral of the
story is we have to be united. We have
to look out for each other. We still
have the same problem in India today.
We still have brown coolies writing
articles, anti-India articles for
Washington Post and whatnot
and proudly saying that you know what
I'm proud to to have written this
article to to have done this
investigation on so on so on and so
forth. We still have these me jaffers in
the country right that's these are the
things that went wrong for us
historically
shaswat shashwat mishra says we seem to
overhide the capabilities of our weapons
it makes our weapons look substandard on
paper various other countries especially
China seem to hype up their weapons
which enhances the export
I'll tell you what enhances the export
of weapons performance
So and once again performance in in a
battlefield it's not being telecast
live. So if you're watching a cricket
match you know that so and so guy has
performed well and so and so guy has not
performed well. We know exactly who
performed in what way.
Roy Sharma did this. Virat Kohli finally
got some runs.
Right? That sort of thing. But let's say
you use 20 different weapons on the
battlefield. you don't quite know which
one has performed well. But if you win
the battle or the war, then most likely
your weapons are better, right? So if
you want to enhance
the export of your weapons, you've got
to fight wars. You've got to win wars.
If you consistently win, your weapons
are going to be in high demand.
So if you want to export weapons, one
way of doing it is to do marketing
marketing lot of marketing. We have the
best weapons blah blah blah. Enhance you
know exaggerate the capabilities of your
of your weapons. Another way of doing it
is to win. So for example when we had
operation we did not really gain any
territory. In my opinion, the only
measure of victory is how much territory
you gained. Otherwise, it's just
pointless because you know if you take
out some aircraft and crater some
airfield those that can be repaired the
aircraft can be replaced. Territory is
what you need to win. Now one thing we
know for sure in operation tendur is
that our air defense system performed
spectacularly.
we now can factually
state that we have the world's best
battle tested air defense system. So
that performance is what gives you
export orders. Uh
when it comes to hiding the capabilities
of your weapons, I think that's a good
idea actually. Don't don't reveal what
your weapons are capable of. Reveal that
only on the battlefield by winning.
That's what you have to do.
Team talks Dharma says, "Is there a way
to regulate alcohol consumption in a
state because we know banning it doesn't
work. Spreading awareness also fails
because people think it's cool."
Um, alcohol clearly is a is not a very
good thing. Uh, people who abuse alcohol
with they will create all kinds of
trouble for themselves and for for the
world. So,
The thing is if you try to regulate
something then it becomes even more
desirable.
You see
if you ban something or if you regulate
something it becomes more desirable. And
there are some states in this country in
India where alcohol is banned or please
go there.
Please go to to those states and see
what happens on the ground.
Is there no alcohol consumption in those
states?
On the contrary.
Okay. So my point is all these things
are pointless. People will do what they
do. The only thing we can ensure is that
people in some states one hears that
there is too much alcohol consumption.
So something should be do done about
that. And there must be reasons why
certain states have excessive alcohol
consumption while other states don't
have that issue. there must be something
locally you know relevant over there in
those states why you have excessive
alcohol consumption for example I have
heard I'm not sure if I'm right but a
certain certain state in the southern
part of India seems to have an issue
with alcoholism
so what's the reason there must be
something local to that local to that
state which is why maybe alcohol is a
available for very cheap over there
maybe it is locally made alcohol which
is very cheap I'm not sure what it is so
one way of regulating alcohol
consumption is to make it expensive,
right? Make it expensive. Don't ban it.
Make it expensive. Impose extra taxes or
whatever on it. That's one way of doing
it. Banning it doesn't work. Spreading
awareness.
Everyone knows cigarette smoking is bad,
but people still smoke cigarettes. I've
seen doctors who smoke cigarettes. I've
seen dentists who eat who which you pan.
So, spreading awareness makes makes no
difference. The only way of doing it is
to make it more expensive. Make it more
expensive.
Divor Singh says, "Was the falank of
Alexander superior to Roman legionary
warfare? What about Mongol pony blitz
blitzkrieg?"
Uh, the Macedonian fallank. Yeah. Yeah.
That was quite a thing, right? That was
quite a thing. You would have these
soldiers called hoplights if I'm not
mistaken who had these like spears that
were like three times the length of of a
man and you would have these these pe
these hoplights would deploy the the
spears right in front of them and for
and you would have their companions who
would be waiting in the arms behind them
and that was almost an impre impregnable
kind of a you know maneuver
until it was not right? Uh until it it
was defeated. So it was uh so was the
fallank superior to Roman legionary
warfare
and the Mongol pony blitzkrieg?
I think the fallank was relevant for its
time period. The Roman legionaries would
have made short work of the falank
because they had other weapons. They had
ranged weapons.
Um
and the Romans they were able to solve
all problems
whether these were engineering problems
whether the these were tech tactical
problems.
What is the use of failanks if you can
be destroyed at a distance? Tell me. The
Romans would bring in catapults which
would take out your fangs from a
distance of 500 ft. Then what do you do
with the falank? So I would say that the
Roman warfare, the Roman legionary
warfare was superior to anything the
Europeans invented in other other parts
of Europe because the Romans did defeat
the Greeks. They occupied they conquered
and occupied Greece. Roman pony
blitzkrieg.
If the ro sorry, Mongol pony blitzkrieg,
the Mongolian way of warfare
was yeah, definitely ponies and
archery.
They would have made short work of the
Romans, the Mongols. They would have
punched holes through whatever the the
Roman legions looked like. the Mongols
would have defeated them. The Romans
there was there was an innovation that
was ahead of its time. So yeah, I would
say the legionaries would defeat the
fallanks and the and the Mongols would
defeat the legionaries.
Karan says, "Are Avans really our stock
people?" I've seen some of the Afghan
immigrants kind of look like Italians,
blue eyes, blonde hair, etc. Easily
differentiated from local Indians and
Pakistanis. They have mixed Iranic and
Central Asian DNA.
The original Iranian DNA, the original
Iranian people
are were not blonde or blue-eyed. Today,
you will see some people in Iran who are
blonde and blue-eyed because those have
been brought those people were brought
into Iran during the Turk occupation of
Iran from the Caucasus region. The true
Persians
aren't white people. They aren't blonde.
The true Persians are darkhaired, dark
eyed people with light brown skin. Okay,
please understand that first of all,
today's Persia is different. Today's
Persia is the consequence of almost a
thousand years of of Turk occupation.
Who was Nad Sha? You think he was
Persian? He was a Turk.
Who was uh the the Sha of Horasma when
Chingishan invaded Horasma? He was a
Turk. He was not Persian. Persia itself
was under Turk occupation and a lot of
people from Caucases from the Caucasus
region and central Asia were were
settled in Iran which completely
permanently changed the demographics of
Iran.
So before the
foreign occupation of Persia, the
Persians looked like people from western
India maybe slightly lighter skin. Now
coming to Afghanistan
and
the pashon people. Even if you look at
Afghanistan today,
it's not one ethnicity anymore. You have
um the Turkmans, you have the Usuzbcks,
you have the Tajiks, you have the
Hzaras, and God knows what other you may
even have Kiris in Afghanistan. Those
are not the original people of Gandhar.
The original true inhabitants or native
people of Afghanistan or Gandhar are the
pashons. Now even even among the pashons
you will find some people who look very
strikingly almost like Europeans. Sure.
But what does the average pashon look
like? If the average pashon were to walk
around in Delhi, nobody will look at
them twice. That is a fact, right? So
why do some pashons look so different?
because that's the nature of the
genetics of the subcontinent. The
further north you go, the the further
you will have influence from outside.
A great example is the tarim basin
mummies. Let's see what the tarim
mummies look like. So before I show you
what they look like, the tarim mummies
are most likely
the tushara people. Tushara the the
people who were called Tushara in the
Mahabharat
in English they are called Tokarians.
The Tokarians are the ancestors of the
Kushan people. The Kushans are now
assimilated among us right among us
among the Indian people. So the the
Tokarians
they
their language was similar to our
language. It went ka gaga that way. uh
and their religion was was some form of
Hinduism but their genetics were very
different but the genetic lineages were
R1 A1A which is essentially the same as
what we even have today in India. So if
you want to look at the tarim mummies
this is what it looks like. Okay look
let's look at this tarim
mummies.
So let's take a look at the tar mummies.
You see that some of them look central
Asian but many of them look like they
you know uh European
and yet they were culturally Indian.
Uh so the that's the deal.
So overall my to answer your question
after going round about in explaining
all the other uh details the pashons are
our people.
The pashons are an extension of the
north northern Indian population.
Even if you go to some parts of UP etc.
you will find people with blonde hair
sometimes very rarely and blue eyes.
So it's it's not that unusual actually.
All right.
Dn Singh says Jesus's birth is
historically uncertain. Why base modern
chronology on it and retrocalculate
epochs like this elucid? Doesn't this
question the system?
To be entirely honest, there is no hard
evidence of the existence of Mr. Jesus,
right? There's no hard evidence. There's
no archaeological evidence of the
existence of Jesus, but it is that
doesn't necessarily mean that he did not
exist, right?
Uh but like you say his birth is
historically uncertain but we have based
all our modern chronology on that the BC
AD system.
So the year of his his alleged birth is
1 AD not even 0 AD it's 1 AD. So AD is
anomin the year of our Lord and BC is
before Christ. Now they have changed it
to BCE and and CE before common era and
and common era which is nothing but
putting a new new branding on the old
thing.
Uh so why is
the entire modern chronology based on
the birth of someone who we don't even
know existed? It's because the world is
euroentric.
Right? the past 500 years it's the
Europeans who were Christians who have
dominated the world and they have shaped
all of this in the in the way they
wanted.
So yeah, see see even today you will see
that we still uh kind of live with some
of the consequences of the Roman era,
the Roman Empire, the Roman period. For
example, the names of the months August.
Why do we have a month named August? Why
is the
10th why is the 12th month called
December which which is named after this
which is 10
should be not called December should be
called 12vember or something right? but
it's December.
Um,
so all of that is the legacy of the uh
of the time when the Romans ruled Europe
and the overall extended region.
So because the world is euroentric and
the Europeans have uh ruled the world,
that's why we have these issues which
don't really make a lot of sense. Hersh
says, "Is keeping two wives considered
as cheating? Like if it's done mutually?
Is it better than today's hookup
culture, etc. Just a thought? It's
entirely up to you. Uh if you have two
wives and both of those wives are happy
with that, then I suppose it is not
cheating. It's not. If it's done with
the consent of both of both of your
wives.
Uh is it better than today's hookup
culture? I would say it is better than
today's hookup culture for sure.
Absolutely. Hookup culture is an
abomination.
Yeah.
So yeah, if if you if you would like to
be in a situation where you have two
wives who are both okay with it, then I
see nothing wrong with that in my
opinion.
Wun says schematics POV Yahwa lightning
god wife is El Ashura. Indradev
lightning god wife is Ashura. What
Indra Dave lightning god's wife is
Ashura
is Jesus son of Indra Garuda Harudah
Horus why I have no idea sir
I don't see there I don't think there's
anything in common between Indian
between the Indian gods and the sematic
sematic gods
and when it comes to Egyptian gods I'm
not sure if there's a connection there
have been all kinds of uh claims and so
on there have been
uh writers such as what's his name? Oak
Oak P and Oak who have made all kinds of
claims similar to what you're saying
here. Uh Indra Deva's god is Ashura.
Okay, let me just Google this. Who who
was Indra's wife?
Who is Indra's wife?
Indrani
she's the daughter of a Assura
okay that is fine assura sura assur is
is a concept from our culture
lightning god so look my point is that
you know what the way I see it I don't
see there are any I don't see any
connections between arian gods our gods
and the gods of the somatic people
Yahweh They they now are are
monotheists, right? The Egyptians were
polytheists, but I personally see no
connection.
An says you call Pakistan a temporary
nation. Even if we military militarily
take over, what do we do with people who
have learned this adversarial ideology?
I'm not sure what we do with that.
We can't assimilate those people back
into our population.
It could have been done in 1947 if we
had very quickly in 5 10 years
reintegrated Pakistan. Then it would not
have had that much of an effect. But
today you have people who have been
living in Pakistan for several
generations regarding India as the
mortal enemy and who are taught to hate
Hindus. Their their own ancestral
culture Hinduism from the time they are
children. The education system you know
teaches them to hate Hindus. How do you
bring that that big population back into
the Indian population? You can't. You
can't. It'll take maybe a hundred years
to dradicalize that population.
So I do call Pakistan an artificial
temporary nation.
And what needs to happen for peace to
return to the subcontinent and for the
wounds to heal is for first of all for
Pakistan
to break up because it's an artificial
nation.
Pakuna needs to return to Afghanistan.
Sind needs to become independent.
Balojasthan needs to become independent.
Punjabistan can do whatever it wants.
P etc. can return to India. Even that
will be an issue. But yeah that will
return and then let things let that
ideology of hatred which is poured
through the education system end and
then maybe in 50 years 100 years we can
look into it whether we can reintegrate
the population with their own people
which is us but yeah immediately it's
not possible what do we do they hate us
they're all of them are terrorists or
have terrorist uh kind of mindset you
can't integrate them with the Indian
population it would be a disaster.
You're absolutely right. Okay. Caution
World says, "Can the USA do something
similar with India to get their way like
they are doing with Venezuela?
If yes, why? If not, why not? Can having
nuclear weapons save India?"
So, what are they doing with Venezuela
is the question. What is the US doing
with Venezuela? Uh they may be on the
verge of maybe attend uh you know
conducting a regime change operation in
Venezuela. They can even invade
Venezuela.
I remember in the 1990s or something it
was 80 late 80s, early 90s, the
Americans invaded Nicaragua,
right? And captured the leader of
Nicaragu Nicaragua and installed a
different government there. His name was
Manuel Doryga. I suppose he's still in
prison in the US. So they certainly can
do that in any country in the Americas.
They may do that in Venezuela.
Can the US do something similar in
India? Well, they certainly can try that
and the the the might of the US military
is way greater than that of India. So,
let's say hypothetically in a completely
absurd hypothetical situation. The US
decides to invade India, they'll win.
That is guaranteed. They'll win. Even if
we have nuclear weapons, they'll win.
And if we dare to use nuclear weapons,
they will totally destroy India. Um, so
they certainly can do that. But is that
what they would like to do? No, they
would not like to do that. They would
like to control India without destroying
India. They would like to control India
by having a proxy puppet government in
India which is actually controlled by
them. That way they can actually avail
of all the resources of India including
the population, manpower and whatever
else without destroying.
It's one thing to destroy a country and
defeat it that way. It's another thing
another thing to control it without
touching it.
So the ideal situation is you win
without firing a single shot and you
control everything. That's better. So
that's what they would like to do
actually.
E Rahul says child marriage in India was
due to the average lifespan of people
back then due to 1,000 years of
operation. question mark by 18 people
had lived half their life. That was by
the end of the British occupation of
India. We don't know what the average
lifespan of Indian Indians was 1,000
years ago. We don't have any statistics,
any data, any records. If those records
existed, they have been long destroyed.
But we know that by the time the British
left India in 1947, the average lifespan
in India was what? 30, 31, 32. That's
it. That's how badly they had destroyed
India. So the average person would live
31 or 32 years.
Uh which means that by 18 people had
lived half their life. And is that why
you had child marriage in India? No,
absolutely not. That has nothing to do
with that.
Child marriages happen in India even
before 10,000 years ago.
That's a different story. It was a it
was a cultural thing. You had child
marriage all across the world.
like I showed yesterday by giving about
a hundred examples from Europe right and
the west but does it mean that if if if
let's say one family arranged their
son's marriage to the daughter of
another family when both children were 8
years old does it mean that they would
go and have sex obviously not right that
won't h that would not happen it was
simply an arrangement and they would
start living together when they would be
maybe 15 16 something like
So yeah, we we we have to be very
careful not to examine our own history
from a western perspective, right? We
have to understand
our own culture first of all, which now
is becoming more and more alien to us.
We don't even understand our own culture
anymore. It it feels like something
foreign to us now. That's what the
education system has done to us.
Divo Singh says so did CIA kill Homi
Babhaba possibly
um Homie Baba was traveling by air by
aircraft when the aircraft crashed the
aircraft carrying Dr. Homie Baba it
crashed in the French Alps
and the
the wreckage was not
discovered and investigated until a few
years ago.
And this this plane crash happened what
like 50 years ago possibly something
like that. And some
CIA former CIA agent had boasted that we
we we killed Homie Bababa. So it is kind
of like circumstantial evidence. They
will never admit that even if they have
done it but it's possible that something
like that may have happened but there is
no 100% incontrovertible evidence that
they did this. So it's a possibility but
I can't say for sure. Uh Sumit says why
is Abu Zed Ahmed's mind body separation
in cognitive psychology cited more than
Patanjali second century Indian work on
mind body and soul. I don't know who Abu
Zahed Ahmed is but why is Patanjali's
work cited less than somebody who has
done something more recently. One is
recency bias and secondly Patanjali was
Indian. We don't even know if he was a
second century person.
Right.
Uh do we know for sure that Patanjali
lived in the 2nd century AD or BC or
whatever? We don't know for sure. That's
what the westerners claim and that what
that's what we go with. We don't know
for sure. Um so look there is
there is this western tendency
to downplay any Indian achievement
right that's there. They will always try
to you know give the credit to somebody
from who is not Indian. For the longest
time they said it was Arabic numerals.
Now they say grudgingly that it's Hindu
Arabic numerals. Why are they even
Arabic at all? The Arabs themselves
wrote that these were Indian numerals
and Indian mathematics. Al-Hisabhind.
I mean can it get more plain than that?
Right? The Arabs were very clear that
this was Indian mathematics. They never
claimed credit for the mathematics or
the science or the astronomy. It's the
Europeans who ascribed it all to the the
to the Arabs.
So yeah, that's the deal.
UMX says origin of Marvaris. Can you
speak Marwari sir? I can't speak
Marwari. Origin of Marwaris. That's the
origin of Indians.
What next? Origin of Noa. Origin of
people from Noida. Origin of people from
Faridawad.
Come on. We are all Indians.
We are all Indians. Our origin is the
same.
India was settled about I don't know
about 75 80,000 years ago. That's our
origin.
That's our origin. All of us.
Abida Singh says, "Your thoughts on the
recent mummified fossil of a dinosaur
found in Canada with its
skin and organs intact." In my topics in
JP Dialogues, um,
a mummified dinosaur in Canada. Let's
Google that. Okay.
Mummified dinosaur
in Canada. Really? Let's take a look at
that. What's it look like?
Let's take a look at it.
Oh, this is not a mummified dinosaur,
bro.
This is a fossilized dinosaur. It looks
like a mummy because it's so exquisitly
well preserved. It's one of those
armorplated dinosaurs.
Do we have an actual mummified dinosaur?
Dinosaur mummy discovered in Canada.
Let me see a news.
So this is it's got skin, armor,
pigmentation, etc. But it's still a
fossil. It's still a fossil.
And this was found more than a decade
ago.
Organs intact. Really?
Uh organs?
Really? You have organs intact?
remarkably preserved internal organs,
specifically its intestines.
Fascinating. Fascinating. So, it's the
same one. We're talking about this guy.
Right. So, what's my thoughts? Sometimes
you you get these things, but uh it's
still a fossil. It's not a mummified
thing. Mumm mum. What's the definition
of mummification? It's the preservation
of the original tissue. Fos what's the
definition of fossilization?
Fosilization means the replacement of
the original tissue with with uh
minerals which retain the shape of the
original tissue but it's not the
preservation of the original original
tissue. So I I am not blaming you Aida
Singh for for saying this. It's the
media that is misreporting the find.
It's not mummified. It's fossilized but
it's very well fossilized.
But there have been discoveries of let's
say T-Rex skeletons
in which the tibia the no not the tibia
femur
either the t it's probably the femur
bone which is a major leg bone it broke
by mistake and when it broke there was
soft tissue inside which was still
present
that was weird I'm not sure if they were
able to extract DNA probably not okay
let's let's Google this. Okay. Um, soft
tissue
T-Rex femur.
Yeah. Check it out.
So, flexible blood vessels, etc. were
discovered in the in the in the bone
inside the bone of the dinosaur.
But they were not able to discover any
DNA. I'm sure if they did discover the
DNA, they will not have publicized it.
So that's interesting. It's happened
more than once that soft tissue has been
discovered in the bones of dinosaurs.
That's more interesting than than this
uh so-called mummified dinosaur which is
simply a wellpreserved dinosaur.
Okay. Uh 6P70 delta says Bashkir are
said to have the highest R1
concentration.
Direct descendants of Yamna perhaps. Why
do some people from Caucases look
somewhat like Indians? Okay. The
the most prevalent
haplo group among the Yamna people is
R1B.
R1B and uh the most prevalent HLO group
among the Indian and European people is
R1A but both are descendants of R1.
So yeah. Now the bashers
um but if you ask me okay let's let's
let's take a look at this okay R1B
versus R1A distribution R1B
distribution
R1B distribution it's like out of India
you can see you can see everything
except for India and R1A if you look at
that
you will find a totally different story
India and
parts of Russia and parts of U Europe
where you have the highest distribution
of R1A.
Now if you go for R1 itself R1
distribution what do we find? You're
going to find a combination of R1 A and
R1B.
Right?
So does it mean that the Bashkir are
direct descendants of Yamna? I can't say
for sure if you if you so do we have
more people
who belong to R1B compared to R1A no R1A
dominates over R1B in terms of
population you have more than 1 billion
people who are part of the R1A HLO group
that more that many Indians belong to so
uh you know so maybe it's R1 A which is
not Yamna Yamna is is a sister Hablo
group. R1B is a sister HLA group of R1A.
Now, why do some people from the
Caucases region look like look like
Indians? You'll see many people from the
Caucases who look like Indians,
especially Armenians and Georgians,
right? Many of them look like Indians.
There is some ancient connection. The
Turks hate the Armenians and the Turks
like to call the Armenians Indians and
they they use it as an insult
apparently. Right. Um there is some
connection. We I'm not sure what the
connection is.
I know for sure that you had Hindu
temples all across the Caucasus and
Central Asia before the
before before 1 AD.
And in Armenia, some of these Hindu
temples were converted into churches
about 2,000 years ago.
Because Armenia is one of the oldest
countries to become Christian and today
because of the Armenia Turkey thing and
Azarbaijan thing those churches have now
been demolished and mosques have been
built on top of those. So Hindu temple
to Christian church to Islamic mosque is
what's the what the state is today. Uh
but the point is that you know there is
some ancient connection between the
people of India and the people of
especially Armenia and Georgia.
Dimnos has basically confirmed news that
Israel pays7,000
for one pro-Israel post to famous
influencers in the West and in India as
well. By the way, can't trust anyone.
Why should they not do it? If people are
up for sale, if media outlets are up for
sale, why would you not do that? 7,000
bucks is not a whole lot of money for
a a post that is projoration. I am I
would say why doesn't India do this
either India also do this? India should
also do this. Why shouldn't India play
the game?
The Pakistanis, the Chinese, they pay
influencers to put out various
narratives on social media,
right?
The Americans also play pay influencers
who take all shapes and forms. What kind
of influencers?
business people,
politicians,
uh, YouTubers,
including people who stay in Germany and
so on. So why can't India also play play
the game? I don't understand that. Why
does India have to stay out of this?
India should also play the game. And I
have absolutely nothing against Israel
doing this. They they doing the right
thing. They're doing whatever is in
their best interests as should everybody
else.
Pankage says Indians are still called
culling khing in Southeast Asia but we
don't know how much we don't know much
about Odisha's contribution in Southeast
Asia. Your opinion please.
Yeah, if you go to Indonesia and
Malaysia uh Indians are called Kolinga
today. What is Koling historically? It's
Kolinga right but it's now called Odisha
for some reason but historically it was
called Kolinga. So, Kolinga has had this
tremendous contribution
in Indianizing and Hinduizing
the whole of Southeast Asia. Um, the
people of Kolinga were traders,
merchants and they were seaf farers.
Ships from Kolinga used to cross what is
now called the Bay of Bengal. It should
be called the Kolinga Bahasagar. And
they used to go to what what they used
to call Sar Nabumi which is Thailand and
eventually Indonesia, Java, Sumatra all
of that and even Vietnam and so on and
this was going on for at least 3,000
years before today. So around 1,000 BC
at least even most likely before that
you would have ships crossing from
Kolinga all and crossing the crossing
the Bay of Bengal
and trading with Thailand, Cambodia,
Vietnam etc. And over the years this had
the effect of slowly gradu gradually
Indianizing and Hinduizing the whole of
Southeast Asia
and lots of people from India settled
over there. The kingdom of Funan was
founded by
a merchant from Kolinga called Condinia
who married a local princess and that
set up the king the kingdom of Funan.
Similarly, you had the Champa Empire
which was a maritimeratic empire which
was completely Indianized which was
based out of Vietnam.
So the people of Kolinga have done
tremendous
tremendous work towards Indianizing
Southeast Asia and today it's all
forgotten which is sad.
Arunar says I am proud of Indian ancient
achievements but terms like Agnivan are
metaphorical.
Russ Raseratakura
mentions sulfur and salt peter for
alchemy not explosives no evidence like
sources of usage of gunpowder exists
before the muggles. Okay, thank you sir
for your opinion. Thank you sir.
Dn Singh says we are ruled by the people
we are not allowed to oppose. How true
is this? What would that be? I wonder
who are these people in India?
We are ruled by people we are not
allowed to oppose. Well, generally in
any country that you are in, whether it
is in Asia, whether it's in Europe,
whether it's in Africa,
you're not really allowed to oppose the
government, are you? You can express an
opinion that is contrary to what the
government says. You can if if if you're
in a democratic country, you can
register a protest and if if your
protest is approved, you can go and
demonstrate on a certain day and certain
time, but you can't really oppose the
government, right?
I suppose that that's the case
everywhere. In India, you have way more
freedom than in the West.
If you live in the west, you know it's a
police state and if you cross certain
lines lines, they're going to shoot you.
No questions asked. That's not the case
in India. In India, you have way more
freedoms than that. And you actually can
abuse the government and and oppose the
government in so many ways. I mean, look
at all these various people who are
opposing the government all the time.
Um,
so it depends on the country. It depends
on the system. In China, you dare not
oppose the government. You're going to
it's going to end up very badly for you.
In Japan, you can certain do certain
things against the government. opposing
the government vocally, verbally etc. In
France to some extent you can do it if
you belong to certain communities
um and so on. It it depends on the
context. It depends on the geography. It
depends on the on the country. Can you
oppose the government in the US? Well,
yeah, you are allowed freedom of speech
and certain things you can do, but
certain things will get you shot. No
questions asked. It depends.
Da says, "Congrats for 300 live
streams." Thank you very much, sir.
Thank you. Watching your videos since
2021. Well, thank you. And currently
also reading your books. Learned a lot.
Thank you very much, sir. I really
appreciate you and all the viewers.
Thank you very much. Thank you.
Vishal Nafa says, "What's quantum
chromodnamics? Is it significant in
understanding dark matter and energy?"
Quantum chromodnamics is the study of
the strong nuclear force color charges.
So the strong nuclear force you're
talking about quarks there. Quarks are
the constituents of the of the protons
and neutrons which make up the nucleus
of atoms. Quarks are not constituents of
electrons. By the way, the electron is a
fundamental particle. But the proton and
the neutron, they are not fundamental
particles. They are made up of quarks.
And there are six kinds of quarks. Up,
down, top, do, bottom, strange charm,
right? And quarks have color charges,
which is why you have chromodnamics. And
the mediators are the gluons. So that is
what quantum chromodnamics is all about.
It's about understanding the properties
of quarks and gluons and uh all of that.
So that's quantum chromamics. It has
most likely no significance in
understanding dark matter or energy.
Dark matter is most likely something
associated with gravity
and possibly the weak
force, the weak force possibly, but
definitely not uh the strong force and
dark energy. We don't even know what it
is. Okay. So, quantum chromodnamics has
essentially very little if any role at
all to play in trying to understand dark
matter or energy.
Florence says, given the Israeli
influence across US politics and
institutions,
why no Jewish president yet, does this
prove that the real power lies be beyond
the old office? It proves nothing. It's
interesting that you are mentioning that
there's been no Jewish president yet.
Interesting. Yeah, probably there's been
no Jewish president yet. You've had
Christian presidents and one possibly
Muslim president Obama. Possibly,
possibly not sure, but definitely no
Jewish presidents, but that obviously
the absence of evidence is not the
evidence of absence or any any such
thing. So it doesn't prove anything as
such,
right?
But Israel definitely has a significant
influence in the US in politics in
institutions which is clear from the
fact that the US gives its unconditional
support always to Israel. There's no
question about that. But is there a
conspiracy behind that? And is Israel
the real power behind the whole office?
I would not venture so far as to claim
that. It's possible definitely but
there's no guarantee. There's no proof.
Divor Singh says Fodor Dostovski led me
down a dark dark path. Worth reading.
It's certainly Dostovski is definitely
worth reading but not all always the
most pleasant experience but you would
learn a lot about the human psyche
from someone like Duvki for sure.
Fast snail says are morning people more
effective I won't try.
I'm not sure about that. I mean
getting up early in the morning and
doing stuff is definitely great. I have
personally been a morning person as well
as a night person.
You know there have been times
significant parts of periods of my life
when I've been someone who wakes up
really early like 5:00 a.m. 4:45 a.m.
I've done that for many years. I've also
been a significant night person. Like
right now also I'm doing it two sleeping
at 2 a.m. 2:30 a.m. but I'm going back
very soon to being a morning person. So
it depends on you. Do do what is best
for you. Do what what what suits you
best. Some people can't wake up early
morning. It's okay. Wake up late
morning. Some people work best at 2:00
a.m. 3:00 a.m. That's also right. Some
people are are are super creative in in
in the you know darkness of the night.
They do their most creative work at like
2:00 a.m. 3:00 a.m. when everyone else
is asleep. They feel super creative at
the time. If that's you, then you do you
do that. Other people feel super
creative early morning,
4:00 a.m., 5:00 a.m. when no one's awake
yet. Whatever it is that that works best
for you, you should do that.
And you should experiment. Try both and
see what works works better for you. We
know the ring. Thank you very much sir.
Thank you. Shuham Shubhham Vare says the
earth is trillions of dollars in debt to
whom Jupiter how to extract more tax
from the ultra rich with the without
them leaving the country.
Uh I'm not sure who who we are in debt
to. I'm not really sure. It's all a scam
actually. It's all a scam. this entire
debt thing, Jupiter, maybe maybe Uranus.
Uh how to extract more tax from the
ultra rich without them leaving the
country? Why do we have to
regard the ultra rich as as bad people?
See, ultra rich are bad people. If your
system is evil and corrupt, if your
system is evil and corrupt, it means
that only the evil and corrupt can
succeed in it.
which guarantees that the ultra rich are
going to be evil and corrupted. But if
your system is not corrupt, it's not
evil, then it will ensure that good
people succeed, which means that the
ultra rich are going to be really good
people who provide a lot of genuine
value to society. And maybe your system
is a mixed system which has good aspects
and bad aspects. It has corruption, but
it has some redeeming qualities also. In
that case, some of the ultra rich are
going to be really evil, corrupt people
and some of the ultra rich are going to
be good people. The point is we know you
know because India has gone through a
thousand years of foreign occupation and
the people who have succeeded have
generally been crooks. That's why
Indians generally see rich people as
people who are who most likely have
succeeded through cutting corners and
and possibly stealing. But that is a bad
mindset to have.
I would like everybody in India to be
rich, to be ultra rich, why not?
And if that is the case, do you want
everyone to be taxed very badly? Uh so I
would say that tax that that taxation
should be simple
and it should be transparent, clear
rules
and it should not be like if you are
richer, you should extract extract more
tax from that person. It should be the
same rules for everybody, same
percentage for for everybody. So if you
are richer obviously you'll pay the same
percentage but the output will be more.
That's how it should be.
AJ Sharma says how Hollywood dig media
creates propaganda.
I don't know what dig media is but
Hollywood how does it create propaganda?
By making movies that tell lies. It's as
simple as that. Make um for example who
won the second world war. It's the
Soviets
who won the second world war. The the
better question is who defeated the
Nazis?
It is mostly the Soviets who defeated
the Nazis. They did most of the
fighting, most of the dying and most of
the winning. But if you watch Hollywood
movies, they will show the Americans as
the great winners and the great
champions and the great saviors of the
world. So that's how you do propaganda.
You tell lies
through movies and TV series. That's how
you do it. For example, the movie
Dunkerk,
not a single Indian was present in the
movie Dunkerk when in in the actual
actual historical events, you had a lot
of Indians there. So just erase the
truth and show lies. That's how you
create propaganda.
Divor Singh says AQI Delhi went hellish
after Diwali. Is firecrackers really
that important? It started after 1947.
Raan Dhan was started in in 1947.
Indians have been bursting crackers for
hundreds of years. That is a part of
recorded history.
The AQI in Delhi, it is hellish because
of the burning of stubble. What is
stubble? Uh it is something that's
burned by farmers after harvesting their
crops. Whatever is left behind, the
stubble, you know, let's say you are
harvesting wheat. So you're going to cut
the wheat plants and the stems will be
left behind.
So what happens with the stems? You want
to plant a new crop now, but you have
the stems of the wheat plants there
which have dried out. So what you do is
you burn that. Burning that will also
have the effect of fertilizing the soil.
So burn all of that. That's called
stubble burning. And stubble burning is
practiced all across uh various parts of
northern India. I will not take the
names of the states unnecessarily.
Take a flight from Delhi and look
outside of the window. You will see
lines of flames all over the place and
big columns of smoke rising everywhere.
That is what is causing the poor EQI in
Delhi and it's going to get worse every
winter. It's not Diwali. It's not one
one or two nights of cracker of bursting
crackers that is doing this. We It's
very important for us to note this.
Okay. Um so it is the stubble burning.
It is the practices of various of of
farmers widespread larges scale
practices that are causing
this hellish AQI. It is not Diwali
firecrackers. Look, it's part of
tradition. It's part of what it's what
we've been doing for centuries.
So I would say let's not go after Diwali
and we have to find ways to address the
real issue, the real problem. Kiran Mo
sir, thank you very much. Thank you sir.
Thank you. I was a big fan of your
wicket keeping and your batting as well.
Satellite says uh if Russia Okay, there
are too many emojis here. I'm not able
to understand what's going on here. If
Russia is a bear and India is an
elephant, they get too strong. Any
chance that
eyes of China and USA teaming up
together defeat Russia? India and China.
Um, no.
The US and China won't team up. They are
natural adversaries and so is China and
Russia and China and India.
So, I don't see the Chinese and the
Americans teaming up. Maybe they could
perhaps,
you know, it makes no sense for China to
to do something that that will cause the
downfall of Russia
because then because then the Americans
will be able to give their undivided
attention to China.
So it doesn't make sense for that to
happen. Yeah. Will the US get and China
get together to do something to India?
That is that is more of a possibility.
But not Russia. Well, not Russia.
Shubhham Var says, "How to tell a
statistic is made up or fake?"
Okay. How to tell that a statistic is a
fake statistic?
Uh the average IQ of Indians is 72. That
is one statistic that is that that is
very popular, right? How to tell? You
have to look up the source of that
claim.
So if they okay let's try and find this
okay what's the average IQ of Indians
what's
the average
IQ of Indians
the average IQ of Indians where is it
come on
76 and 99 these figures are highly
controversial exactly that's my point
highest IQ in India where the so if if
If you get this claim that the average
IQ of India is 76, what's the source?
What's the source?
Oh god. The source of the claim
that India's
average IQ
is is 76.
So we have to look at the research paper
that has made this claim and then you
have to look at the research method
methodology.
Ah
the controversial works of psychologist
Richard Lynn and political scientist
which is the misnomer Tatu Hanen. Okay.
And these people they took very small
tiny
small unrepresentative samples
and they use that to represent the
entire nation. You understand how you
can tell lies through statistics. You go
to let's say an orphanage where the
children are let's say hypothetically
malnourished and they are underage not
adults and then you do some IQ tests in
the English language and you apply those
to those children who don't even know
English. So they're going to perform
very poorly and then the average IQ
comes out at 76 from a collection of
let's say 20 students and then you claim
that the average IQ of Indians is is 76.
That's how you make up fake statistics,
make fake claims and then the world
starts believing them. That's how we do
it. All right? So you can tell this only
if you understand how fake statistics
are constructed.
You have to understand these things
otherwise you can't tell otherwise
you'll be misled. So you to educate
yourself. If your teachers and your
schools and your in universities do not
educate you, it is important that you
take the responsibility yourself that I
will educate myself and I will learn how
these things are done. All right.
6 P70 Delta says Kushell and Abijit
Aritra support Israel stating that the
historical homeland of Jews it is. Yeah.
Okay. But when it comes to Ukraine and
Russia, a different set of logic
applies. Ask them why this hypocrisy.
Look, I don't know what some what other
people say. I am not responsible for
what they say. I don't know if this is
what they claim. I have not I don't
watch podcasts. I don't see do all that.
And I'm not going to ask them why this
hypocrisy or not or whatever. I am
responsible for what I say,
right? Uh and and people have various
reasons for for coming to various
conclusions and they have the right to
come to whatever conclusions they want.
It's up to them. Um,
what what is my perspective on Israel?
It is indeed the historical homeland of
the Jews and Israel has the right to
exist and the people of Israel have the
right to that nation. That is my clear
uh unambiguous perspective. When it
comes to Ukraine and Russia,
I'm not sure how we can apply the logic
of Ukraine to logic of Israel to Ukraine
and Russia. Historically, Ukraine was
also part of Russia. Okra means
borderlands. Anyway, that's that's uh
I've spoken about this in depth and what
Kushal Mea Abhijitra says say or don't
don't say I'm not aware of it and
and yeah, it's up to them.
They have the right to make whatever um
to have whatever views they see as right
and they those views don't have to agree
with my views. That's fine. Vignor Singh
says Indian lobby in California managed
to force Gavin Museum new Gavin Newsome
to veto important bills prohibiting
foreign nations from interfering in the
state.
Indian lobby
in California managed to force Gavin
Newsome to veto important bills
prohibiting foreign nations from
interfering in the state.
So what's the effect of this?
So first of all the Indian lobby has
forced Gavin Newsome. So they have
something on him do they? They have
tremendous leverage apparently.
Otherwise you can't force someone like
Gavin Newsome to do something. And Gavin
Newsome has vetoed bills that prohibit
foreign nations from interfering in the
state in of California which means that
now foreign nations can interfere in the
state of California.
How is it in the interests of the Indian
lobby unless India can interfere in
California? I'm not sure. I'll have to
look into this, sir. I'll have to look
into this. Interesting. Interesting.
Vive Singh says Indian defense is
conducting a triforce exercise in in
Rajasthan and Gujarat. Okay. Followed by
a no sale zone in Goa and Karvar. Is
this just the preparation for something
big? What are my views?
Can't say.
Look, if you want to do something big,
you don't you don't announce it. You
don't telegraph it.
If you want to do something big like
let's say do something to Pakistan, you
don't announce it in this manner.
You do it sudden suddenly, quietly.
But of course, if you want to do
something big,
then
if you start moving the armed forces in
a big way, then it looks like you know
you're start you're preparing for an
invasion. So you could say it's just a
military exercise exercise that we are
doing. So that also that logic also
works. So is this preparation for
something big? Maybe, maybe not. I can't
say. I don't think
something big will happen at this point
in time. I don't think so. Maybe I'm
mistaken in in which case I'll be happy
to say I was mistaken. If something big
happens, I'll be actually happy. Right?
It's high time something big happens but
I think it's unlikely. I think it's
unlikely at this point. Rahul G says why
is Russia strategic conducting nuclear
forces drill? Because you have to be
always prepared. You have to keep see
why do nations conduct military
exercises. Why is it done
to keep the armed forces in a state of
readiness? The armed forces should not
become complacent or lethargic. So
always keep drilling, always keep doing
some military exercise or the other so
that you are always fighting fit and
ready. That's why you do it and that's
why this is being done.
Dins says says will oneyear military
conscription solve civic sense problem?
It's not
practical.
Let me tell you why. India has a
population of 1.4 billion people, right?
How many
people turn 18 every year? Let's ask
Google
how many Indians
turn 18 every year. Let's see.
Approximately 12 million Indians turn 18
every year. Okay.
12 million every year. approximately
and obviously half of them are going to
be males.
So let's say you want to do one year
military service for every year for 6
million males. Can the Indian armed
forces do all that babysitting and
handholding of 6 million men every year?
Don't they have anything else to do like
taking care of the borders and whatever
else? Not possible. Let's say you do
only 10%.
Instead of 6 million, six lakh even that
is a huge number.
Okay, you do 1%.
But then it doesn't solve any problem.
You see, it's not practical. That's the
problem.
Kanesh Koshik says how and when or when
and how did we go from Sanskrit to Hindi
through many intermediate sta stages.
Hindi did not suddenly appear one day
out of Sanskrit. Before Hindi, you had
other older languages. Praits,
right? Uh so one of the older praits we
know about is Pali. Pali was spoken
about 2 and a half thousand years ago in
the Magad region of of Paratwash. It was
the language that was spoken by the
Buddha to communicate with the local
people because Sanskrit was by that time
already seen as a high language and not
the vernacular language the people that
that the language that people spoke
commonly. So that's why Gotham Buddha
preferred to do his preachings in Pali
instead of Sanskrit.
So even 2 and a half thousand years ago
we had moved on from Sanskrit in in in
in you know in terms of the vulgar
language the the common commonplace
language. So you had multiple stages
multiple languages. For example we have
a language which is a very major
language in India which is the Marati
language. Did Marati emerge out of Srit
straight away? No.
A thousand years ago you had something
called Maharashtri Prait which is the
ancestral language of of Parathi. If you
talk about Gujarati a thousand years ago
you had something called Gurjari, old
Gujarati which is the ancestral language
of not just Gujarati but also of the of
the Marawadi and Vadi languages.
So you had multiple languages that
emerged over time
and these flowed continuously from and
and and the languages changed and
evolved over time.
So that is how it happened. It is the
upper branch upper branchization
of Sanskrit that happened. All right.
Next travel guide and tip says what will
be the outcome of the Trump Xiinping
meeting? I think Trump will want to make
some concessions so that Xiinping can
start selling rare earths again.
Most likely I don't think Trump has a
lot of leverage over Xi Jinping this
time. Yeah. So most likely the US will
offer to make some concessions to China.
That's what I think will happen. A gore
a chasm. A goricasm. Okay. Says what
happens if Russia suddenly stops all
crude refined products and gas exports
right around the winter? I guess Russia
contributes about 10 to 12% to the
world. It will cause a spike in in
demand and uh spike in oil prices in the
world.
Um
yeah, it will certainly certainly have a
significant spiking impact on oil prices
and um gas prices etc. around the world.
See which are the major nations that
that purchase Russian oil? One is India.
India may be on the verge of potentially
reducing some of the purchases because
of US pressure. I don't know.
Uh another one is China.
Um and then you have India purchasing
Russian crude and refining it, turning
it into various other products like
diesel and whatnot and then exporting it
to Europe and other nations. So that
could also be hit. So if Russia suddenly
stops all crude, all refined products
etc. You're going to have a surge in oil
and petroleum product prices across the
world. 6P70 delta says serious question
need detailed answer why TFR of Israel
is so high despite TFR of Jews in Russia
and US being around 1.1 to 1.5. No other
high income nation has such high TFR.
Look, I am not an expert in Israel in
Israel's policies. But if the TFR of the
people of Israel is about let's say
three or three and a half, let's find
out.
Let's find out what is the TFR.
Israel TFR
uh about three children per woman. So,
so significantly higher than Western
countries and other countries. Why is
that so? I'm sure the Israeli government
has offers incentives
uh to people to have more children.
That's what I'm assuming. I don't know.
I am not an expert in Israel policies
and all that, but I'm telling you that
most likely there are incentives that
are given to the people of Israel to
have more children. I cannot give you a
more detailed answer than that.
Rashid Shirasav says, I asked about zero
earlier.
My friend's dad got fired after he
founded team reported to US embassy. He
founded
cops came to his college his scholarship
revoked
zero. What is co zero? Let me let me
find out what is zero. Let me Google
this. What is cir?
Canadian investment regulatory
organization. I'm sure that's not what
you're trying to talk about here.
Uh
okay. I'm not sure what zero is. Your
friend's dad got fired after he founded
team reported to US embassy.
Cops came to his college. His
scholarship revoked. Your
cops came to his college. Which country
is your friend's dad in? Is he in the
US? Is he in Canada? Is he in Germany?
Is he in some other country? Is he in
India? I'm not able to understand what
the context of what you're saying is
sir. I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry.
Uh, Dnos says, "Big Mayan owl god."
Okay. Kokulkan,
which Mayans invoked when fighting
Spaniards turned out to be a owl
like dressed guy on psychedelic drugs
who got killed in minutes.
Okay.
A god is is an idea and sometimes the
idea is represented in the form of a an
idol or paintings or carvings of
whatever. It's not some guy, right? Or
if some guy is is cosplaying a god
and he's on psychedelic drugs, you're
going to get killed in minutes.
Obviously, you fight the Spaniards
who've got metal weapons that the that
the uh Mayans don't have, Aztecs don't
have. So yeah,
right. Spade says, "For the past 5 days,
I've been getting tweets from anti-Hindu
account. This has been happening since
Diwali. Why are left-wing accounts
always spewing venom against India?
It's it's fashionable right now to be
hindophobic and there is no action.
There is no consequences of being
hindophobic. Look, if you are let's say
Islamophobic, there will be
consequences. you may be banned from
from the platform or maybe somebody will
come and take your head off. Um, if you
are anti-Semitic, there will be the
platform may ban you and there may be
some legal action taken against you
depending on which country you are in.
Uh, if you are anti-Christian, I suppose
nothing much happens to you, but
something may some perhaps happen to
you. Some kind of consequence of some
kind. But if you are Hinduhobic, you can
do it with impunity and there's no
consequences.
And Hinduism is the last evil religion
left, right? We are the last
polytheistic religion standing. Despite
having being been under foreign
occupations for a thousand years, we
still stand. And that is unacceptable to
the west. So makes sense.
Uh Dimnor Singh says, can the drug
cartels supposedly trained by ex army
men make a dent against US army if they
fight? No. No chance.
But the point is, why would the drug
cartels fight the US army?
Why do the drug cartels exist?
To supply
drugs to the US, right?
And why are drugs available on every
street corner in the US? Aren't drugs
illegal? So why do all Americans take
drugs at some point in their lives? Why
is it a why is it a right of passage or
of passage in the US? Why am I giving a
French accent here? Why is it the
passage right of passage in in the US?
Why is it so? Maybe there's some
connection. Maybe maybe it is being done
maybe it's being done on purpose. Maybe
the drug cartels
serve a purpose. You know, maybe they
serve some clients.
So why would they fight the US army?
that that that performative thing is
done once in a while but overall they
play a a role. Okay. Pratik Bora says
are mushrooms food of the future? Why is
awareness limited? Are mushrooms food of
the future? Mushrooms are fungi, edible
fungi. Some of them many of them are
very dangerous. Don't eat those. Yeah.
Uh and uh they are pretty good sources
of protein from what I know. and they
taste kind of like meat.
Are they the food of food of the future?
I'm not sure about that.
What's the food of the future? The food
of the past, I suppose. Why do we need a
different food of the future?
Um, yeah, I'm not sure if mushrooms are
are the food of the future. I'm not sure
about that. Why is awareness limited?
In India, people don't really eat
mushrooms, right? Yeah. It's not been
been something we have been accustomed
to eating traditionally. Not sure why,
but it is what it is. Divor Singh says
this Soros guy has a god complex. He
runs left wings of too many countries.
Can't figure out if he is a pawn of the
deep state or an enemy. He is not an
enemy of the deep state. A person of
that stature, if he tries to be the
enemy of the deep state, he will not
exist for too long,
right? He certainly has a god complex.
did he once took down the British
economy to a certain extent and he has
penetrated
the cabinets of so many different
countries through his assets. He's
definitely not an enemy of the deep
state. I'll tell you that
Mistri says
what if we would want to contribute to
our nation and culture as an atheist
most of our cultural aspects are tied
with religious scriptures and beliefs.
Okay. So let's say you are an atheist
and you want to contribute to the nation
and its culture as an atheist. Most of
the cultural aspects are tied with
religious scriptures and beliefs. Okay?
So you could contribute to the nation
maybe as an engineer,
you know, maybe you build roads, maybe
you build highways, maybe you build
bridges, maybe you design aircraft,
maybe you design submarines, maybe you
design um you know ships, maybe you
design helicopters, maybe you build
helicopters, construct construct stuff.
So that's one way you could do it as an
atheist, right? uh but you want to
contribute to culture as an atheist
maybe you could be an architect and
create new architectural styles
that doesn't have to be tied to
religious scripture and beliefs so I'm
sure there are many avenues that you
could explore which are not necessarily
tied to uh religion and religious
beliefs and scriptures right it's
possible
parasi is a new member thank you very
much sir and welcome to the channel I
really appreciate your become becoming a
member. Thank you very much.
Past snail says, "Visited Hampy heritage
site and was amazed by archaeolog
archaeological marvels." Uh, highlights
the greatness of prosperous Vijayagar
Empire of the 16th centuries. urge
others to visit. I would also urge
others to visit for sure. I should visit
it myself. I've never visited Hampy. I
should. I should. I've seen photographs
and all that. So clearly a magnificent
archaeological site and of course
painful to visit but we should visit.
So I agree with you sir and I would also
urge everybody whoever can please go and
visit this wonderful amazing
archaeological site and it'll
give you an idea of how prosperous and
how great the Vijayagoga Empire was and
what was taken from us.
Divor Singh says, "Can God create a rock
heavy enough that God himself can't move
it?" The sentence, this sentence
basically logically disproves an all
powerful God.
H interesting. Is this a logical
self-contradiction?
Can God create a rock heavy enough then
that God himself can't move it?
H
so this was this would assume that God
is a physical creature
right
because if God is the designer of the
universe
who has designed the universe let's say
coded the universe and decided what are
the rules that the universe will obey
then God doesn't really have to maybe
the universe is far bigger than God
actually is. Let's say God is a
programmer. Okay, we we're talking about
the simulation hypothesis here. Let's
say God is a programmer who has
programmed the universe in a simulation.
In that case, the simulation is a
non-physical simulation. It is physical
for us but not for God.
So, I'm not sure if this sentence
logically disproves an all powerful God.
It disproves an all powerful God only if
you assume if we assume that God himself
is within the universe that he has
created and God himself is physical.
If God is not physical, if God is not
part of the universe, maybe God is
outside of the universe or God is the
universe and is non-physical
then this logically does not disprove
anything. So you know think beyond
physicality.
Paras Vidi says thank you for your
knowledge. Thank you very much sir.
Thank you so much.
Divor Singh says what is the best
argument for the existence of God for
you? Ontological contingency argument
first more argument I don't know.
I
am a hopeful agnostic.
I am not by any means an atheist.
I
to be very honest I think atheists are
idiots.
Yeah. No, no disrespect meant to
anybody. It's just how I see it.
But I
I have not seen any evidence of God, of
the existence of God. I have seen a
universe that exists which follows a set
of rules, some of which we understand,
most of which we don't understand at
all. But it has a set of rules. Now,
does it mean that that a god has created
it?
It doesn't necessarily mean that. Maybe
there's no God at all which would be
which would be very disappointing. So
I'm hopeful
that God exists and all that but is
there any argument for the existence of
God? I am not sure. I have not delved
that deep into philosophy. Can't say for
sure at all.
Vive Singh says without Islamic and
British rule would India have become a
global leader in science and technology
and how would the world look like look
today?
Well, that's an interesting question.
Would India have become a global leader
in science and technology? Did India
have
what the Europeans had that that that
burning desire, that burning drive, that
that urgency
to to develop technology at a fast
pace, fast rate. I think one of the one
of the criticisms you could make of
Indian civilization is that it was very
content.
It was very content that it knew a lot
of things about the world
and maybe there was to some extent a
lack of urgency.
I mean why did Indians never invent the
bicycle?
Why did Indians never invent the
bicycle? It doesn't take a tremendous
amount of technology to to invent a
bicycle.
Why did that innovation not exist?
A bicycle is something. See the wheel
existed for thousands of years in India.
The wheel.
So why didn't any Indian put two wheels
together in that manner? We had steel,
we had iron, we had metal for thousands
of years which you could have used for a
chain. So and you can even make a
bicycle out of wood, right? So why
didn't Indians
ever invent the bicycle?
So to some extent it looks like there
was some lack of urgency, lack of
innovation, right?
the
the Europeans once they acquired certain
technologies they just took it to the
next level in a very very rapid time in
a very rapid way in a very short time
frame we went from the dark ages to to
nuclear energy in just a couple just a
100 years
India never did that right so I'm not
sure if India would have be become a
global leader in science and technology
India was the greatest knowledge
superpower Yeah, we invented education.
We invented the concept of the
university,
but maybe we lacked some of the urgency
and some of the qualities of the of the
Europeans, possibly. Yeah.
Paris says, why not build a public
system to track how government funds are
spent across sectors? If everyone could
see the money flow could greatly cut
corruption and laundering. What do you
think?
Okay. The idea is to build a public
system that tracks how government funds
are spent across sectors.
H a public system to track who will
build it.
How will we know what funds are being
used where?
Are you talking about a third party
system which is not affiliated with the
government? If you are not in the
government, you don't quite know where
the money is going, right?
You know what the budget is, what the
government has announced. You know how
much money is allocated to X project, Y
project, Z project, whatever, whatever,
whatever, right? We know all that. But
how is the money actually being used?
How will we know it? You can only know
it if you are part of the government.
Which means that the government has to
create this public system to track the
funds. But if there is allegedly any
corruption in the government,
will this public system
be high fidelity?
Will it be reliable? You see, you see
what the problem is.
Ideally, you should have everything you
know that is the this these systems
should exist. Ideally, everything should
be transparent. Ideally, but it's not an
ideal world, right? And if somebody
decides let's say within the government
to to to build a system like this which
makes everything available to the public
in transparent manner if there are
sectors of the government that are
corrupt and that are very powerful will
they allow this to happen
right so in in in theory it's a great
idea
and if the system starts exposing where
the corruption is will that not cause a
big problem for whoever is running the
system.
Right? So
in theory it's a great idea. In practice
it will never happen until we change the
system and and
you know launch a war on corruption.
Ashoto thank you very much sir. Thank
you.
Sharma says American Senate has Roman
eagle and fascis
which symbolize Rome's authority over
America.
dollar also has the Roman eagle.
Yeah. So you see the west regards Rome
as one of its uh foundations of western
civilization. Rome was not a
civilization. It was an empire. But if
you ask the west the people of the west
Europeans and European origin people
what do they regard as the two or three
foundations of their of their
civilization which is not really
civilization they will say it's it's
Rome some of it's Rome it's Egypt and
it's u it's Israel as in the the the
Jewish people Jewish culture Judo Roman
values Judeo-Christian values that sort
of thing So, if you look at the American
Express credit card,
I suppose I could show it to you. What
you will find is that it has a Roman
Centurion on it. Let's see.
MX credit card.
What's it look like? There you have it.
What is this? It's a Roman centurion,
Roman soldier. So
yeah, it doesn't mean that Rome author
Rome has any authority over America.
Rome doesn't even exist anymore. It's
Italy which is a vasal state of the US.
So it's the other way around actually.
Okay. IPK_1
says but sir Arian invasion theory is
true. 100% literacy sir.
I know sir. I know. I know. Ran invasion
theory is 100% gospel truth. Yes sir.
100% literacy.
6P70 Delta says, "Hope you remember my
question about Buryats. Did you see
a knife duel between a Yakut and a
Ukrainian soldier that even Elon Musk
spoke about? Guess who won?" It was the
Yak the Yakut person.
I remember. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. I had seen that a couple of years
ago. I think it was a couple of years
ago. I don't remember your question
about Buryats. Was it What was it?
I've taken too many questions today.
Uh but yes, there was a Yakut soldier
who was fighting who who's a Russian
citizen and he got into a knife fight
with a Ukrainian soldier. He lost a part
of his ear or something, but he won and
he got an award from Mr. Putin, didn't
he? Yeah, I I'm aware of that. Yes.
Okay. Kiran Media says, "Congrats on the
third 300 episode. Thank you very much,
sir. Keep on keep it going. Cheers."
Cheers, sir. Thank you so much. Thank
you for your encouragement and your
support means a lot. Thank you sir.
Divor Singh says treaty of Tripoli says
US is not questioned. My goodness. What
is the treaty of Tripoli? I'm not aware.
Let's Google it.
Treaty of Tripoli. What is that? Treaty
of Tripoli.
What's it say? Tripoli.
Um
let's quickly see. Uh, it's between the
US
and
the tree Barbari. Okay. 1796
Libya. Okay. Authored by Joel Barlo.
And what's it say about Christianity?
Uh, okay. This is interesting. It's
cited in discussions regarding the role
of religion in the US government due to
a clause in article 11 of the English
language translation that was ratified
by the Senate and signed by the
president which says which states the
government of the United States of
America is not in any sense founded on
the Christian religion
and modern translations of the official
treaty confirm that no such phrase
exists in the Arabic text. Okay, that's
interesting. A pretty interesting
historical curiosity, I suppose.
And if the US even even if the US did
sign such a treaty with uh Libya in
1700, whatever, is it binding that does
it change the nature of the US? I'm not
sure it does. Not sure. So, I'm not sure
what what the real truth is, whether the
Arabic text also has a thing. It looks
like it doesn't. So I'm not sure why
that English version
English language version of the text
which says the US is not Christian was
ratified. I'm not sure why.
Yra Singh Shakawad is a new member.
Thank you very much sir. Thank you very
much.
Dib Yayan says what's the story of AQ
Khan Abdul Khadr Khan? Abdul Kadir Khan
was this Pakistani nuclear scientist
who apparently was working in Europe in
the early 1980s
and who allegedly stole
blueprints of a nuclear reactor or some
kind of was it centrifuges was it a
nuclear reactor what was it I'm not
quite sure but some kind of blueprints
he stole apparently probably from the
Netherlands and he brought those back to
Pakistan And that's how he was he was
able to start Pakistan's nuclear program
which ended which culminated in the
development allegedly of nuclear weapons
by Pakistan. That is the story of AQ
Khan that what that's what we are told.
I personally don't believe that
Pakistani nuclear scientists had the
capability to develop a an indigenous
Pakistani nuclear weapons program or
even a nuclear energy program on their
own even with the help of blueprints
donated by the west.
So that's the story we are told but most
likely the Pakistani nuclear weapons are
American nuclear warheads given to them
on loan. Silia thank you very much sir.
Thank you.
Okay next question. Arman
Madwani says what are the historical and
socioeconomic reasons for Indians
becoming carb maxers who don't
prioritize protein. India is the only
nation in the world where protein
consumption is negatively correlated
with disposable income. Wow. Really
incredible.
One of the reasons why Indians have
become carb maxers.
You know if you see the typical Indian
breakfast
it's carbohydrates.
It's going to be aloo paratha which is
all carbs with uh I don't know some dal
or some cholay. If you look at the
Indian breakfast in in in southern
India, it's going to be idlies and dosas
and all that it's just carbs, carbs,
carbs. If you look at your regular
lunch, it is roti which is carbs. If
dal, chaval, dal has a little bit of
protein. Chaval is all carbs and some
subabzi.
Why is it like this?
One of the reasons why our diet became
carbscentric is because we faced several
hundred years of artificially engineered
famines that were imposed on us by the
British. So we had to eat whatever was
available and that became somehow carb
ccentric carbohydratecentric.
Another relig another reason is
religion.
We became very pacifistic.
No meat,
right? No meat. And we now imagine that
our ancestors were all vegetarians.
Uh maybe this is the the influence that
Buddhism that Bodha Dharma had on Indian
life. See Bod Dharma emerged about 2 and
a half thousand years ago during the
life of Gotham Buddha. But it was an
obscure fringe
uh path of dharma. It was an obscure and
very fringe dharmic path in India until
it was catapulted to national and global
eminence by Ashoke by Emperor Ashoke.
And both the dharma Buddhism is all
about nonviolence
and and uh not eating meat etc.
And that became
mainstream in India as a consequence.
And today Indians imagine that their
ancestors did not eat meat and Lord Ram
did not hunt a deer and so on and and
what I'm saying right now will right now
offend a lot of people who are watching
right now. I know that um and so on you
know so these are some of the reasons
why Indians have become carb maxers
that we we we believe that we should eat
carbs only you know don't eat protein
meat is evil and uh yeah that sort of
thing. So multiple reasons, one is this
the the starvation diet that we had to
adopt which became part of our tradition
and culture and secondly this this thing
about not eating meat.
Okay. Divor Singh says was the B2
designed by an Indian who then betrayed
the US and gave the designs to China. I
think it was a parci person. It
he did not design the B2 the entire B2
aircraft. He designed the stealth
technology,
right? Let's let's quickly Google it. It
was a parc uh engineer.
Par
engineer
B2 stealth
spy. Okay, that that should be enough
enough uh keywords. Okay. Noshir Gowadia
Indian Indian board born pari engineer
who was instrumental in designing the
propulsion system for the B2 stealth
bomber and he was later convicted to
espionage and uh yeah selling classified
information to China. Yeah. So he was a
par
obviously of Indian origin and he's the
guy who is now in prison. I think he's
still alive. So he's in prison and he's
been sentenced to about 30 something
years in prison.
Amisha says, "Is a Tarhan dress the
world's old oldest woven garment?" Is
it? What is the Tarhan dress? I'm not
aware of it. Let me see. Okay, let's
see. Uh, Tarhan dress.
What is that?
Okay. Cairo, Egypt. It's over 5,000
years old. My goodness. It has to be the
oldest woman garment. It's more than
5,000 years old. How did it survive?
Because Egypt is so dry. Because
Egypt has a very dry climate, very
little moisture. That's why such organic
material was able to survive for so
long. More than 5,000 years. Wow.
Definitely the world's oldest surviving
woven garment for sure. An says followup
catch 22 governance versus education
system what are the first steps towards
improving government's governance system
you generally talk about fixing
education to fix bat
what are the first steps towards
improving the governance system the
government
the first step is to launch a war on
corruption
Okay,
if you can wipe out corruption,
what else can you ask for? That will be
the only improvement improvement we
need. Another improvement, structural
improvement is that you know we should
move to a presidential system.
So that's two improvements I can think
of. But first of all, where is the war
on corruption? Where are those achadin?
Yeah. So the first step is a war on
corruption.
There should be consequences for
Guaranteed consequences, not pleasant
consequences for for indulging in
corruption. That will shake up the whole
country if you if you do that. It'll
shake up the whole system.
Secondly, a presidential form of
government. Thirdly, a more centralized,
less federal system of government. So
these are some of the things that need
need to be done because right now the
states have too much power and the
center can often isn't doesn't have
sufficient power to to make necessary
changes in the country and implement
necessary reforms.
Uh so you know overall I would say the
entire system is rotten.
The entire system is nothing but
a continuation of the British system of
the British colonial system. The
objective the purpose of the British
colonial system was to oppress India and
Indian people and the exact same system
still continues.
So ideally we want to end that system
and and and implement a new system a
system that is rooted in Indian culture,
civilization and values. But who will do
that? Nobody. So I would say that the
more practical pragmatic thing to do is
to launch a war on corruption then
eventually move to a presidential form
of government. That would be a better
way of doing things somewhat incremental
improvement.
Rajat Chhatriji says the CNB dipole is
the largest uh temperature difference in
the CNB.
The largest temperature difference in
the CMB. Okay. the the the cosmic
microwave background radiation it has a
temperature and the temperature
fluctuates obviously there'll be very
small microscopic not microscopic but
very small tiny fluctuations in the
temperature the CNB fluctuations and
that was first discovered when we
launched the cobe satellite
that was in the what ' 90s was it 80s
let's google that cobe satellite
co satellite Right.
Yeah. When was that launched?
Yeah. 1989 to 1993. And it gave us the
first indications of a fluctuation in
the cosmic microwave background. There
you have it. See the W map is far more
detailed. But the Kobe satellite for the
first time showed us that there were
fluctuations.
Okay. So, so that's what you're
referring to. That's what you're
referring to. Okay. I read an article
but why it matches with earth's equinox
I'm not able to understand
earth's equinox
what does equinox mean
okay let's google that equinox
look one of the two year times in the
year when the sun is above the imagined
line around the center of the earth
equator and day and night are of equal
length That's the equinox.
Okay.
Equinox is two times per year when the
sun is exactly over
the equator and day and night are the
exact same length. That is equinox.
Now, what does a temperature difference
have to do with the equinox?
I'm not sure.
I'm really not sure. Even I'm unable to
understand. It matches with the earth.
Okay, let's Google that. CMBB dipole
earth equinox. What is that? C
MB dipole
equinox.
What's the deal?
A normalous alignment between the cosmic
microwave background CMBB dipole and
earth's equinoxes. Uh CB dipole etc.
Okay. One side of the sky appearing
hotter and others opposite side
appearing cooler. When the dipole
okay
the temperature difference older slide
it's draw equinoxes two points anomaly.
The surprising finding is that the axis
of the CMB dipole appears to be aligned
with the earth's earth's equinox points.
This alignment is not predicted by the
standard model of cosmology and suggests
an unknown large scale physical
correlation
is considered an normally because it
suggests a potential large scale
preferred direction of the universe
which is unexpected given the
cosmological yeah all that an isotropy
all that homogeneous isotropic on the
largest scales yeah I'm not sure I'm not
sure I wasn't even aware of this one
this this particular thing that's a
correlation between this and that
shouldn't be, right? Makes no sense.
Makes no sense whatsoever. Anyway, I
shall look into it. It doesn't look like
there is an answer to the to to this
question, but uh thank you for bringing
this to my notice.
Very interesting and perplexing for
sure. Okay. Divor Singh says, "Why don't
we own Sri Lanka yet? It's right here.
Right there." I believe that's what
Joseph Stalin asked once. The apparently
the story is that an Indian ambassador
went to present his credentials to
Joseph Stalin
and uh they somehow ended up discussing
the map of India and Joseph sen points
to this island. He says what is this
island? What part of India is this
island? And the Indian ambassador says
no no sir s this is not an Indian
island. This is Sri Lanka. He stalin
says what is Sri Lanka? to the Indian
ambassador says this is a separate
independent country and Stalin says why
is it a separate independent country he
was perplexed he was puzzled and he
looked at the Indian ambassador as if he
was mad do you people have any sense
whatsoever why is this a separate
country should be part of your country
and uh that's the question that diving
is asking it's right there why don't we
own it
I don't have any answer
why don't we own it. I mean it's
culturally, ethnically or or people. Why
don't we own it? Why isn't it part of
us? I have no idea. Yeah, because India
lacks ambition. I suppose hit the
complete
all book reviews before
ending 8our live streams.
All right, sir. Your wish is my command.
I shall attempt to do as much as
possible. So, thank you.
Uh AVM says, "Do you think souls have
male and female characteristics? Is that
a function of the host that they
inhabit?"
Look,
like I said a while ago, I am a hopeful
agnostic. What does it mean to be an
agnostic? It means that you don't know
for sure whether the supernatural
exists. as in the existence of God and
complement to that is the existence of
the soul.
Right?
So we have no evidence that the soul
exists. There's no evidence. But I hope
it exists. I hope the soul is is
something that exists. I hope it is
immortal. I hope we have transmigration
of the soul. I hope we have
reincarnation. I hope there's a god that
exists. I I hope all of that. I'm
hopeful. But I don't know for sure. So
if I don't know for sure, how do I think
whether souls have males or female
characteristics? But let's say let's say
the soul exists. Okay.
Do souls have male and female
characteristics?
I would say no.
No.
Because if you if you
if you consider the concept of
reincarnation,
a person a soul can be reincarnated as
male or female.
Typically, it is said that a soul is
reincarnated thousands of times. And I
would say it's statistically likely it's
50/50 male and female each time.
So, I don't think souls have uh gender
characteristics.
I think it's a function of the body body
that they choose to inhabit whenever
they are uh born.
Uh Ammon Madwani says is there a
scenario where in which we peacefully or
coercively reintegrate with the
temporary nation? Is India making any
efforts to subvert it from within? Look,
if India is making efforts to subvert
the temporary nation from within, those
are not supposed to be known to us.
that's supposed to be done in the utmost
secrecy.
So is India making see I mean the
government of India has not told me of
any efforts that they are making in case
they're making some so I can't answer
that question do you understand now is
there a scenario in which we can
peacefully or coercively reintegrate
with the temporary nation maybe in a 100
years time let me tell you why because
when we're talking about Pakistan the
temporary artificial nation
it's got a population of what 160
million what's the population of
Pakistan let's quickly Google that
Pakistan population
what's the population 255 million that's
that's a massive population
right
these people I'm sure there are many
really nice people in there
but most of them have been taught to
hate us from the time that they were
born. This hatred is systematically
inculcated in these people and a
significant percentage of the population
has terroristic tendencies.
Now is there any scenario in which we
can peacefully reintegrate with this
nation? I don't see any scenario in
which it can lead to any peaceful
outcome.
Right? So what needs to happen is
Pakistan needs to be ideally peacefully
balconized.
Synindraesh needs to become independent.
Baloistan needs to become independent.
Kyber Pakuna needs to reintegrate with
Gandhar with Afghanistan. PJK needs to
reintegrate within India. Even that will
be a that even that will be a problem.
And Punjabistan can remain whatever it
is. Then we need to have a cooling off
period of maybe 50 years, 100 years,
multiple generations come by and then
those are gradually dradicalized
and then we can think of perhaps
reintegrating at that point in time.
Maybe in 50 years, maybe in 100 years
right now makes no sense whatsoever.
It'll be a disaster.
Prattana says where did Harapans expand
from? Before urbanization period, there
were local cultures that got taken over
and local cultures reappear post 2000
BC.
Where did Harapans expand from? Where
did they come from?
They are Indians. India has been
inhabited since about 80,000 years
before today.
If the out of Africa migration theory is
correct
then India was the first found settler
first place where the out of Africa
migrations permanently settled the
original founders zone and that's where
our ancestors have been living for
80,000 years.
The Harapans are not some separate
species of individuals sir. These are
our ancestors
and their ancestors were the people who
were living in India for 80,000 years.
So
in this region of India, northern and
western India, you had what they called
the industy civilization or harapan
civilization which was simply a phase of
our history and that was an advanced
phase of civilization with urbanization
with advanced technology
with standardization of weights and
measures and so much more. Right?
So it's not like local cultures were
taken over. It is the same culture that
evolved into something higher.
And then about 2000 BC, you had massive
climate change events.
The Saraswati dried out to a significant
extent and our ancestors had to abandon
the big gigantic metropolices they had
built and they had to either migrate
westwards or eastwards and that's what
happened. So it's the same culture, same
people that's continuing being influing.
It's not like the Harapans came from
outer space and they took over this
place and then they disappeared back to
outer space. It's not like that. Okay.
Okay. Sager Gare says big fan. Thank you
sir. Thank you so much. What is the
justification of for animal sacrifice to
deeds in Hinduism? I have no idea. I
don't know. See even I'm dassinated. I
haven't studied this. I don't know based
on ancient text. And how does this
practice compare to sacrifice in Islam
during Eid ala I have even I I still
understand my culture I don't know
anything about Islam so I can't do a
comparative thing why did sacrifice
happen sacrifice
see I can't say for sure why animal
sacrifice happened but I know why human
sacrifice happened
look we had some goddesses called
examples uh Kali
Chamunda
these goddesses
it is said that they sometimes demanded
human sacrifices.
Does it mean that this this is evil
stuff? No. The goddess would never
demand the sacrifice of a good person
to please the goddess you had to
sacrifice evil people. Your enemies the
enemies of the culture enemies of
civilization.
That sort of thing. So I think that
justification I can understand. So see
for example the goddess Chamunda she is
the kulvi of various chhatria clans
chhatrias are warriors and if they want
to keep their mother goddess happy they
have to go and kill the evil people who
are the enemies of the civilization
which makes sense
so that I can explain that I understand
apart from that you know pashubali
animal sacrifice I am not very clear
about that so I won't be able to answer
that part of the question
okay shubat shukl class says watching
you for the past four years. Thank you
so so much. So much seen you evolve.
Thank you sir. From the most blunt and
non-compromising in your views from one
of the fastest growth YouTube channels
to 949K.
I know I know that's an evolution, isn't
it? Hats off to your commitment for the
cause of civilization. Thank you so
much, sir. I really appreciate your kind
words, your your being a viewer of this
channel for the past four years.
It started very rapidly. It's it I mean
I had no intention of of having a
YouTube channel. And then one day in
what was it in 2020
I I think I I did a pilot episode of Ask
Kabit. I think in early 2020 or
something and uh it was just one episode
then I didn't stop doing anything. Then
in late 2020 I made a video about
Chinghan. why Ching Khan refused to
invade India despite being on India's
doorstep and that's a that's been an
open question for 700 years in history
and I
I gave my answer to that question and
that video blew up and then again I did
not do anything on the YouTube YouTube
channel this channel for like six seven
eight months but the subscribers kept on
growing so then I revived the Ask a
Bijit show in uh June 2021 and it's been
going on ever since and it is driven
entirely by you all my viewers. It's not
me who decides what questions I will
answer. It is you who decides what
questions to ask and I do my best to
answer the questions. That's what I do.
And for some time the channel grew very
fast. Now it is apparently going to be
at 948 949 for some time depending on
what I don't know what factors that's
not in my hand so I don't care. I'm just
happy to do what I'm doing. So thank you
Shubat. Thank you to everybody else as
well.
Shardul Despand says see Bharati Navy
mind speaker mind sweeper strength. What
are my views? Let's see. Indian Navy
mind sweepers. Indian
Indian Navy mind
ah mind sweepers.
How many do we have?
uh category mind sweepers of the Indian
navy
uh ka bundicherry class mind sweeper
and bodified versions of other mind
sweepers
India revives a mind sweeper plan
to counter various threats okay what's
your point sir my my views
my views is that we that mind sweepers
are an important component an important
asset to have especially when you are a
nation with such a gigantic coastline.
What are mines? These are explosive
devices that float on the surface of the
ocean or float slightly below the
surface of the ocean and they just wait
there passively for a ship to come and
if the ship comes in proximity or or
hits the mine, the mine explodes and
causes significant damage to the ship or
even sinks the ship.
So you can you know deploy mines at sea
and create and cause havoc for the enemy
and we have enemies obviously. So that's
why we need to have it is important for
us to have these ships called mind
sweepers and if we are acquiring more of
those I would say it's a good thing.
Okay. Arman
Madwani says as of last month India has
cut its Russian oil imports. I have
personally looked through the data. Why
are we bending the knee to Uncle Sam? Is
it because of Uncle Sam? Is it not
because of Uncle Sam? I'm not sure.
Maybe the Americans are imposing some
kind of pressure on us that we are not
that we in the public domain are not
aware of. Maybe there are some threats
that have been made to us. And see, the
US is the world's most powerful nation,
right?
They can destroy any nation if they want
to.
Make no mistake about it. If they want
to destroy a nation, they can actually
destroy it completely. They can destroy
the economy, ruin the economy. They can
re they can send the nation back to the
stored age
because you haven't seen that happen.
That's why you feel that you know maybe
we have some leverage against them. They
have flattened entire nations. Look at
Iraq. Look at Libya. Look at so many
other examples. So maybe the Americans
may have made some threats to us that
the government have may have decided
that you know what it's not worthwhile
standing up to them.
The long-term future is what's more
important than short-term buckling to
the threat, bending the knee. I don't
know, maybe it's the case. I I don't
know what's what's going on. So you have
personally looked through the data and
India has cut the Russian Russian oil
imports. I would say if that is the case
then it's most likely because of threats
from the United States. Threats of what
kind? What nature? I don't know.
But they have all kinds of leverage
against us. Yeah.
Uh so it's possible that we may entirely
stop buying Russian oil. Even that's a
possibility.
Would I be pleased with that? I would
not be pleased with that. But you know
what? And what pleases me more is that
we we we have a long-term future. So
yeah,
Geopolitical Dubai says full
hypothetically, allegedly, supposedly
potentially support, sir. Thank you so
much, sir. Thank you so much. I really
appreciate uh your viewership, sir, and
your questions. Thank you, sir. Divor
Singh says, "Does hard work and
discipline bit beat talent and genetics?
Can a teacher's child become a conqueror
greater than any so-called warrior
people?
Does hard work and discipline beat
talent and genetics?
Usually, it does. You may have talent,
you may have genetics, but if you're
lazy,
well, then you're going to be defeated
by those who work hard.
I would say hard work and discipline
beat talent and genetics if talent and
genetics is lazy.
So if you are
someone with endowed with great
genetics, you know, but you never go to
gym in lift weights, then an ordinary
person with regular genetics will become
a better bodybuilder than you if they
spend the time and if they work hard.
Similarly, when it comes to achieving
something in life, if you are super
talented, super intelligent, but you sit
around smoking weed,
then a person with regular IQ who works
tremendously hard is going to outperform
you. Uh so can a teacher's child become
a conqueror greater than any so-called
warrior people? Well, if the warrior
people want to sit around doing the
thing, then a teacher's child can become
a conqueror. So I think overall hard
work and discipline can beat talent and
genetics as long as talent and genetics
are lazy. But if talent and and genet if
if if you have two people one is a
regular person one is a person with
talent and genetics and they both both
work equally hard then the person with
talent and genetics will win every time.
An says please make videos debunking
bharata misconceptions. All right. So
thank you very much for your suggestion.
I will look into this very seriously
sir. Thank you
and possibly make it. All right. Uh DN
Singh says is it wise not to punish the
perpetrators of the anti- sick programs
in Delhi 84 Sajjan Kumar etc. They live
free among among us.
There has to be justice.
Whoever has done whatever crimes
have to be punished for that.
So
anybody who committed crimes has to be
punished otherwise we cannot function as
a as a proper society.
And if some individuals are living free
despite
having committed various crimes then
it's it's a travesty travesty. And why
is it the case that
the punishment has not been you know
meated out for that we have to
introspect as to what is wrong with our
system that you know criminals are
living free amongst us so I would say
anybody who has committed crimes has to
be punished otherwise your society will
degrade it will stop functioning
properly and then yeah that's not what
you want
Dan Patel says
the direction uh yes I agree with you.
So what Dash is saying that if um being
able to speak multiple languages like
like French, English, Hindi, Gujarati,
it can help me to work at the United
Nations organization
and in a a post in this direction,
it certainly can. If you can speak
multiple languages, it's it's always uh
going to be an asset for you. Especially
if you want to work in an organization
like the UN, you know, it's also an
asset if you are in business. It's also
an asset if you are in diplomacy.
If you have to deal with multiple people
from multiple countries on a regular
basis, it's always great to speak
multiple languages.
And of course you have to speak
languages that are widely
accepted or widely regarded as as as
international languages. So historically
the language of diplomacy for the past
two 200 300 years was was French right
even today senior diplomats they
typically speak some form of French
broken French good French okay French
but they speak French right uh for
example Dr. Kaval Cibil he speaks
French. Dr. Shashi Tarur he speaks
French. So you will see that and when it
comes to diplomats of other countries
also they will speak French.
Um
so yeah it's always an asset to be able
to speak multiple languages and if you
want to work in the UN it's it's a great
advantage to have. Anonymous scientist
says he how have wars in Ukraine, Middle
East and Afghanistan? How will these
wars reshape global geopolitics?
Question from Sam the Gamer. Sam the
Gamer.
How do these wars or how will these wars
Ukraine, Middle East, Afghanistan
reshape global geopolitics? Look, you go
back to the time before 2022.
How was the world like?
It's a pretty peaceful world. You did
not have the Middle East issue, right?
You do not have the Ukraine war. And
today the world is very different. It's
like pre Ukraine, post Ukraine. pre-
Ukraine war, post Ukraine war.
So before February 22, the major crisis
in the world was the pandemic. You could
not even speak about the pandemic. You
could not even speak about the corona
virus on YouTube otherwise the video
would get demonetized and Spotify would
put all kinds of things and stuff,
right? There was a major crisis in the
world. But now we have a war and that
world has polarized the world that war.
So you have Russia and China and Iran
and North Korea on one side and the the
the US-led western order on the other
side and you have nations like India
which are kind of neutral
and uh the Middle East war it is Iran
versus Israel mainly also Gaza Gaza is
mainly solved now
uh so that also is creating tensions in
the world Afghanistan Pakistan is not
that much of a major issue globally
But for us over here, it is something to
be concerned about. So,
so when it comes to the Ukraine war, it
has become the the starting point. You
could say officially if historians
100 years from now, write history, they
will say that the second cold war
started with the Ukraine war. Right? So
that is a major turning point,
inflection point in global geopolitics.
And each of these issues, each of these
wars has its own effect. So yeah,
uh Varun Sharma says, "I see companies
like Google opening more offices in
India to evade Trump regime's actions.
While I do see them increasing taxes on
the service sector example TCS, what
will happen to for example Google India
Limited, Amazon India Office, etc. From
what perspective? Let me just reassess
what you're saying. Okay. Companies like
Google are are opening more office
offices in India to evade the Trump
regime's actions
and you see them increasing taxes on the
service sector. You see whom increasing
taxes on the service sector? You mean
the Indian government.
If you increase taxes on the service
sector, you are disadvantaging the
service sector, right?
What will happen to Google India limited
Amazon? What exactly are you asking? I'm
not really sure. Who is increasing taxes
on the service sector? Is India
increasing services on taxes on the
service sector? I'm not sure about that.
Has India taken the step of increasing
taxes on the service sector which brings
in so much money for India? Doesn't make
sense, right? I have not I've not seen
that.
or is the US increasing tax? I'm I'm not
really clear about what you ask me sir.
What will happen to Google India Limited
Amazon India office they will continue
as far as I see?
I'm not sure if India's increasing taxes
on them. I'm not sure. Not sure.
If you had
been a little more clear about what
you're asking, I would have been able to
I would be happy to answer you sir. Uh
DN Singh says uh so Arabs created
algebra algorithms
algebra algorithm. So if there's an al
it's it's Arabic, right?
So that's what we are told and that's
what lots of people believe and that's
the kind of propaganda you will see on
social media that the Arabs created
algebra algorithms and so on. those
things came from India but because those
were transmitted via the Arabs into
Europe with Arabic sounding names like
algebra al whatever that's why we are we
are taught today that these uh that
algebra came from Arabia and so did
algorithms but clearly that's not the
case
mandate dictator you think Modi
assassination attempt
How many questions are you trying to ask
over here?
Nathan Gadgkar is ethanol mandate like
dictator Modi assassination attempt real
if yes did China and Putin really help
Modi to escape why did China help who
caught CIA agent who killed CI agent in
or Russia China
okay let's slow down first of all
ethanol I have no idea okay I don't
discuss internal politics forget about
it um do I think the Modi assassination
attempt story is real I have no idea
I think it could be just pure
speculation
I don't know.
But assuming maybe it's real. Do I think
Putin China actually helped Modi escape?
Well, if he came back and escaped and
did not the attempt did not happen,
maybe they did help him. Why did China
help? Because they don't want something
like that horrible to happen on Chinese
soil.
Who killed CI? I have no idea. All of
this is just pure speculation. There is
no evidence whatsoever that this
happened or did not happen. I don't know
who has planted these stories in in in
social media but it's like becoming a
very big thing now. I have not seen any
evidence
that something like this would have
happened. Obviously if an attempt
happened and it was foiled then you will
never see evidence of that. But then
what's the point of discussing it? Yeah.
It's just an academic exercise, a a
theoretical exercise. So I don't know. I
can't say I can't com I can't possibly
comment because I have no idea. I have
no information.
So Shant Bharaj says Joty thank you for
bringing us from darkness to light.
Thank you so much sir. Such such very
very profound words.
I am too small a person to be that to
play that role but I am doing whatever I
can and I'm very grateful for people
like you and everybody else for being my
viewers. It is truly an honor and a
privilege. Thank you very much to all of
you and to you as well sir Susan Budwaji
G. Thank you so much. Varun Sharma says
experiment civic score based points
system in India mandatory for all
colleges and jobs.
Civic sensebased points system in India
mandatory for colleges and jobs
could work. Perhaps
one could potentially try it out in some
parts of India as as as a as a trial
project and see whether it has an actual
effect.
Could it work? It can only work if if it
can reliably give you points.
For that to happen, you need a system
that follows each individual around
everywhere they go and sees everything
they do. How do you make it work? And
isn't that a horrible infringement on on
a person's privacy?
Of course, civic sense is all about what
you do outside of your home. But how
will you
track a person's actions and activities
reliably
every time they're outside their house?
How will you do it?
Is it feasible? Do we want to make India
a surveillance state where you have CCTV
cameras every goddamned where? Do you
want that to happen?
I I don't think it's a good idea
just for civic sense.
It's better to to reform the education
system and make people understand why
civic sense is important. And secondly,
instead of having a pointsbased system,
just ensure that anytime someone is
caught
breaking the RO rules, they are punished
harshly. That's what would make more
sense. Duv Ary says R1 A Z 93 originated
from R1 AM417
and we do not find any ancient skeletons
containing basil R1 AM417 then Arian
migration is right. Do you understand
sir? Everybody everybody
we have these theories right? Arian
invasion or Arian migration. Now if we
say arian invasion they will say you are
living in the 20th century. It is Arian
migration not invasion. Migration
invasion never happened but there was
migration. Now let us understand what is
the core claim
of the Arian invasion. migration,
tourism, picnic theory. What is the the
core claim or core set of claims the
first you see
they may they over complicate things to
hide the real claims. What is the real
claim? The first claim is that Hinduism
is foreign to India. It came from
outside.
And second, the second claim is that
Sanskrit is foreign to India and it came
from outside.
These are the two core claims of the
Arian invasion, migration, whatever
theory
and to obfiscate that they will go into
genetics they'll go into everything.
Tell me something. What does genetics
have to do with language or religion?
H is Tulsi Gabbad somebody who carries
Indian genetics but she is a Hindu.
Right?
So
Arian invasion migration is not about
genetics. It's about the it's about the
language and the religion. That is the
real claim. They are trying to claim
that your language and your religion are
foreign to India and your you all are
descendants of invaders and you don't
belong in India. That's the claim. You
will never be able to prove or disprove
it through genetics
and all of this. Whatever you're saying,
I don't know, man. I'm I'm I'm done with
this genetic stuff.
I am no longer aware of I have not been
keeping track of what's happening week
by week by week. What new research has
has happened in recent times?
Right? The core claim is that Sanskrit
and Hinduism are foreign to India. What
does that have to do with genetics?
So yeah, there you go sir. That's it.
Vamshi Khalim says, "Congrats on this
milestone." Thank you very much, sir.
Thank you. Earliest humans have been
found in Africa. But this is not enough
to conclude or prove that humans
originated in Africa. I completely agree
with you.
Thus far, we have found the earliest
evidence of humans in Africa.
So based on that evidence,
we can perhaps say that humans
originated in in Africa. But it is not
sufficient evidence to conclusively
prove that humans originate in Africa.
Maybe sometime in the future, maybe in
50 years, we will find evidence that is
older of humans, maybe in Eurasia
somewhere.
So based on that new evidence, we will
have to change our our understanding of
the world. So we have to always remember
that we must always keep an open mind
and when new evidence and new facts come
in front of us we have to change our
model of the world accordingly. Right.
Right. So thus far the earliest evidence
is from Africa. That's why we said that
there was an out of out of Africa
migration of homo sapiens. But in the
future if if we find new evidence that
shows something else we're going to have
to change our model. And that's how it
works.
Arya says, "I think modern day Afghans
look very European
uh because of Kaukazin
Muslims from West Asia migrated to
Safawid Afghanistan and Kizilbash
ethnicity are descendants of Kizilbash
soldiers of Anatolia. The Kizilbash are
Turks of Turk origin ethnicity. Modern
day Afghans look very European. Not all
the average Afghan looks like a north
Indian but there are some Afghans who
look European.
So for example, the AANs who are of
Tajik ancestry, they look way more, you
know, European-like than subcontinental.
If you see Afghans of uh of of of
Usuzbek ancestry, lots of them are of
Usuzbek ancestry. They're not the
original Afghans. The original Afghans
are Pashons. Even among the Pashons, you
have some people who look more European
than most. But the average Pashtun looks
like a North Indian. Understand that.
When Mr. Muttaki came to India, did he
look like a foreigner?
The Afghan the Afghan foreign ministry
came to India for a week recently. Did
he look like a foreigner at all to you?
He's a standard looking pashon. The
average Afghan looks very north Indian.
Maybe somewhat taller on average. If I
go to Kabul, I keep my hair open right
now. It's it's tied. If I grow my beard
for a couple of weeks and I keep my I
keep my hair open, I will look like a
Talibani. Larger than the average
Talibani. My point is
my point is the average Afghan the
average Pashon looks like a North
Indian. Look at the Afghan cricket team.
One or two of them may look kind of
European.
Most of them look like they could be
Indians. Some of them look even darker
than the average Indian. For example,
what is his name? Um, Muhammad Shazad.
Let's let's go there. Uh, Muhamad
Shahaz Shahazad.
Yeah, the Afghan cricketer. This guy, he
looks darker than the average Indian.
He's a pun.
So, let's not, you know, stereotype
things.
Um yeah the average person looks like a
north Indian person that's the fact
ICMBBS says
congratulations on number 300 thank you
very much um was at a Diwali event here
in the UK and a diplomat IFS had no idea
who reform were totally they should know
the local politics of their host my god
really
well that's disappointing I would say as
a diplomat in a host country, it is your
job to know the local politics of the
host country.
That's incredible. Was that person newly
arrived?
Even if you are newly arrived, you're
supposed to do your homework before you
arrive.
Well, that's that's deeply
disappointing. Yeah, that's that's
terrible. Anyway, thank you so much. uh
for thank you so much for for your kind
words and uh yeah I agree with you it's
terrible.
Ritik Thiagi says, "Why does India still
reflect a colonial hangover with roads
named after Max Mueller who while many
scholars continue to praise him for
advancing Sanskrit studies in Indian
philosophy in Germany? Because we are
still a colonized nation. My dear friend
Ritik Ryik we are still completely
colonized.
We are colonized in so many ways. The
entire Indian system is the colonial
system. We haven't changed a thing.
Very little has changed. The same system
continues. The same institutions
continue with different names. What used
to be called the IC
is now called IAS. Indian civil services
is now the IAS. The same thing
we are simply deeply colonized. We are
getting more colonized by the day
because the system it progressively
dassinates Indians.
Uh yeah. Yeah. So that's the deal. So we
still have roads named after our
oppressors, named after people like Max
Mueller. Thankfully there no longer is a
road named after Orurange in Delhi but
so many such things. Yeah.
So we so the the the reason is that we
are still deeply colonized. We never
changed the system. We never overthrew
the colonial system. The colonizers, the
foreign occupiers left in 1947.
But we continued worshiping their
system. We preserved it and that that
system is one of occupi of of of
oppression and and dassination and
further colonization. And that's why we
are the way we are today.
I mean ask yourself this question. If
you don't speak English well, will you
get a good job in India?
You go for a job interview in India and
you speak an Indian language. What's
going to happen? They're going to laugh
you out of the room. That's the problem.
We are all still mentally coronized.
Oman Pata says, "Why do
most of Indian historians hate Rajuts?"
There are many Indian historians who
also who also hate the Maratas. By the
way,
whoever served India, whoever fought for
India, whoever died for India, those
people are hated. Okay? And that's why
there are these attempts to create this
this hatred and and mutual animosity
between Maratas and Rajpos between
Gurjars and Rajp and God knows what
other things man
it's it's this constant attempt to
create divisions between Indians and the
Rajpus they fought the Turks for several
centuries starting from the 7th what 7th
8th century AD all the way until the the
Turk the Turk Empire became an empire
from a kingdom, the the the Muggal
Empire.
Until that time, the Rajputs fought and
they fought for centuries,
right?
And that obviously is is something that
is a hateful
characteristic to have to fight the
Turks, to fight the occup the oppressors
and occupiers. And that's why many
Indian historians who are mentally
coronized and who are India haters they
hate ratch and many of them hate the
maratas also because the maratas
destroyed
the tur the turic muggal empire the
maratas did that they established hindi
varajia and that's why many historians
hate the maratas too so rajuts and
maratas and make the two fight best
naran says how to take oneself self out
of slavery mindset.
What are the top five subjects one
should learn in order to earn a good
lifestyle and be respected?
Top five subjects that one should learn
in order to earn a good lifestyle and be
respected.
Top five subjects
you should learn how to communicate
effectively
in whichever language
works for you. You should know how to
communicate effectively verbally and
communicate effectively in
writing.
That's very important. That's the first
thing you should learn.
The second thing you to learn is
critical thinking.
What is right, what is wrong,
how to differentiate,
how to say, how to tell what is the
truth and what is lies.
critical thinking. Critical thinking is
is is super important. Without critical
thinking, you will never succeed in
life.
Third thing to earn a good lifestyle and
be and be respected
uh personal finance.
You know, if you whatever money you
have, how to manage that, what to do
with it?
Why why don't they teach that in school,
college, university, personal finance?
And next how to earn
how to earn
you know how to make money it's very
important without being a slave
I mean it depends on you what you
consider to be slavery some people would
consider working 15 hours a day on a
business to be slavery some people would
consider a 9 toive job a slavery it
depends on on who you are so you have to
determine What's the best way for you to
earn a good livelihood? You should know
how to make money.
So these are some of the things you need
to have. You need you need to know.
These are not subjects that you you are
taught in school or any academic
syllabus, but these are the subjects
that are very important, right? Um how
to be respected?
Well, how to be respected? First of all,
make money. be financially independent.
That's the number one thing if you want
to be respected. You don't have to be
super rich. Even if you are just making
enough money to to barely survive as
long as you don't depend on anyone else
for money, you're good to go. You will
people will have to respect you, right?
And of course, after that, the more
money you make, the more respect you you
gain from society. That's how it works,
right?
um
and so on. So yeah, and how to take
yourself out of slavery mindset. I I'm
not sure what you mean by slavery
mindset, but uh whatever it is, you to
break those those thought patterns and
uh you have to adopt thought patterns
that empower you truly empower you and
uh help you achieve whatever your full
potential is. Sir Yep.
Abininov says, "Why do albino Indians
look white but albino blacks don't? Is
the white race albino version of Indian
race? I'm not sure." Uh, the white race
isn't an albino version of Indian race
of the Indian race. Um, the white race u
see first of all there's no white race.
There are different ethnicities in in
Eurasia, some of which have
significantly lighter skin color and
some have significantly darker skin
color. And I'm talking about the
Indo-Uropean people. I'm not talking
about the East Asians here. So, we are
one of the major Indo-Uropean groups. We
are the Arians, the Indians,
right? Um, and today it is considered
that the Europeans are Arians.
But the two Arians are us. And and and
in the past people knew this. Rudyard
Kipling knew this. Let me give you an
example.
Okay. Redard
Kipling
Arian.
Where's the poem?
Now it is not good. Okay, this this
little poem. Now it is not good for the
Christian's health to hustle the Arian
Brown. But the Christian rian smiles and
he weth the Christian down. You see who
was the Arian here? It's us, right?
Kipling knew who the Arians were. Uh
so coming back to your your point, why
do albino Indians look white? Because we
and the European people, we I suppose
share the same ethnicity, macro
ethnicity. The Indo-Uropean people,
right? The facial features etc are very
similar. The skin color is different. So
if you paint an Indian white, you look
like a white person. But African people
they have very different uh skin sorry
facial features etc right the shape of
the lips the shape of the nose the shape
of the skull it's different so even if
Africans become albino they still don't
look like Europeans I would not say that
the white race is an albino version of
the Indian race like I said there's no
white race as such they have different
ethnicities but it's overall one
extended ethnic family the Indo-Uropean
people
Okay. Sankit says, "My opinion on CIA
whistleblower John Kiriko." Very
suspicious person. Very suspicious.
Okay. Most likely a plant.
Ryik P says, "Your top five greatest
military generals of all time." Top five
greatest military generals. Hannibal
Barka, Julius Caesar, Napoleon Bonapad,
Mustafa Kimaladay Bakhat.
That's five. These are generals. I'm
talking about generals, not emperors.
I'm not talking about kings over here.
So Julius Caesar was a general. He
eventually became kind of the ruler of
Rome, but he was never an emperor.
Animal Barka once again he was a
warrior. A general he was not an
emperor. Napoleon was a warrior. He
eventually became emperor later, but he
was a warrior. Mustafa Kabalaturk was a
general. And Tubai Bakader was a
general, never an emperor. He served the
great kingis Khan. Right. Okay.
A Bromeier says Nepal has an IQ of 43 on
the Lin scale, which is the lowest rank
of all plausible. I don't believe all
this nonsense for one bit.
I'm not sure what the Lind scale is, but
an IQ of 43.
Come on.
So they say that the Indians have an IQ
of 76, which again is is a lie. And if
the Nepales and the Indians are the same
people, same ethnicity, which we are,
how come Nepales have such a lower IQ?
What I don't believe any of these IQ IQ
stories and all that. Um, yeah. So, I
don't believe it. Let me first Google
what is this lin scale. Okay. Lynn scale
L Y N scale.
LIN scale.
Okay.
Lin IQ scale. What is that? IQ scale.
IQ L what am I doing? Uh IQ scores
compare compare. Okay. Okay. Okay. Lyn
and Tatu 100. Same thing. Yeah, that is
utter nonsense. I don't believe it for
one second. Come on. IQ of 43. Nepal. I
don't believe it. Nope.
So, okay. Next. Rashit Shvastav says CRO
Japan.
Cir Japan. His dad got info of team
reporting to the US. Okay, you you
pointed something out earlier. What is
CR Japan? Let's see. C I R O Japan.
What is CO Japan? Aha.
Aha.
Cabinet Intelligence and Research
Office, which is their version of the
ROW. I suppose it's an intelligence
agency.
Okay.
N National Civilian Intelligence Agency
under Japanese cabinet secretary at
tasked with advancing national security
through collecting okay all of that
right okay now what was the earlier
question I can't remember now what was
the deal
I yeah I've taken so many questions
today that I don't remember what the
original question was unfortunately
his dad got info of team reporting to
the US and then said there were some
consequences Well, you see, okay, okay,
something like that, right? One of your
friends, his dad and so on. Well, you
see, Japan is a nation under foreign
occupation. It's under US occupation,
and if you do certain things, there's
going to be certain circumstances. So,
yep.
BS001 says, "I am 18 and pursuing
engineering. I wish to be good at
physics and maths. My professors just
want me to mug up the formulas.
I don't see myself progressing like
this. I need your help. Okay. You wish
to be good at physics and maths. Okay,
fine.
And you wish to progress. Good. But what
is your ultimate objective in life? Why
do you want to be good at physics and
maths? Do you wish to earn a livelihood
through physics and maths? Do you wish
to become a physicist or a mathematician
or would you like to become an engineer
which in which once again you need
applied physics and mathematics? What
exactly is it that you wish to do with
your life? What's your long-term
objective? I can help you only if I know
what your long-term objective is.
If you wish to be a physicist for
example, then in that case um
I can help you understand how to learn
physics instead of mugging up formulas,
right? I can give you a path. Let's say
you want to learn quantum mechanics. I
can tell you how to do that. You have to
first you have to first master the
mathematics.
What kind of mathematics? You have to
master differential equations. Before
that you will need calculus. calculus,
differential equations, algebra,
geometry, trigonometry, linear algebra.
I'm sure I missed one or two, right?
Matrices, determinance. Oh, okay. All
that um if you want to go into so so you
need to master all that mathematics and
then you go go ahead with studying
quantum mechanics and then I can tell
you which books to start off with and
which which are the intermediate books,
which are the advanced books. Um if you
want to learn relativity for example
general relativity geometronamics then
you have to take a different set of you
know a different path you don't you
still need to learn mathematical math
physics but you will need to master
tensor algebra and tensor calculus and
then it's it's a different set of books
you do so I don't know what your
objective is
but I can give you this general set of
suggestions that if you want to be good
at physics In maths,
>> you have to start with the basics.
You have to, if you want to be good at
physics, you have to be good at maths.
Not all mathematics, not not the kind of
mathematics that mathematicians learn,
number theory and whatnot. You need to
be great at uh
at at maths that's applied in physics,
mathematical meth methods of physics. So
it is
you it's non-negotiable that you have to
master mathematics all the maths that's
used in physics and then you have to do
that through the right books because if
you if you study mathematics or physics
through various textbooks that are well
recommended in India written by Indian
authors you will get lost and you will
never do well.
So
the the game plan is master the
mathematics.
Spend a way more time on mathematics
than on physics. If you can do that,
physics will be super easy. That's what
I can tell you sir.
Okay. Kunal Krish says, "Does the Gona
dynasty really exist?" I have no idea.
Don't know, sir. Sorry.
Ashish Yoga says, "Why do the Japanese
live longer than Indians? Do they have a
different lifestyle and food habits? Has
India been affected by GMO foods? The
Japanese have a very different lifestyle
compared to Indians. Their food habits
are very different.
They eat more protein and they eat less
food. They eat fewer carbohydrates. They
eat way less red meat than white meat
and they eat a lot of seafood
and they walk a lot and they are a
developed nation which means that they
have, you know, less pollution, less
whatn not all that. And because they
have continued this lifestyle for
centuries and it's a very beneficial
lifestyle that's why they live longer.
Indians face way more pollution, way
more stress, way more what third world
nonsense than the Japanese. And Indian
diet, the Indian diet is is no longer
the great diet we used to have several
centuries ago. Today it is a carb maxing
diet, very little protein. Indians have
very high amounts of stress and so on. I
don't think India has been thus far
affected by affected by GMO foods. And I
hope it doesn't ever happen. But because
of all these reasons, the Japanese live
much longer than Indians. I'm not sure
about much longer, but I'm sure at least
a decade longer than Indians. Right. I'm
pretty sure.
Right.
[\h__\h] says, "Next understanding America
episode when right now it is on hold."
Right. I've got too much on my plate.
I'm writing now. I have these book
projects that I'm working on and books
need to come out. That's a target I've
set myself. So right now I'm focusing on
that. In the future I will restart
understanding America at at the
appropriate time but right now it's on
hold.
Okay. Locks D. Wow. Woo. Okay. In Trump
Putin Alaska body meet was Putin body
double. How can I say? How can I say
if Putin wants to meet with Trump why
would he send a body double who doesn't
only Putin can negotiate right a body
double can look like Putin but they
can't negotiate so it doesn't make sense
to send a body double but who knows
anything is possible
6P70
Delta says Ukrainian outlet
claim about Asians weaker than them. Let
them clean.
Why should we care? Why should we care?
Let them say whatever they wish to say.
Why do we have to let it affect us?
And when they talk about Asians, are we
are they referring to Indians or are
they referring to Southeast Asians or
Eastern Asians? I have no idea. And I
honestly I personally don't care. I am
least concerned about what people say.
Let them say whatever.
Kural Krish says, "I have an SSB
interview soon. It's my dream to become
an army officar."
Okay. So, it's my dream to become an
army officer and serve the motherland.
Any tips for the interview? I am not an
army person. I will not be able to give
you any tips. I'm sorry.
I don't know what the interview is like.
I'm not sure what they ask you and what
they look for in a person.
So yeah, I am not a person with an army
background
and uh yeah, I won't be able to help you
with that. I'm so sorry. So So if you
want to prepare for the interview,
talk to somebody who has gone through it
or somebody who has understanding
of what it is that the SSB looks for in
a person and that that's how you can
prepare. I won't be able to help you
with that. I'm very sorry but I wish you
all the best sir. I hope you get what
you are looking for and I hope you make
your you you make your dream come true
sir. All the best. All the best. Kunal
artib says when will the education
system be restored?
I don't know if it's if it were in my
hands I would implement it right away
within a year after planning properly
and I would implement it over a period
of 20 25 years.
But it's not in my hands. So I have no
idea. It doesn't look like the
government of India, the current
government has any intention of
reforming the education system. They
have done something called what new
education policy something NEP blah blah
blah which is nothing. It is nonsense.
Yeah. So unfortunately I don't have an
answer to this question. So sorry. I
wish I had. Gorov Gavi says why did NATO
let India reclaim Goa from Portugal in
1961? It was a minor matter minor. They
did you know condemn India harshly for
what we did but go is it like it's a
minor matter and it's not like they were
in a position to come and stop us. They
did it and then it was then it was
announced to the world. So and it it did
it's not like it it was a month-long
operation. It was like a half an hour
operation more or less. So
Rajendra Chola sir great name love it.
Pro-ism protests in the west. Is it
organic? Well, it depends. Some of the
protests may be organic. Some of these
could be manufactured and astroturfed
pro-national protest, pro- nationalism
protests. Well, overall, if you look at
the west, they are very anti-ism.
Nationalism is a bad word there. So, if
there are protests that are pro-
nationalism, I would say that those
people who are doing the protests are
taking personal risk, standing up,
standing up against the system. So maybe
some of these are probably organic.
People are fed up of being ruled from
Brussels, right? Let's say you are in
Austria. Let's say you're in Germany.
Let's say you're in Italy. Let's say you
are in the Netherlands or wherever you
are. Who the hell is Brussels to tell
you how you going to live your life? And
that's what's being done to the people
of the EU. And people are fed up with
all this illegal immigration and whatnot
that's happening. So it makes sense that
you know there will be these pro-
nationalism sentiments and people will
eventually become frustrated enough to
protest. So maybe many of these could be
organic.
Ram Bhakta says, "Shouldn't my diet help
me achieve my goal? For example, non-veg
increases my urge to perform more
physical work while veg food gives me
peace and allows me to focus on my brain
work. Why most Hindus were wedged?
Your diet should Yeah, you I agree that
your diet should allow you to achieve
your goals, whatever your goals are.
So, if you want to be super strong and
powerful and physically fit and muscular
and all that, well, non-veg will help
you a lot with that. Veg food will give
you peace because it will Yeah. you know
you will get this peaceful feeling that
you know I have not eaten something that
has caused some living being in pain
right um
so it's up to you it's entirely up to
you what kind of lifestyle you want to
have what your goals are and uh your
your diet should certainly align with
your goals in life uh why were most
Hindus wedge
it's it's a more recent phenomenon the
past I don't know 2 and a half thousand
years
when I say the past 2 and a half
thousand years are a more recent thing.
You can imagine how ancient Indian
history is, right? Uh I think it it it
all began with the mainstreaming of
Buddhism by Emperor Ashoke. That's where
these these uh ideas of you know super
nonviolence and not eating meat and all
these ideas became uh mainstreamed in
Indian culture. Historically before
Buddhism there was no such thing in
Hinduism. Everybody I mean
nonviolence was regarded a hinsa was
regarded as as an ideal but most Indians
did not necessarily feel compelled to
not eat meat especially those who were
warriors you know they would eat meat
uh so it's not like most Hindus were veg
throughout history during the Vic times
most Hindus were not vegetarians right
Okay. Chocolate boy says, "Please tell
me the origin and historic evidence of
Goa's bandi so much. I have absolutely
no idea, sir. I'm so very sorry. I don't
know. I don't know anything about this.
Sorry.
But if you ask me about the origins and
all that,
we all Indians have the same origin,
right? We have been on this subcontinent
for 80,000 plus years. That's our
origin.
All sama in India have the same origin.
Okay. Santan Banerjee says there's the
lack of an attempt to diversify economic
development across multiple cities and
this results in overpopulation in
certain cities such as Bangalore. How to
handle this? Great question. Why do
people congregate in a few metropolitan
cities in India?
Bangalore you are seeing this
overpopulation this tremendous
straining of the resources of the city
other metropolitan cities like Delhi
Mumbai Kolkata Kolkata not so much
anymore because no one goes there that's
what I hear I'm not sure but you know
Chennai
lots of people
gravitate towards these massive cities
because all the opportunities are there
in those cities and there's a lack of
opportunities in the rural areas and in
Tire two, tire three cities, right?
That's a problem in India
and and that needs to be addressed.
There's also this east west kind of
issue divide that there are more
opportunities available on the west
coast of India compared to the east
coast of India. So these issues some of
these issues are are are are present at
the state level. Some of the issues are
there at the at the central level and
these need to be addressed.
Um
so how to handle this?
Every state needs to handle this. Every
state needs to ensure that we need to
have at least
10 cities or or centers where you have
all the opportunities that that can
possibly be made available to to a
person to to whatever people want,
right? That sort of thing. States need
to take it up. Every state needs to
ensure that you know there is sufficient
development across the state not just in
maybe one city. That's what needs to
happen. But that's a state level issue.
MK says Porus defeated Alexander. Porus
was small. Alexander was large. But why
not Indian kings rather than Porus
defeated Turks?
Um
Turks were less than Alexander.
Okay.
So, Porus most likely defeated Alexander
and Porus had the advantage of battle
elephants and whatnot. And um
yeah, so why did Indian kings not defeat
Turks? Because the Turks were a
different kind of beast, right? The
Turks were nomads who had different
tactics from Alexander. And uh the
lessons of the of the Greek campaign of
Alexander were were long lost. The Turks
came to India after 1000 AD. At that
time it was a very different India.
India was no longer united
and to deal with a nomadic force
you needed a united India.
Yeah, it's an interesting question
you're asking here. But you can't really
compare Alexander with the Turks. Turks
were a different kind of beast.
Alexander was this classical invader who
came with a big army and uh they had a
certain way of fighting warfare which
was similar to what the way Indians
fought except for the fact that Indians
had had elephants. The Turks were a
totally different kind of entity and
their method of warfare was totally
different from what India had seen
before. So you can't really compare the
Turks with Alexander. Okay. A project
smiling Buddha says why no ambitious
project in India like a bridge to Sri
Lanka east west connection like Swiss
canal oil gas pipeline to Southeast
Asia. A bridge to Sri Lanka was
attempted many many thousand years ago
and was done and today if you build a
bridge to Sri Lanka we will have to
overwrite the bridge that historical
bridge and maybe destroy archaeological
artifacts.
Now ambitious projects need to make
sense economically and geopolitically.
East West connection like S canal that
would be a very very major engineering
project you'll have to cut a sw cut a
canal through like several thousand
kilometers the S canal is tiny compared
to what you're what you're proposing
here and what how does it help India
economically if you create a S canal
like thing but a thousand times larger
why how does it help us
oil gas pipeline pipeline to Southeast
Asia,
oil gas pipeline to Southeast Asia.
Well, Southeast Asia is not a major
producer of oil or gas and we still
haven't discovered any major oil or gas
in India, you know, comparable to what
you have in the Gulf. So once again,
makes no sense to have a oil, gas
pipeline to Southeast Asia. What we can
possibly have is oil or gas pipelines or
other pipelines between India and West
Asia, maybe the Gulf region. That may
make sense if it if it it can have
significant economic benefits for India.
So ambitious you know what kind of
ambitious project I would like to see.
India should become a space fairing
nation.
ISRO should become a genuine competitor
and rival to SpaceX. India should ISRO
should should develop
reusable rocket technology and rockets
that are comparable to SpaceX's
Starship. That's the kind of ambitious
project I would like to see. Projects
that actually make sense and and advance
India's interests and and in India's
hard power. That's what I would like to
see. We you don't want to have projects
just because you know they they are
status symbols. They should actually
make sense.
Kunal Krish says in a Karnataka village
the Gore Haba festival went viral
wrongly making people think it's
celebrated across India and hurting the
nation's image. What is a goryhaba
festival? I have no idea. And I would if
it's something that is going to hurt
India's image, I'm not going to search
for it on on Google.
Uh well, these things happen, right? If
there is some some some let's say fringe
practice, some strange ritual or or some
strange tradition some in some part of
India and uh
and if it goes viral, well, people
outside of India will assume all Indians
do that.
So yeah that that's always a risk you
you you stand you know that can happen.
Sure. Uh Rajat Chhattaji says I strongly
believe that with technological
advancement fading qualia theory will
prove soon that consciousness is
generated by brain. I hope I was able to
explain CMBB dipole anomaly question.
Congrats on 300 episode. Thank you very
much. I un understood what you're
talking about the CNB dipole anomaly
with the equinox as well that was
strange um so you strongly believe that
with technological advancement fading
quailia theory will prove soon that
consciousness is generated by the brain
that is the strong belief that you have
okay we shall see we shall see uh I
personally don't know where
consciousness emerges where does it
emerge from does is it is it an emergent
phenomenon
Does it emerge out of complexity? Is it
generated by super complex uh systems
like the brain? The human brain is the
most complex physical system that we
know of in the entire universe actually
that we know of.
So is
is is is consciousness generated by by
that is it emergent
or is is there a field of consciousness
which some people believe? I I have no
idea. I can't say but uh let's see let's
see let's see if your uh theory whether
your belief turns out to be true let's
see
hersai says what were these different
people different sides of the world
called and what type of culture they
were following before Islam and the
Christianity arrived what were these
different people different sides of the
world called which different people
different sides of the
and what type of culture they were
following before Islam and Christianity
arrived. Okay, look um Islam and
Christianity, they both are present in
Eurasia
and
Africa, right? Historically, that's
where they've been present
before
Christianity
spread across Eurasia, what did you
have? You had the old polytheistic
Indo-Uropean religion and its various
manifestations across Eurasia. The Roman
religion, the Greek religion, the
Persian religion. The Persian religion
was an offshoot of Hinduism which was
kind of a rebellion against Hinduism
which was the original religion of
Persia and these are all polytheistic
traditions. So that's what you had
before Christianity became a thing. In
Africa, you had various polytheistic
traditions which uh we don't quite know
very well of because it's all been wiped
out and nothing was documented.
Uh so Islam and Christianity both spread
across Eurasia and Africa and eventually
they spread to other parts of the world
as well. So mainly you had polytheistic
practices. Uh what were different people
in different parts of the world called?
Well, each each region has had different
people who were known by different
names. I would have to give you hundreds
of names then.
Uh look in the Americas you had people
called the Incas. Inca Empire was there
in present day Peru that region. Uh you
had the uh triple alliance, the Aztec
triple alliance in present day Mexico.
You had so many different peoples who
lived in North America who have all been
wiped out or marginalized
um and so much more. Right? So it was a
very diverse world. Wamshi Kaleim says
not only bad people highest
sacrifice issa chakraarti
not only bad people
highest sacrifice issa chakraarti I have
I'm not able to understand what you're
saying sir is it a question is it a
statement what is it about
who is is chakraarti
Sorry sir, not able to understand but
anyway thank you so much. Fast snail
says does hosting 2013 cricket CWG
Commonwealth Games add leverage to
Olympic bid bid? It may if we can
demonstrate that we can organize we can
host and organize a global or or or a
major sporting event.
It could
possibly add some leverage to the bid to
host the Olympics, but yeah, 2036 or
something. It may it may to some extent.
Yeah, I think I think it's certainly
something that will help in
bidding for the Olympics.
MK says, why was the Delti Sultan not
glorified like muggles by our
historians? Secondly,
how is Erdogan voted to power despite
high inflation?
Why is the Delhi Sultternate not
glorified like muggles by our
historians? Because the Muggal Kingdom
eventually became an empire and it it
encompassed the entang
right. The Delhi Sultan was never able
to expand it to that extent.
So it makes sense to for for historians
to to glorify the muggles because the
muggles eventually expanded that much.
The Delhi Sultanate never did. So I hope
that explains that how is Erdogan voted
to power despite high inflation. I
suppose he must be popular, charismatic.
Maybe people are aligned with his uh
ideology and his vision for his nation.
I'm not an expert in Turkish politics so
I can't say anything beyond that. But
clearly if it's free and fair elections
then people see something good in him
and that's why they are voting him to
power. Wamshi Kalim says could the US
send China to the stone age? Russia
the US can can send China to the stone
age. If they try to send Russia to the
stone age the whole world goes to the
stone age. Maybe even that doesn't
happen. Maybe we go back to the age of
the dinosaurs
after a 10 20 year nuclear winter.
Yeah, humanity doesn't survive. If the
Americans try to bomb Russia to the
stone age, there's going to be a nuclear
war and nothing will survive. If the US
tries to do that to China, the US will
take some damage but they will win. So
yeah,
Pratik Kumar Roy says, "What are no why
are most of the Indian doctors and
dentists in private hospitals absolute
a-holes?
They intentionally do wrong treatments
compromising the health of patients. You
see in any civilized society,
education and health care should be
free.
The government is free to tax people.
Tax the people but provide these two
things for free. You cannot turn
education into a business.
You cannot allow health care to become a
business. If you allow health care to
become a business
then people will become the victims.
And the same for education.
So today the emphasis is on retaining
patients not on curing patients. Now if
you cure a patient, the patient is gone.
But if you keep a patient sick,
you keep on prescribing medicines that
treat symptoms, not the root cause, then
you keep on making money and the patient
can be endlessly monetized.
That's why education and healthcare
should never be allowed to be
commercialized. But today we are
commercializing everything and we think
it's progress. That's the problem.
That's the problem you see. So they want
a patient to be a a golden goose, a milk
cow. Keep on giving what the doctor
wants, which is money, money, money,
money until there's nothing left. That's
a terrible system. And that's what we
have today. Sad.
Rajat Chhatraji says I strongly believe
that with tech advancement it will show
fading quailia theory is true and
consciousness is not generated by brain
is vidanta says
I hope I was able to explain CNB dipole
alignment yes you explain that
so you strongly believe that with tech
advancement it will show fading quailia
theory is true and consciousness is not
generated by brain as vidanta says I
don't think the vdanta philosophy says
that the consciousness emerges out of
the brain vanta would say that
consciousness is an integral part of the
universe
and consciousness simply is concentrated
in in the brain but it's not emergent
out of the brain
so vanta would say that consciousness is
everywhere
everything has some consciousness this
object
also has apparently a little tiny bit of
consciousness perhaps. I don't know. Um
so I'm not sure about exactly what
Vidata says about consciousness but but
as far as I understand it's it would say
that consciousness is an inherent
property of the universe. The universe
itself may be conscious. That sort of
thing. That's that's what Vidanta most
likely says. Okay. Hey, Vun Sharma says,
"I was saying that Trump will increase
taxes on the what
on the
uh listen uh I would like to tell all of
you that I am not able to anymore
remember what you said half an hour ago.
I've taken so many questions and
discussed so many topics that if you
expect me to understand what you had
said 20, 30, 40, 50 minutes ago, I won't
be able to. I'm sorry. So, I'm not sure
what you're saying here. Sorry. Once
again, Fast Snail says, "Can't wrap my
head around the my head around the fact
that 1989 fire incident caused
India out of the semiconductor race. If
we had a plant set up in 1984, we should
be leaders." But yeah, the plant was
sabotaged. There was a fire. The fact
the plant was destroyed and our
wonderful politicians, our leaders, they
never bothered to restart that. So we
should have been a world leader in
semiconductor technology in chip
manufacturing technology but now we are
starting off all over again as
beginners.
That's that's what we've had in India.
Yeah. Yeah.
Dark Knight says, "Congrats for episode
300. Thank you very much, sir. I've been
watching you for two years and you have
awakened my genetic memory of my
thousand-year so proud Indic bloodline
and heritage and the need to preserve
its integrity. Thank you so much, sir.
I'm so proud. I'm so glad to know that
uh
that you feel this way and thank you so
much for having been watching me for 2
years and and and just keep keep
learning, right? Be proud of who you
are. Be proud of who we are, what our
heritage is and what we have achieved in
the past. And always remember that the
past achievements are there to serve as
guidelines to remind you of what you're
capable of.
But it doesn't mean that we are great
forever. Today we are not a great
country. We have to become great again.
So we have to all work together towards
that. So thank you so much sir and keep
going.
Karthik R says, "Thank you Abijit of the
Chaan for being our history teacher.
You're very welcome sir. Our education
system is garbage. Unfortunately, sadly
it's true. Yeah. School education in US
Canada is also poor standard. Yeah.
True. True. True. That Hindus should
send schools to Patanjali gurukuls need
dharmic
whiff.
Okay. I'm not sure what whiff is but
yeah sure. Um I know that the education
system now in the US and Canada is also
not good anymore. It's poor and there's
a lot of uh indoctrination these days.
They seek to brainwash children into
believing various, you know, strange
ideologies that are typically not good.
Um that's unfortunately the case the
case. So yeah, if you have access to
guru schools, you should certainly send
your school your your kids to those at
least on a part-time basis as uh
something that supplements the regular
education. That way they will be they
will have some grounding in in our
culture and civilization. So I agree
with you sir. So thank you very much
sir. Thank you. Karthik G. Pratik Kumar
Roy says your views on Apple products
versus Microsoft Android.
I have used all three. I have used Apple
products. Microsoft products Android as
well. Android has its own benefits,
advantages over Apple. Apple has its own
advantages over Android. When it comes
to computer operating systems, I have
always preferred Microsoft. I've always
preferred Windows. I also use a MacBook
when I travel because it's a super
lightweight thing. But uh if you ask me
to make a choice, I would prefer the
Windows operating system over over the
uh MacBook operating system.
Um yeah, so it's it's a mixed bag. They
all have their own strong points and
weaknesses.
Um yeah, but Apple generally makes
products that really last and are really
good. So if you buy an iPhone, it's
going to last you several years unless
you are someone who who who likes to
change it every year which I don't I
would not recommend at all. Uh Anish
Panchchal says big fan of yours. Thank
you for sharing knowledge. Thank you
very much Anish G. Thank you very much.
I really appreciate it. Thank you sir.
Okay. Priyanu Jen says almost every
protest in India is funded by USA. They
they are our civilizational enemy not
China who is with whom we have border
issues. USA seems personal.
If you ask me who is more of a
civilizational adversary to India, I
would say see
China I I know they have sought to
balconize India.
But do they seek to destroy Indian
culture and civilization? They don't.
They don't care. They don't seek to
destroy India's culture and
civilization. They don't try to change
to engineer or to re-engineer our
demographics. They don't try to do
religious conversions in India. The
Chinese don't. The West does that. The
West is will not be content with merely
balkcanizing India. They want to
eradicate Hindu Dharma.
So from that perspective, the west or
you could say the US is a bigger
civilizational adversary
of India than China. I would agree. Dark
Knight says being constantly on the
defensive against invaders is
foolishness. The invader only needs to
win once for you to lose everything. I
completely agree. You have to take the
fight to their home,
right?
I mean uh if you had kings who took the
the fight to the Goris and the Gaznavis
in their own backyard, it would have
been different. If you had kings who
would have sought to invade Central Asia
and defeat the the Turks in on their own
home turf, which was certainly possible,
it would have been different. So being
constantly on the defensive is a recipe
for disaster. And you're absolutely
right. They only need to win once and
you're done. And they will destroy you
forever. Yeah, totally totally correct.
Kajuru Baton says, "Congratulations on
three." Thank you very much. Thank you
very much. Been watching you since the
Ukraine war began. Okay, that's 2022.
Awesome. Awesome. Thank you so much.
What is the key differences between
the Slavs of Russia and the Serbians?
Same ethnicity, same religion. Why don't
they collaborate more?
key differences between the Russians and
the Serbians.
Well,
the only real difference is that these
are the two different geographical
locations. Let us uh go to the map and
let's take a look. Give me a second.
Okay, let's put the map on the screen.
So, Serbia is in the Balkans region.
It's a Balkan country.
Okay. So, we're talking about this
country here and and you can see that
it's it's not very close to Russia.
What's the distance between the borders
of Serbia and the nearest Russian
border? If we ignore Khaledin, it's
about a thousand kilometers, right?
Yeah. So,
that's that's the major issue. Apart
from that, they are Slavic people. The
Serbian language is different from the
Russian language. Same religion, sure.
Same ethnicity, for sure. Why don't they
collaborate more? I am not really clear
about what the deal is. Uh
yeah, how did Slavic people end up in
Serbia? And
yeah, so the main
main difference is that Serbia is
significantly farther away from Russia.
Beyond that, I would not be able to tell
you. I have not really studied the
history in detail. Serbia, Croatia.
Croatia isn't Slavic, is it? No, it's
not. The name of Croatia is based on the
name of the river Sarasati. Actually,
Ravatka.
Um, yeah. So, I don't know the key
differences between Slavs and Russians.
Not not not sure.
Rajendula says, "Why have you never
spoken even slightly negative about
Israel? Are you afraid of Mosad? Is it
something else?" Have you ever bothered
to see the videos on my channel, the
short clips? Have you?
I mean, I don't understand how people
say as if they speak as if they
understand everything and they know
everything in on on under the sun.
H
let's let's let's do this experiment,
shall we? Let's open my channel.
H
Okay, let's put that on the screen. I I
I find this really annoying and
irritating this attitude of some people.
So, here's my channel. Okay, this is my
channel.
Now, let's search for Israel.
Israel. Okay, what do we find?
Is Israel a sovereign country? Is Israel
US's master? Does Israel have a
complicated relationship with with
India? Is India Israel India's friend
western Wasal something else entirely?
Is Israel not a US state? Indians
lectured by Israel is on on on TV. Is
that a very complimentary thing thing?
Does Israel love India? Reality check
for Indians. Does it look like something
very positive about Israel?
H uh why does tiny Israel dominate the
the the Middle East? Why I respect and
admire Israel etc. Indian Jews in
Israel? Racism, persecution, shattered
dreams.
I am saying that Indian Jews, Indian
origin Jews face racism, persecution
and shattered dreams in Israel.
Have you bothered to see that?
I just don't get when people do all
this. It's so annoying.
What are you trying to achieve?
Right. So, I just showed you what the
truth is. I have criticized Israel where
whenever it's relevant,
but do I agree with the various things
like Israel is doing this or that in
Palestine? I don't.
I believe that Israel is doing the right
thing when it comes to the way it is
dealing with Gaza and Palestine. Right.
Okay.
Galler says, "Brave DIA
Brave Dia scared of CIA Aal.
What is DIA? Uh, this happens in nations
on a verge.
Okay. I don't speak German.
I I don't speak German. I'm very sorry.
I I speak French. I don't speak German.
Uh
means security
means under
I I do get some German.
Okay. Okay. Okay. Um but I'm not sure
what DIA is.
Is USA on the verge? I'm not sure what
you're asking there. Um, I'm kind of
getting a little bit of what you're
saying in German, but I am not really a
speaker of German German language, so I
can't really say what uh get exactly
what you're saying. And I'm not sure
what what BIA is. BIA. Yep. Yep. Sorry,
sir. Sorry. Very sorry. Congratulations
on the remarkable achievement, sir, says
Animesh Paul. Thank you very much, sir.
Thank you so much. 300. It's quite
remarkable, actually. 300 live episodes.
It's it's yeah it's not something that
happens very often. Uh thank you sir
Gallver says I adore your commitment
five hours in counting but what we are
your HMTS and always and we will be
forever
Nityanand oh you read the book you read
the story borrowed time. Yeah yeah yeah
thank you so much sir I really
appreciate uh your support. HMT is an
all wins you read it. Thank you so much
for reading it. I really appreciate
that. Thank you sir. Pranov Mur says
opinion on Nlesh Oak and his and his
research. Look, I haven't unstudied his
research.
>> Uh like I said like like what how many
hours has it been? This has been like
five and almost six hours now this live
stream is on. In the first hour or so of
the live stream I answered a similar
question. What's my opinion on Dlesh Oak
and his research and the and something
similar.
Look, I haven't studied his research.
There are multiple people who have taken
up the work of attempting to date
precisely the Ramayan and the Mahabharat
based on archoastronomical
analysis.
Okay. And multiple people have done this
work and they have come up with
very different dates. So first of all I
have to express my heartfelt thanks and
admirement and and and and admiration
and gratitude to the people who have
dedicated so much of their own personal
time in doing this research
right we should all be thankful to these
people all of them
because no one's paying them for this
for for spending the time on these
things and still they've done that. So
that's number one. Number two,
many of these people who have done this
research have come up with very
different dates and uh unless I spend my
own time and several months of it, maybe
a year or two and do the calculations
myself and the interpretation of the
Sanskrit versus myself and come up with
my own dates, I don't know how to have
an opinion on X person or Y person or
Zed person's research. I don't know. So
I don't understand how many Indians
decide that so and so person is the
right person who has made who has made
the right analysis. How do you know by
are you an expert in archive astronom
arstronomy? How do you deter determine
that X person is has made the correct
analysis and Y person is wrong? How do
you determine
do you do it based on who whose face you
like or who speaks the best English or
who speaks the best Hindi? How do you
make a determination?
I don't know how to determine that. So
unless I go ahead and do the
calculations myself, which I'm very
capable of, but I don't have the time.
Until I do that, I can't say who is
right and who is wrong. So I'm going to
say I have no opinion right now about
this research. But I am very grateful
to all of these people for spending this
much of their own personal time and
effort in doing the research. I am
grateful to that to them for this. A
tech desk says Arabs translated Indian
and Persian mathematical texts but many
discoveries like the first mathematical
crankshafts, robots and optics were
original Arab innovations without even
Persian or Indian contact. Isn't it? I
have no idea. I don't know.
We know that the Arabs translated Indian
and Persian mathematical texts. Indian
mathematical texts.
The Persians also translated our texts.
Okay. And those may have been translated
translated by the Arabs. But the
original texts were Indian texts.
Whether they're Arabic or Persian. The
Arabs may have translated some Persian
texts, but those also were translations
of Indian texts. Uh mechanical
crankshafts, robot.
Did the Arabs have robots?
I am not aware of any Arabic robots.
uh optics.
Did the Arabs come up with optics?
I'm not sure about that. So I that's
beyond my scope of knowledge. I am not
aware of any crankshafts or robots or
optics that were Arabic innovations. I'm
not aware of those. I am aware of the
translations, right? That's what I can
tell you. I'm not aware of any of these
innovations.
Okay. Polarizer says current government
wouldn't compromise with sovereignty but
what about only fans and insta
subscription feature corrupting youth
that could be game from deep state I
think omni fans one sorry only fans is
is is an abomination
it's it's ghastly
is it available in India
I am afraid to even open it here I don't
know what what will come up on the
screen. So I I'll not do that. I know
Tik Tok is banned in India. Is is is
only fans available in India. In
when you say Insta subscription, you
mean Instagram, I hope. Or is there some
other Insta somewhere? Um I know that
people have this tendency to take the
phone and do real read real real like
several hours a day.
I know about that. Um and that's
obviously what what do they call it?
brain rot right it destroys the brains
um
should India ban only only fans well if
you can ban Tik Tok why not ban only
fans why not are Indian people or you
know creators on only fans I hope not
so much degeneracy coming from the west
which is you know sad to see terrible
terrible yeah
congratulations
on completing 300 episodes. Thank you so
much. Always got to learn a lot. Thank
you so much, ma'am. Thank you for your
encouragement, for your support. Means a
lot. Thank you very much, ma'am. Thank
you.
Uh 6P70 Delta says around 2015.
US special forces wanted to set up
manufacturing of Russian machine guns
PKM and NSB in United States. Even NATO
countries like Poland and uh
BG,
Belgium still manufacture them to this
day. But many still say Russia makes
crap. What's my opinion? I don't think
Russia makes crap equipment.
Um maybe the Russian equipment isn't as
sophisticated
as the American equipment. Maybe it is
not that complicated. Maybe it is not
that expensive.
Russian equipment is robust. It's
reliable.
If you look at their military
helicopters, they're like flying tanks.
You can shoot as many rounds of
ammunition you want at those. They'll
take it. They'll take the hits. They'll
keep flying. You You can hit them with
missiles.
Chunks of the airframe will fall off,
but they'll still take you home. I think
Russian equipment
is super robust, super strong,
and super reliable. The AK-47,
it works under any conditions. You dump
it in water, you take it out, it'll
work. Sand goes into it, it'll still
work. You do that to to an Uzi or or M60
and see what happens. Yeah, the same
thing. Uh, so Russian equipment isn't
super sophisticated sophisticated like
the American one sometimes, but it's
it's it's very good. It's very reliable.
So I don't agree at all that Russian
equipment is crap. Not at all.
Okay, Ano Patel. Well, thank you, sir.
Thank you very much. So I'm a massive
fan of yours. Thank you so much. Your
channel and content and intellect is
absolutely amazing. Thank you very much,
sir. Once again, I am born I'm a born
and raised and proud Canadian of
Gujarati descent. Okay. My family is
from East Africa, four generations
removed from India. Anyways, well, thank
you so much, sir. I'm I'm glad to hear
from you. You are a proud Canadian of
Gujarati descent from East Africa, I
suppose, Kenya or Tanzania.
And we know what happened in that part
of the world in the 1960s and '7s. You
had the rise of Idi Amin Dada and there
was this very strong and very
unfortunate anti-Indian sentiment
and because of that lots of Indians were
forced to migrate out of East Africa.
Some of them, most of them went to
England. Some of them went to Canada.
Various uh some went to Australia. Very
few came back to India. I have met a few
who
one was a practicing doctor and so on.
Yeah. So anyway, thank you so much sir
for your contribution for for your very
kind words and keep doing well sir. Keep
doing well.
MK says, "Rank Turic empires with
respect to damage done to India."
Um,
the Turk invasions of India were not
launched by empires.
They were launched by various
opportunistic nomads.
So you had the Delhi Sultanit which was
a Mamluk
dynasty, wasn't it? A slave dynasty.
Gulam dynasty and they came from which
Turk empire not an empire and when it
comes to u the Muggal Empire the Muggal
kingdom which eventually became an
empire for a brief time brief period of
time uh there so gentor was was this guy
called Zahiruin Baba who came from Vana
he was a prince he was not from an
empire he was from a small kingdom and
they did tremendous damage to India for
sure the muggles and so did the uh the
Delhi Sultterate and the Goris and
Gaznavids and also Nad Sha who was a
Turk ruler of Iran. So can't really rank
them as empires but they all did
significant damage in various various
different shapes and forms. Sir
MK uh sorry Akil Krishna Kubar says I
stay in the Netherlands. Thank you
for first of all reaching out and uh
you're staying in the Netherlands. All
right. Recently they're beginning to
build two asylum centers there. Asylum
centers. Okay. My question what is the
position or say of Netherlands in NATO
and in the world? Congrats on Thank you
very much long-term subscribers. Thank
you very much Akil G. So
um so Netherlands is building in the
Netherlands they are building two asylum
centers there. Asylum as in refugee
asylum.
I suppose that that's what it was me
because you don't you no longer have
mental asylum centers anymore. Okay.
Okay. So, two refugee asylum centers
which means illegal immigrants who come
into the country and who have to be
sheltered or whatever. Okay.
The question is what's the position or
or stature or standing or say of the
Netherlands in NATO and in the world?
Well, if you look at NATO,
you have a bunch of European countries
and two North Africa North American
countries. Which two North American
countries? Canada
and the US.
And of all the members of NATO,
there is no question about the fact as
to who is the hedgeman. There's only
one. There's only one leader. There's
only one boss. It's the United States.
All other nations are
followers of the US. And among these
nations that are part of NATO, some
contribute more, some are more
significant, some are less. For example,
Germany kind of contributes more to
NATO. France kind of contributes more to
NATO. Netherlands
also plays a significant role in NATO as
a host of US nuclear weapons. Let me
just double check that. Does the
Netherlands host US nuclear weapons?
Let's check it.
Does the Netherlands
do the Netherlands does it do the
Netherlands
host
US
nuclear
weapons?
Yes, the Netherlands hosts US nuclear
weapons. Approximately 15 nuclear bombs,
right? Um so that gives the Netherlands
kind of a privileged position in NATO.
This is one of one of the chosen vasals.
Yeah. Chosen to deploy American nuclear
weapons on its territory. And obviously
those will be aimed at either Khaledrad
or Russia proper.
Obviously not China or something else or
not not any NATO nation. Uh so that's
the kind of thing you have. Uh so all
NATO nations apart from the US are
followers of the US and some of them get
some special privileges like the
Netherlands has been allowed to host
nuclear weapons on its territory.
Really now says I'm fascinated by how
Naji had so much influence. How was he
able to be welcomed by the Germans and
the Japanese? What did he bring to the
table?
Yeah, that's that's a great question.
Nit gi when he went to Germany he did
not go there as a head of state. He went
there as someone who was a rebel against
the British occupiers of India. As such
he came as a supplicant. He was he came
there to ask for help
and somehow he was able to meet the top
leadership
in Germany as well as Japan. So clearly
they saw something in him that this man
has some ability
some leadership ability that is
exceptional otherwise you the doors
never open to you right never open for
you to meet the top leadership
impossible I mean go to Delhi ask to
meet the prime minister of India what
happens they'll ask you why do you want
to meet the prime minister what what do
you seek and why should the prime
minister
who is so incredibly busy, why should
the prime minister spend some time,
invest some time meeting you, right? How
does that benefit the nation?
So clearly the Germans as well as the
Japanese who are fighting the British
and the Americans, they saw
something in Niti. They saw it in such a
way that they felt that meeting with
him, investing that certain amount of
precious precious time meeting with with
him will be beneficial to them and their
cause.
Maybe as a long-term investment, maybe
he will be able to to defeat the British
and uh throw them out of India
potentially and that would be beneficial
for their cause. So that sort of thing.
So what did he bring to the to the table
at that point in time? nothing but the
potential that he had, the leadership
ability and yeah and and and his track
record also like uh he was what the
topper of the I uh Indian civil services
and uh he already had demonstrated that
he had
the ability to you know lead political
movements. He had become the president
of the Indian National Congress before
he was outmaneuvered by Mr. Gandhi. So
he already had a track record and he you
could see that he had tremendous
potential. So that's most likely why he
was welcomed by both the Germans and the
Japanese.
MK says should we prefer Chinese gadgets
over US gadgets with respect to data and
surveillance? I think it's about
choosing which you know which brand of
poison do you like the best. That's how
it is. Whether it is data or
surveillance, both will take your data.
Bast will do some kind of surveillance
on you.
So it's just two different brands of of
poison. That's how it is.
Karthik says King Ashoke was already a
Buddhist during the Kolinga war.
Correct. Contrary to what is thought to
us. Yes. He had already begun practicing
the precepts of both the dharma before
the Kolinga
military operation
before the Kolinga campaign before the
Kolinga war. So what we are taught is
that Ashok was this Hindu king who
fought in the Kolinga war and he
triumphed. He triumphed. His army
triumphed and he saw the death and
destruction that his military campaign
had brought to the people of Kolinga and
he was filled with a great remorse and
because of that he he gave up his evil
religion Hinduism and turned to the
superior pacifistic Buddhism religion
and converted to Buddhism. That's what
we are taught. Buddham saram gachami
that's what we are taught. But the fact
is that he had already started
practicing the precepts of Bodha Dharma
officially before the Kolinga war and he
fought that war as a Buddhist not as a
Hindu. If you want to create a
differentiation between Buddhism and
Hinduism then he fought as a Buddhist.
Okay. Okay. Rajendra says when the US
left Pakistan and Afghanistan
and created a power vacuum, why didn't
we bribe them and make them our vasal?
What what went wrong with the Indian
government?
See when the US
see first of all background background
story Pakistan was created by the
British to serve the British
geopolitical interests in the
subcontinent region and the Gulf region
West Asia region. Pakistan is kind of a
bridge in this region right uh and its
objective was also to to prevent India
from accessing central Asia by land.
So that's why Pakistan was created and
Afghanistan was a different story. Now
Britain very quickly became a second
rate world power in the 20th century
especially after 1956 the so campaign so
crisis
and then the US became the big daddy of
Pakistan
and this relationship became very
important especially important uh after
the Soviet invasion of Afghanistan. So
the US started funding and financing
Pakistani terrorist activities at this
time much of which was later diverted
into India.
So Pakistan was a US facile for the
longest time. Then around 2012
the US left Pakistan alone after the
Osama bin Laden thing was done and all
that and at that time Pakistan was left
without a big master to serve which is
why they chose China. to they chose to
serve China. Now why didn't India bribe
Pakistan make Pakistan it's our vasal
because Pakistan is
its definition the definition of
Pakistan is anti-India not India the
nation was created as an enemy towards
India right the nation was created as a
rejection of India and Hinduess
and the the uh the justification
that is given to the people of Pakistan
for allowing the army to rule as as the
dictatorial power is that without the
army India will destroy us. So the army
could never be in a position where it
would take Indian bribes and become an
Indian masal. They would always if they
did that they would lose all legitimacy
in the eyes of the people and you would
have a civil war and the people would
try to oust the the army from power. So
that's why Pakistan could not do that
and that's why they chose China and
China obviously had deeper pockets than
India.
India could never match the kind of
bribes the Chinese could give to the
Pakistani generals. So there is also
that factor.
Now Afghanistan
the US of uh the US occupied Afghanistan
for about two decades right and they
they left Afghanistan in the year 2021.
They withdrew from Afghanistan in 2021
and they handed power to the to the
Taliban.
And before handing power to the Taliban,
there was this this DHA agreement
between the US and Afghanistan and the
Taliban with some secret clauses. And it
has been alleged by very very uh
reliable sources that the US pays the
the Taliban a stipend of between 30 to
100 million in cash per week in exchange
for certain
you know certain things that the Taliban
does for the US like keeping China out
of Afghanistan.
So even when the US left Afghanistan,
withdrew from Afghanistan, they had they
had placed the Taliban in power and they
were paying the Taliban. So India could
not bribe them. But see today,
India and the Taliban are on good terms.
Aditi, thank you very much ma'am. Thank
you.
Sedhart Gupta says, recommend book on
Nazi stem pre and old indic.
recommend book on Nazi stem
pre
and I don't know sir anyway I don't know
any book on the Nazi stem uh so I I
won't be able to sir
Khan says
fan AC what is my preferred perfume
okay I use two or three different
perfumes one is uh something by Dio. I
think it's a dark black perfume. I
forget the name of the perfume. Uh there
is one by Lacost. It's a white one.
So that's two. I also have used uh
Isa Miyak
is Myak. One of the nice perfumes by
Isaak. So I don't remember the names but
uh yeah I just keep on buying the same
one. Yeah. Anyway, thank you sir. Thank
you for being a fan. Appreciate it very
much.
Okay, how many hours has it been? 6
hours plus. It's been a long session.
Rudra says, "Congratulations." Thank you
very much. Thank you. Watching you for
the past three years. Thank you very
much for being a longtime viewer, sir.
Being a life have been a life-changing
experience even after decades. We
recognize this as one of them. Thank you
so much. That is truly an honor for me.
Thank you very much, Rudra G. Thank you.
Slendy's says, "Uh, I see Indian hate
online skyrocket during Diwali. Why do
white people demonize us and how will it
be in the future? Also, neighbors
deserves as much attention as Zoho.
Please visit their site once. I will
check it out." Neighbors,
uh, why do white people demonize us and
how will it be in the future? Look,
from the West's perspective, we should
have been
eradicated as a civilization.
We are from their perspective a defeated
culture. We were defeated once and the
way they see it cultures they defeat
disintegrate and disappear.
You will see that all across the world.
Look at Africa. They colonized Africa.
There's nothing left of African culture
and civilization. Nothing at all. They
conquered North America. What is left of
the native American culture? Nothing.
Right? They conquered Australia. The
Australian Aboriginal people, do they
even exist anymore? Do they even are
they even relevant? No. New Zealand. So
everywhere they have gone and whatever
they've conquered, they've destroyed.
But we were conquered and occupied for
two and a half centuries. But we still
are here and we are once again growing
as a nation. And that's what they hate.
So that's why there is this hatred
towards us, right? That's why
MK says would defeat at Deutsland better
be UK
would a defeat at DE
better for UK
seeking illegal immigration
I'm not sure what you're asking sir
would a defeat at Deutsland de Denmark
deutsand what is it Germany better for
UK seeking illegal immigration.
Would it have been better for the UK to
lose to the Germans
if they would not have to face illegal
immigration today? Is that what you're
saying? I'm not sure.
Sorry, sir. Blue Moon says, "Views on
Zoran Mandani as the next mayor of New
York City. He looks like a snake to me.
Serpent. Serpentine guy. Don't like the
guy at all. Can't stand him. He'll be a
terrible mayor for New York City.
Terrible. It'll be a huge mistake to
vote for him. GH
polarizer says, "Predicting this as the
last super chat." Let's see. Looks like
it's the last one. Looks like it's the
last one. I don't see any super chats
after this. All right, sir. Thank you
very much, Mr. Polarizer. And thank you
very much everybody else. This is this
has been in excess of 6 hours
and it looks like we have more super
chats. Amit Rao says, "Thank you for the
work for the resurgence of Indian
civilization. Congrats on number 300 and
best wishes always." Thank you so much.
Thank you very much for your wishes,
sir.
Thank you very much. I really appreciate
your
wishes, your kind words. Thank you very
much. Injured soccer player says,
"Congratulations on your 300th episode."
Thank you very much, sir. Pan since
summer 2025. Thank you. What is the
fascination with Stonehenge? Been there
and wasn't impressed one bit. Okay,
you've been there, you were not
impressed at all. What's the fascination
with Stonehenge?
Well, it's an ancient artifact. In the
UK,
uh in Europe, you don't have so many
ancient artifacts. Their their culture,
their their adoptive culture and
religion, it's pretty new, right?
Christianity
and uh
and somehow they have turned stone hedge
stone hedge into this iconic site. There
are many other sites like these with
men's standing stones and sites that are
aligned with you know the the summer or
winter solstice or whatever it is right
but somehow it's it's been u it's been
turned into an iconic site. It's all the
power of marketing and whatnot.
Um, yeah. So, I'm I'm not really sure
what is so special about Stonehenge.
There are many other, you know,
Neolithic
uh sites
in Europe, not just in the British
Isles, but outside of that also, which
are potentially far more interesting.
So, it's just the power of narrative,
the power of propaganda, the power of
marketing. That's all it is. All right.
All right. I think that brings me to the
end of today's session. I won't be able
to take any more. It's been a long one.
Long long one. I know there are a
million more comments out there. But I
think it will be
it will make sense for me to end this
now over here. So let me end this
session at this point in time. It's
crossed 6 hours 18 minutes. Thank you so
much everybody
for for all your questions for your
viewership for your wishes
and everything else and we continue the
ask a show continues it shall continue.
All right everybody thank you so much
keep asking questions keep raising your
standards keep learning and I look
forward to seeing you in the next live
stream. Until then take care I'll see
you soon. Thank you. Bye-bye.